~ Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ~
*Misty white breaths you exhale*
~ Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte ~
*Slowly blown by the wind now*
~ Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni ~
*Into the clouds in the sky*
~ Sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku ~
*Gradually fading away*
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above the sky*
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
At the end of the day...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
When people are rushing home...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
That's when my day starts.
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
This is my only menu.
(tonjiru, beer, sake, shochu)
If a customer wants something else...
...I'll say "I'll make it if I can."
That is my business policy.
(Store Sign: 'Meshi-ya')
Do I ever get customers, you may ask?
I do get quite a few.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
('The Late-Night Diner')
=Season 2=
You look tired.
It's evident, most especially today.
Cuz that new part-timer at my
job is so unreliable.
- Where do you work?
- At a bento (boxed lunch) store.
That guy doesn't even
know how to hold a kitchen knife.
All people start out that way.
He's right.. I'm sure you started
out the same way, Masashi-san.
But back home, my family has
a fast-food diner.
I lost my dad early on.
So my mom had me always
helping out at the diner.
Then why don't you teach
that new guy?
It can pave the way for his or
your own growth, right?
But that guy's so useless.
Maybe he'll quit soon.
- Good evening.
- Oh, welcome.
I made some 'nikogori.'*
(*jellied fish stock)
Every other day, I get to make...
...'karei no nitsuke'* at my diner.
(braised flounder)
The next day, the fish stock
would've congealed.
I scoop out some of it...
...so that for customers who like it,
I give it to them for free.
Here you go.
That 'nikogori,' it looks more like...
...transparent gelatin, isn't it?
The dishes in this diner are made
uniquely for each customer... right?
Yeah.
Itadakimasu.
Master, I'll have some nikogori, too.
Sorry, I only made enough for one.
Because I had a feeling...
...that Ikumi-chan will come today.
Thank you.
She really looked like she
was enjoying her food.
Yeah...
To see an expression like that...
...one couldn't help but remember to
prepare nikogori for her.
You're certainly right.
Is she a regular here?
What does she do?
I think it's better if you don't scrutinize
other people's background details.
Sorry.
Is my fried chicken bento not done yet?
I'm preparing it now.
Damn that newbie...
...he didn't show up anymore.
You remember? The nikogori thing.
- Hey, what about my fried chicken?
- Sorry!
Lunch break's almost over,
for pete's sakes.
- Can you take my order?
- Please wait for awhile!
Sorry for waiting.
What would you like to order?
- Let's see...
- Yes?
- One order of mixed fried bento and...
Mixed fried... got it.
And also green salad.
Green salad, yup.
Here's the fried chicken bento...
Thank you for waiting.... Oh, I'm sorry.
- I'll take care of this side.
- But...
It's alright.
For fried chicken bento...
that'll be 2500 yen ($32).
Here.
- Yes, thank you very much.
- Thanks.
One order of mixed fried
and green salad please.
Uh...okay!
- Anything else?
- Chicken soup.
Soup it is, got it.
Ah, hot!
Please drink all you want.
Are you sure this is ok?
It's alright, this is for what
you did the other day...
...you really saved my skin.
You, too Master... you should make use
of Ikumi-chan's receptionist skills.
- Sorry... if I make a poor receptionist.
- But I do like Master's quiet nature.
Yeah, you're popular.
But you are having difficulty manning the
store alone every lunch time, right?
No... it's no problem at all.
My dream is to open my own diner in the future.
Also keeping myself busy
will pave the way for my own growth.
Whose line is that, by the way?
Uh, anyway... If my diner had a 'kanban-musume'*
like Ikumi-san... that would be awesome.
(*a pretty girl who attracts customers to the shop)
Uh, Ikumi-san...
Is it okay if you go out with me...?
Or...not?
I...
I already have a boyfriend.
Oh... is that so.
I see.
Of course, you do.
I mean, how could you not have one...
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be... it was my fault.
Thank you for the treat.
It's late...
I'll walk you home.
No need.
Well, then... good night.
See you.
Why did I blurt it out like that?
I guess I couldn't help
expressing my feelings.
That's youth, eh?
But some girls like guys who are
a bit assertive.
Really? Then I'll do my best.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
Was that Miku-chan just now?
Haven't seen her for a long time...
I heard recently that
she's popular--
Ah, Kimochi...uh...
Today.. uh... I'm serving braised flounder,
it's quite good.
Right...right right.
- It's the best.
- Really?
If you say so, then there's no reason
why I shouldn't eat it, I guess.
Here, eat.
Be quiet and eat.
- I just had this awhile ago.
- Really?
Yeah.
You wanna use my chopsticks?
Uh... excuse me! A while ago,
you said something about a woman...
Oh...Miku-chan?
Did you mean 'Ikumi-san?'
Ah, right, right..
Her real name's Ikumi.
What do you mean 'real name?'
'Cause Miku-chan's a prostitute...
...she works in a brothel called SILKY
in Kabuchiko.
I heard it's difficult to book her.
No... I'm not gonna do that.
I just wanted to ask.
Miku-san, you have a customer.
Okay.
I'm Miku.
Welco--...
But Rumi-san, isn't he just
buttering you up?
Eh? You think so?
- But you know...
- Right, right...
...a good man wouldn't say such things.
What a cruel thing to say...
So that's how you see me, huh?
No, no...
...generally speaking, is what I meant.
After all, you just don't see that a woman like
me deserves the attention of such a man.
But Rumi-san...
...aren't you just being delusional?
Anyway... I'm a woman who has lots of
confidence, and a strong sense of self.
See, there you go again.
Well, those are the defects
you need to fix then, right?
You guys are so nosy.
At the end of the day,
people go rushing back to their homes.
But if you feel something's left unfinished...
...some nights, you may want to make a detour.
You mean the thing you cook an okonomiyaki* with?
(*savory pancake with toppings)
Right, right... in Hiroshima they
call it 'trowel.'
But in Osaka, they call it a 'lever.'
Master, give me more.
A 'trowel' is what you use to
spread the cement...
But the 'lever,' you see...
...Since an Osakan-style okonomiyaki sticks
to the pan, you try to raise it up like a lever.
Ah, yes, yes.
That's why they call it a 'lever.'
But what's the actual name of it?
So this time I asked a person from Kyoto.
He said...
"Oh, you mean, the 'turner' thing?"
I've been wondering about it for so long...
it turns out it's simply called a 'turner.'
Why am I feeling this way?
She said she has a boyfriend.
If it's painful for you...
...why not be honest with her?
It's true that I like her...
I'm crazy about her.
But...
If you're just gonna hesitate...
...it'll be a rude thing to do
to Ikumi-chan.
Then two more months went by...
Master.
Hey.
You can't afford to be lazy.
Sorry...
Just having a break.
- So... it's about to end, huh?
- Yes.
Good for you.
You'll finally be free.
But I feel uneasy.
I only did it...
...so I can pay off my parents' debts.
It had barred me from doing other things.
But anyway...
I'll be finished with it.
I can do whatever I want.
But I wonder whether I can return to
my original self...
Well... take time to think about it.
When it's finally over,
we'll have a celebration.
Consider it a graduation gift.
Thank you.
- Manager, can I be excused?
- Yeah, sure.
Hello... yes.
~ Anata no kokoro wa anoyamano yuki no yo ni ~
*Your heart is like that mountain of snow*
~ Fukaku tsumori tozasa rete iru no deshou ~
*Deep thoughts locked under the heap*
~ Setsunai omoi wa ano yama ni ~
*Feelings of pain*
~ Kiite moraeba iikara ~
*That mountain heard it*
~ Itoshii kimochi wa ano tsuki ni ~
*Feelings of love*
~ Uta tte kika sereba iikara ~
*That moon heard you singing*
~ Nakanaide ~
*Don't cry*
Master.
Oh, hey.
I haven't seen you here lately.
You're going back home?
My mom suffered a heart attack.
Though she has gotten well...
...there's no way she could
run that diner alone.
So I decided to take over the business.
I'm going back tomorrow via bullet train.
I see.
Can you let me stay here until morning?
Today, you can drink all you want.
Thank you very much.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
Masashi-san, long time no see.
Likewise.
Master, let's celebrate.
It's all over.
Is that so... congratulations.
What are you celebrating?
Um, you see...
I finally broke up with my boyfriend.
I see... that's great.
Master, more beer please.
Comin right up.
Ikumi-san...
Uh...
I'm going back home tomorrow.
I'm no longer coming back to Tokyo.
But...
Would you wanna come and hang out
with me in my hometown?
But...
You broke up with your... 'boyfriend,' right?
Then one year later...
- He took my advice.
- What advice was that?
They look really presentable in those
'samue' (monk's working clothes).
'We're calling our diner, the unofficial
branch of 'Shinya Shokudo.'
Read it too, Master.
This could well be called
the 'greatest timing' of one's life.
With just the right timing...
...everything is possible.
When cooking the fish,
prepare it well in advance.
Blanch it briefly,
then rinse it with cold water.
Clean and remove the scales to take out the
smell... You can then make a tasty broth.
The next day, the broth will cool and congeal.
You'll then have a delicious nikogori.
Please taste.
Okay.
Thank God.
So then...
good night.
~ Yarusenai yuhi yori ~
*More than the dreary sunset*
To be continued
~ Shinji reru asahi o mitai ~
*Rather see the sunrise to believe*
KOBAYASHI KAORU as 'Master'
~ Dakara sukoshi yume o mi sasete ~
*Let me dream a little*
ITO AYUMI as 'Ikumi'
SHIMIZU YUTAKA as 'Masashi'
~ Ashita e mukau tame ~
*So I can go on tomorrow*
HIRATA KAORU as 'Adachi Saya'
FUWA MANSAKU as 'Chuu-san'
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
UNO SHOHEI as 'Komichi'
KOBAYASHI ASAKO as 'Rumi'
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Music: Satou Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by Suzuki Tsunekichi
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
Insert song: 'Nakanaide'
by Fukuhara Kimie
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Food Stylist: Iijima Nami
Based on the manga by: Abe Yaro
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
Screenplay: Mukai Kosuke
Directed by: Nomoto Fumio
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*