~Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte~
*Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind*
~Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku~
*Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away*
~Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo~
*From up above in the sky white clouds reach down*
~Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru~
*To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by*
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
~Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru~
*To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by*
...That's when my day starts.
~Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru~
*To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by*
~Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne~
*Always seems like a thing of the past*
~Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
~Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
EP 2: "Tomatoes Wrapped in Pork Belly..."
Master, thank you for everything.
Then, with this...
Ah.
Tezuka-kun, take care of yourself.
He's got the look of someone who is about
to go jump onto the train tracks, huh.
He said he's going back
to the countryside.
Did he fail or something?
Yeah...
Once you fail, it can be quite...
It seems I've gotten used to
seeing people failing.
The sadness of leaving the capital city...
...it's only felt by the people from
the regions, you won't understand.
Didn't you say...
you grew up in Tokyo?
Hello, welcome.
Hello. Tomato Rolls please.
Sure thing.
Come sit...
Nice ambiance, right?
Oh... yes.
Didn't you see him along
the way? Tezuka-kun.
Tezuka?
He came.
Really...
Is he okay?
He ate Tomato Rolls...
...and has gone back to the countryside.
I see, the countryside...
Ah, Master. This guy won the
Newcomer Award... Hashimoto-kun.
Oh, nice to meet you.
Then, congratulations.
- Drink...
- Thank you very much.
Newcomer Award for what?
For manga.
"Big Comic"...
I always read that.
His winning story is set
to be published in the next issue.
Right now, there are talks
of having it serialized.
That's amazing, isn't it!
Wait, is it okay...
...if I have his autograph now?
I wonder if it's too early.
I'm digging in.
It's delicious.
Told you.
He's called Tezuka Osami.
What a name, huh? It's his real name.
One character away from Tezuka Osamu*?
(*famous mangaka)
Years ago, was he...
Yeah. He was the Newcomer of the Year.
Then, I was put in charge of him.
He wanted to go home though,
because he couldn't live up to his name...
In the end, he didn't become
successful with us...
It seems he was drawing for some
magazine elsewhere but...
I see... he had given up, huh...
Uno-san, I'm gonna do fine.
I have no intention of giving up.
I'm counting on you. 'Cause I was pushing
for you in the preliminary round.
Yes. I already quit
my side job yesterday.
You've burned your bridges, huh!
It's kinda exciting, isn't it!
I'll... cheer for you!
Don't interfere.
Quit bothering em.
It's dangerous to rush inside trains while doors
are closing so please refrain from doing so.
[Big Comic Original, "Hayate Mobius" by
Hashimoto Wataru, Newcomer Awardee!]
- Can I take this?
- Yes, that'll be 320 yen.
This is 1 million, huh...
That's amazing...
Bet you're happy 'cause your
wish has come true.
When you turned down those job offers though,
I honestly thought you were a fool.
Yamada, do you wanna read, too?
Sure.
It's 'cause I can't draw anything
except manga.
Wonder if I could aim for it too...
I was told it's impossible so I quit and
became a civil servant.
Ah... I'm gonna be part of
a Japanese delegation.
Of what? Of teachers?
No, soccer.
Aren't you a substitute teacher
in high school?
I'm off.
Ah! Noriko!
Sorry... but my PASMO* has expired.
(*Ticketing card system for trains)
Wakamiya-san, what do you
think about it? Honestly.
I laughed quite a bit.
Laughed...
Though there's nothing there
to laugh about.
No, when I said I laughed,
what I meant was...
I wasn't simply laughing.
I was kinda like laughing
around the story.
Uno-san... What did Uno-san say?
Oh... Uno-san's busy.
'Cause they're launching
a first issue right now.
No... But his opinion is of a
high level so...
Anyway, the editor-in-chief
isn't convinced.
Whether he wants to let you debut
the series or not.
She doesn't understand it too well.
That Wakamiya-san, to be honest
I don't know what to think of her.
Well for me...
I think she seems a good editor.
No but...
I think it's useless if they're not
committed enough to die in this together...
The mangaka and his editor.
Well it seems, you're
not trying hard enough.
Uno-san, you're committed enough
to die with me, right?
Eh?
I won't lose, no matter what!
'Cause I have nothing else but manga.
Sorry... Noriko...
If you have money for drinks,
pay the rent first, will you?
I love manga so much and yet...
This time, I was feeling gloomy...
I pretty much vented out my
feelings directly...
...I mean into the drawings...
Why don't you try reading
these kinds of references?
That person's level is just too low!
Please, just give me
your opinion, too, Uno-san!
Hashimoto-kun...
Do you yourself find this interesting?
Eh?
Do you really think it's interesting?
Yes.
To be honest, it's boring.
No one's gonna pay to read this.
I don't know what Wakamiya
told you but...
You're the one drawing, are you not?
If you lie to yourself,
you'll be disappointed in the end.
Here. This is your last glass.
Haven't heard from him.
I guess he's not drawing.
I'm already accustomed
to disappointments.
Well, it doesn't look like you are.
Even if you turned pro...
those who survive from that point on...
...it'll be a struggle
a dozen times over.
It's true that there will be someone
who'll kill himself...
...just cause he can't draw manga.
The guy who gave up and went back to
the countryside might be happy by now.
You mean Tezuka-kun?
The newcomers I brought here
and ate Tomato Rolls...
...they didn't become successful, huh?
Hey, now. Don't blame my cooking.
I'm joking.
What are you doing?
Hey!
I've had it!!
Why don't you work?
I AM working. Everyday, I'm trying
to come up with a concept...
Do you think I'm stupid?
It hasn't even turned into
a single penny!
It's a work that I have
to build from scratch!
It's not like I a job where I punch in
a time card and get a salary!
You said that you'd quickly
become a mangaka...
...and go pro!
Let's break up already.
Come on!
- Over there, that one.
- Yeah, I get it.
You like... manga?
I also like to draw.
AHH! Shiiit!
I'm already, thinking about
quitting manga.
I see.
It's better if you decide it yourself.
But I'm scared.
If you take manga away from me...
I've got nothing left whatsoever.
I wonder if it's the reverse?
With the intention of
getting rid of everything...
In the end, all that was left...
...was manga, wasn't it?
Welcome.
Master, long time no see.
It's me, Tezuka.
- Tomato Rolls and beer.
- Sure thing.
Oh, she's Yayoi-san.
- Right now, we're drawing together.
- Together?
Yes.
I went back home to the countryside...
I'd been doing caregiver work but...
that's where we met.
Since I was in high school...
...have been drawing
manga as a hobby, too.
I wanted to quickly forget about manga,
that's what I thought but...
While I was talking to Yayoi-san,
she also mentioned she wanted to draw...
And so, it seems I became
straightforward with her.
So the two of us kept drawing and
repeatedly sent our works to publishers...
Then, it finally gets to be serialized.
It's great that you've realized
your dream, isn't it?
So today, no matter what,
I wanted Yayoi-san...
...to come and have a taste
of the Tomato Rolls here.
He's always been talking
about your Tomato Rolls.
I'll make it right away.
Are you still gonna use
the name "Tezuka Osami"?
Oh, sorry. Nice to meet you.
I also have been drawing.
Oh... really?
Our names will be together.
I'm no longer bothered about it.
Well? You like it?
Yes! Tomatoes are sweeter when roasted.
It suits the pork.
It's better, right?
Master, here's my payment.
Thank you for everything.
Yeah.
Then, Hashimoto-kun,
take care of yourself.
If you've become tired,
take a break from manga.
When the time comes that
you feel you really want to draw...
Then, you should draw again.
'Cause I did the same thing.
Thank you.
From then on...
...he still hasn't even once
come back to eat Tomato Rolls.
I'll be waiting, Hashimoto-kun.
♫ Skewer and sprinkle with salt
♫ If it turns golden brown
♫ It's delicious when served piping hot
'Master'
KOBAYASHI KAORU
'Hashimoto Wataru'
ISHIDA HOSHI
'Noriko' - SHIINA KOTONE
'Uno' - DANKAN
'Yayoi' - YAMADA KINUWO
'Tezuka Osami' - YAMAMOTO HIROSHI
'Kaneko' - KIYOBUMI KANEKO
'Chuu-san' - FUWA MANSAKU
'Wakamiya' - SHIBUYA ASAMI
'Hashimoto's friends':
ITABASHI SHUNYA / SONODA REIONA
'Young boy' - KOMIZO NAGI
Original work:
"Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
Screenplay:
KOJIMA KENSAKU
Planning:
ENDO HITOSHI
SHIBANO MASAYUKI
Producers:
TSUITSUI RYUHEI
OSANO TAMOTSU
ISHIZUKA SHOGO
TAKEZONO MOTO
OP Theme Song:
"Omoiizu"
by SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI
Theme song:
'Yakimochi'
by TAKAHASHI YU
(Warner Music Japan)
Food stylist:
IJIMA NAMI
Art:
HARADA MITSUO
Director:
KUMAKIRI KAZUYOSHI
Planning:
AMUSE
MBS
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT
GEEK SITE
A 2014 production of:
AMUSE / SHOGAKUKAN / TOEI
KINOSHITA GROUP / GEEK PICTURES / MBS / RKB
This drama is fictional