KOBAYASHI Kaoru
KUROTANI Tomoka
LILY Franky
ODAGIRI Joe
- Found him!
- He's here...
It's him...
Don't resist!
("Shinjuku's largest gambling operations
prosecuted... Operators arrested for
profitting from gambling..")
("Arrested suspect, Katagiri")
On that night, 8 years ago...
Time seemed to have stopped for him.
("Arrested suspect, Katagiri")
Directed by: MATSUOKA Joji
He had lost everything.
Still clenching firmly to the seeds of hope...
...sealed up along with his bitter memories.
SHINYA SHOKUDO (Season 2)
'The Late-Night Diner'
Master... Another glass of ginger ale
plus garlic gyoza please.
Comin right up.
Delivery?
Hello?
Can you still make a delivery to 'Meshi'-ya?
Thanks for the patronage.
Hello.
Sorry... For troubling you to come
here during your closing time.
No problem.
We can accomodate orders up to 1 am,
but since our daughter is still small...
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Also this...
I made this chili oil myself so please use it.
Really?
Thanks then, I'll accept it.
Thanks for your patronage.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
This really tastes awesome...
But Master...
didn't you make your own gyoza before?
Yeah.
But I'd rather eat these than make em.
So I just call to have them delivered.
In Kamata, Tokyo, particularly in the Haneda
area, the gyoza there is famous.
That owner who delivered this...
was trained in a Chinese restaurant in Haneda.
He had dreamed of opening
his own store...
Now he finally opened one nearby.
It's true... so yummy!
Isn't it?
I'll do the rest, you can go now.
Just one more.
'Just one more...just one more...'
you've been saying that for the past 3 minutes.
I guess so.
It's okay.
It's faster if two people are doing this.
Hey, you've stopped...
Uh, yes.
Hey, Master... still not here yet?
I'll call and ask them.
Sorry! Thank you for waiting.
- It's here!
- Finally!
At last, we'll be able to eat
the legendary gyoza.
- Where's the owner today?
- Should I place this here?
- Yup!
- Yes.
We had a lot of deliveries today...
...so instead...
...my husband entrusted me
to deliver this.
Is that so...
Oh, here.
Take this.
Thank you for your patronage.
Til next time.
Why was she delivering the food?
I was surprised myself... I didn't know she's
the wife of the gyoza store owner.
Do you remember 8 years ago?
He's late, huh?
Today is my birthday.
I'm getting impatient because he called me
up and told me to wait here...
And that at exactly 12 midnight,
he'd give me a ring.
Guess he's a man who
can't keep his promises.
I actually believed him.
Better stop thinking of foolish things.
I just want my life back.
Don't get into that anymore.
Those times, it's already over
between you and her.
These past eight years...
...it was the same for her too, but...
...she had chosen to embark on
a different road.
From hereon as well.
It is shameful but...
can't it really be helped?
Good evening.
Welcome.
Master.
You're very satisfied with our gyoza, right?
Yeah.
But you can make it, too...
...so that when our store's closed...
...you can still serve gyoza
to your customers.
Yours is better... I can't make
it as good as your gyoza.
Don't worry about it, Master.
My wife's birthday is next week.
Our store will be closed.
Really?
It was a second marriage for me.
My daughter is my child
from my ex-wife.
But my wife is really
good to my daughter.
Master, my daughter has always
wanted to come here.
I would like to bring my wife.
I'll teach you to make gyoza, and
in exchange, you celebrate her birthday with us.
But no need for a gift.
Just being with us is fine.
Sure thing.
Four orders of fried gyoza.
Yep.
Thank you for calling,
this is Anomori Gyoza Store...
Yes.
Is it a delivery?
A call from my home.
My father said that he'll continue
working at the factory...
I have to see him tomorrow.
Okay...
You should persuade him not do it.
Yes.
I also didn't know you got arrested.
Later on, my dad became ill...
I had to constantly watch over
him at the hospital.
I thought you had abandoned me.
I thought the same about you.
Although I haven't forgotten you...
... I had no time to worry about it.
Afterwards, my father was discharged from
the hospital, and a little while later...
I had a marriage meeting with him...
...and married him.
You have a child?
We have a daughter...
she's in elementary school.
And you?
Your birthday's coming soon.
Can I still fulfill that promise I made to you?
Let's go somewhere together.
Stop joking!
That's already a thing of the past.
I thought I'd never see you again.
So I erased from my memories
those times that I spent with you.
What's wrong with that?
I would never have thought of you
if we didn't meet again.
I better go back soon...
Please stop.
At 7 pm, on the night of your birthday,
I'll be waiting for you outside the diner.
The snow that fell yesterday
has not melted...
Seldom lasted this long...
it still remained on her birthday.
Master.
I know how you got your scar.
- Asuka.
- Tell me how I got it.
You got hit by a yoyo.
I also hit Kaoru-chan with it
and blood came out.
But soon, she got better.
I'm really sorry.
She's fond of speaking out of turn.
Papa, guess what I'm doing.
- It's a bit shoddy.
- What is it?
It's really lousy.
Is it a croissant?
Correct!
Master.
My parents have never quarreled.
They really have a good relationship.
- Lovey-dovey, huh?
- That's right, super lovey-dovey.
- Huh? Where is it?
- What's wrong?
Just the recipe for the chili oil
I wrote for Master...
It seems I forgot to bring it.
- Never mind, just give it next time.
- It's okay, I'll go and get it.
Papa, can I go with you, too?
- Sure, come on.
- Yay!
Let's go.
- There's still snow.
- Yeah.
Likely there'll be more.
Asuka.
We're off then.
Be careful while walking.
- We'll be back soon.
- Be back soon.
Oh, I saw some snow crystals.
- How did you see it?
- Tachibana-sensei showed it to us in school.
- Through a microscope?
- Yes.
It seems it's not so simple.
The gyoza I wrapped... is in good
competition with Asuka-san's.
I was also poor in wrapping gyoza at first.
My husband would often scold me for it...
He wanted to let you know...
That this is his passion.
I know.
Master.
Do you want to say that I should
continue living happily?
But it's impossible to go back to the past!
Are you going?
Your life... it doesn't only belong to you.
My life...
belongs to me.
Mama.
Mama, happy birthday.
- How did you get this?
- It's a secret we kept from you.
We reserved a cake for you
and we went to pick it up.
- We wanted to surprise you.
- Oh, I'll show it to Master.
I...
You might catch a cold.
Mama, let's cook the gyoza.
Okay.
He didn't show up in my diner anymore.
- Here you go.
- Looks delicious!
Itadakimasu.
- Yum!
- So good.
~Watashi no umareta kono machi wa ~
*I was born in this city*
~ Taitei konkuriito de dekite ite ~
*Mostly made with concrete*
~ Tonari no kojo kara wa kikai no oto ga kikoeru ~
*Always hear the sound from the next-door factory*
At the end of the day, people are rushing home...
~ Tonari no kojo kara wa kikai no oto ga kikoeru ~
*Always hear the sound from the next-door factory*
~ Watashi to ittara mukiryoku de ~
*I'm a person always without any energy*
But if you also feel something's left unfinished...
~ Watashi to ittara mukiryoku de ~
*I'm a person always without any energy*
Some nights, you may want to make a detour.
~ Watashi to ittara mukiryoku de ~
*I'm a person always without any energy*
Some nights, you may want to make a detour.
~ Sora bakkari nagamete ita ~
*Looking only at the sky*
~ Tori no uta mo kikoenai foroo o ~
*I cannot hear the birds singing*
~ Kikai wa utatte ita ~
*The machines were singing*
~ Son'na machi ga watashi no furusato ~
*Such is my hometown*
~ Subete no dekigoto wa itoshii omoi de ~
*All things are cherished memories*
~ Son'na machi ga watashi no furusato ~
*Such is my hometown*
~ Kikai no oto wa natsukashii komori uta ~
*Sounds of machines, nostalgic lullabies*
Welcome.
If I can, I'll make you anything you like.
=Shinya Shokudo (Season 2)=
The End.
~ Yarusenai yuhi yori ~
*More than the dreary sunset*
'Master'
KOBAYASHI Kaoru
'Murata'               'Momoko'
LILY Franky      KUROTANI Tomoka
~ Shinji reru asahi o mitai ~
*Rather see the sunrise to believe*
'Saya'                  'Kanemoto'
HIRATA Kaoru        KANEKO Kiyobumi
'Rumi'                           'Kana'
KOBAYASHI Asako      YOSHIMOTO Naoko
~ Dakara sukoshi yume o mi sasete ~
*Let me dream a little*
'Goro'                      'Chuu'
MATSUO Satoru         FUWA Mansaku
'Komichi'                 'Marilyn'
UNO Shohei            ANDO Tamae
'Kosuzu'             'Hana'
AYATA Toshiki    ASAKURA Aki
~ Ashita e mukau tame ~
*So I can go on tomorrow*
'Tsukiko'                        'Take'
ICHIKAWA Miwako        HOTARU Yukijiro
'Ryu'                           'Gen'
MATSUSHIGE Yutaka   YAMANAKA Takashi
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
'Katagiri'
and ODAGIRI Joe
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Music: SATOU Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by SUZUKI Tsunekichi
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
Insert song: 'Haneda' by FUKUHARA Kimie
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Food Stylist: IIJIMA Nami
Based on the manga by: ABE Yaro
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
Planning: AMUSE, MBS
Production: AMUSE
Producers: MORI Natsuko,
OSANO Tamotsu, TAKEZONO Gen
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
Screenplay: MANABE Katsuhiko
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*
Directed by: MATSUOKA Joji