~ Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ~
*Misty white breaths you exhale*
~ Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte ~
*Slowly blown by the wind now*
~ Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni ~
*Into the clouds in the sky*
~ Sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku ~
*Gradually fading away*
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above the sky*
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
At the end of the day...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
...when people are rushing to get home...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breath*
...that's when my day starts.
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
This is my only menu. (tonjiru, beer, sake, shochu)
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
If a customer wants something else...
...I'll say "I'll make it if I can."
That is my business policy.
(Store sign: 'Meshi-ya')
If you're wondering if I ever get customers...
...I do get quite a few.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
(Late-Night Diner)
=Season 2=
How is that?
She can't be sleeping,
you'd think.
But believe it or not...
...she had always been like that.
Since she came in here for the first time...
Can I have fried chicken?
Yes.
What would you like to drink?
Is it necessary to order a drink?
Not really... Well, in this diner...
...I've gotten used to asking it, sorry.
Still, we all have to drink.
Here you go... 'karaage' (fried chicken).
Let her sleep.
She must be tired.
She's probably working too hard.
Thanks.
What about your change?
Deduct it from her fried chicken.
Your food's ready.
Would you like some beer with that?
I don't drink sake but...
...I can't drink beer either.
Wait for a sec...
Here.. You can drink this.
So every time she comes over...
...she would sleep by the counter.
Here you go.
Sleeping in a place of business can really
be a worriesome thing to do.
But it's ok, right?
Just by watching
Saya-chan's sleeping face...
...makes this sake taste smoother...
Right?
Men are so simple, no?
I was already dreaming...
What were you dreaming about?
That I went through so much trouble making
fried chicken but it got eaten by someone else.
So... fried chicken please.
Yes, ma'am.
Saya-chan, is that ginger ale?
That's a highball, right?
A mixture of whiskey and soda.
Is that so.
I wanna have one, too.
Master...
It's only for her.
Master, that's favoritism.
But highball was fashionable
a long time ago, right?
It's popular even now...
Because it's an easy drink for women.
But why did they name it 'highball?'
There are several theories to that...
The most credible one was...
At a bar counter in a golf course...
A person there was ordering whiskey and soda...
...when a golf ball was hit and it flew up so high...
...that the man cried out, 'High ball!'
But normally a golf ball would travel far.
Couldn't he have said, 'Far~?'
If so...
...then it would've been called 'Farball?'
So did the first base runner intercept it?
What're you talking about?
Aren't you talking about baseball?
No, we're talking about golf.
No no... we're talking about highball.
Hey.
Sho-chan.
What's the matter?
Is it okay?
Yes, it's alright.
Come out with me.
Okay, wait a bit.
Thanks, I'm done.
What about your fried chicken?
If everyone likes, they can have it.
Uh, no need to pay...
That man...
I've seen him before.
Who is he?
I think he's a stand-up comedian?
I've seen him once in one of those
late-night stand up comedy places.
What was his name again?
Is he popular?
Not at all.
No one was watching the show.
I have to take care of the my kohai*...
(*younger/newer members of a group)
Those guys can't pay yet.
I understand.
Sorry, Saya.
Next week, someone from TBS network
is comin to watch.
A writer for 'Comedy Rookies.'
That show on Thursdays at 8.
Okay.
It'll change from now on...
I'll make it big for sure...
This year, I'm gonna be a success.
And I'll be able to pay you
back what you've given me.
Can't I go along with you today?
I cannot let my kohai see my weaknesses, right?
I'll come back tomorrow morning.
Yes, hello~...
Thank you, thank you very much...
Please favor us, everyone.
Please favor us.
I wanna get married...
Why bring that up
all of a sudden...?
'Marriage?'
But it's hard to meet with her parents,
what will you say to them?
'Oto-san'...
You're practicin' already?
Fine, what will you ask the dad?
'Oto-san...'
'Please give me your daughter...'
'...so we can have children.'
No... Not like that...
What're you prayin' for?
For my boyfriend to get a big break.
'Big break?'
He's a stand-up comedian.
Really? So he's funny, eh?
Maybe.
What do you mean 'maybe?'
I'm not even sure nowadays.
But I do really hope he'll make it big.
That's what we came to Tokyo for, right?
Saya-chan looks haggard lately.
Uncle, beer.
Fried chicken again?
How was it?
What about?
The writer for 'Comedy Rookies?'
Who's that?
Sorry.
'Sorry?'
What do you mean you're sorry?
- What the hell for?
- I'm sorry.
You know nothing about it.
You know nothing about what I feel.
Sho-chan, I'm sorry.
- Sorry.
- What the hell are you apologizin' for?!
I'm sorry.
You're looking down on me, aren't you?
Ouch.
During such things, don't just dive into it.
But he stole the wallet of the man
sleeping next to him...
...I caught him red-handed.
What if he had a knife?
I'm a level 5 in judo (blackbelt holder).
You're being over-confident, eh?
Oww oww oww!
What did ya say to me, ya motherf***er?
Stop it, stop it.
What's with you?!
Saya.
You're a dumbass, dumbass!
- Lemme go, lemme go!
- Now now.
It was your fault that I
threw that damn fried chicken!
- What the hell are you doing?!
- Stop!
What did you just say to my sister?!
- Stop it.
- You can't treat a woman like that!
Leave us alone.
Sorry, okay... Sho-chan?
Let's go home... c'mon.
We didn't have a father.
Our mother was working all the time
so she didn't have time for us.
I was the one who would take
care of Saya.
There was a big age difference
between us...
..So naturally...
how should I say it?
...I guess I was too strict with her.
Well, that's what a detective is...
that kind of thing happens.
Just after her high school graduation...
...she started having a relationship
with that guy...
She left home with him...
I tried to stop her but...
...she said to me...
Thanks.
She said I never approve...
...any of her choices.
Still, her favorite food hasn't changed.
She dreams...
...that her Onii-san (older brother) always
grabs it from her and eats it.
That's why...
...she would ask for fried chicken.
She told me about that story...
...of your childish antics when you were kids.
Cool.
Say... is this the first time you
let someone inside the backstage?
Of course.
- Be careful with that.
- It's cool, huh?
Can I see it?
Looks cute on you.
Really? Is it cute?
Shosuke, we're up.
Let's go out for drinks afterwards, 'kay?
This'll be over quickly... see ya later.
Yes, hello...please favor us!
Uh... I wanna get married.
Oto-san...
I, uh...
That woman tires herself out
so you can do this?
A guy like you shouldn't do that.
Have you been in
touch with mom?
I see.
Whatever kind of life you choose...
...I will always support you.
It's ready.
~ Koe ga kareru made ~
*Until my voice grows hoarse*
~ Uta o motto do ka ~
*I will go on singing*
~ Watashi no uta kikoete imasu ka ~
*Can you hear my song?*
~ Kimi no kokoro ni hibiku ka ~
*Does it resonate in your heart?*
Though it seems a lot has happened...
...Saya-chan and that guy did
eventually break up.
Welcome.
Master, fried chicken.
Comin right up.
Although Saya-chan had went back
to live with her mother in Chiba...
...she would still come and hang
out here from time to time.
Saya-chan, you don't look
sleepy anymore.
Yes, it's because I get enough
sleep at home.
We don't get to see Saya-chan's
sleeping face anymore.
It was a shame though
for a lot of my customers.
Ah... 'highball' had been added.
('Highball (full glass) - 400 yen [$5]')
Totally didn't notice it...
...He finally added to it.
It's a historic moment, isn't it?
Master is a man after all, huh?
Wait... it's okay, it's okay...
We also wanna drink highball.
Master, we really do wanna drink it.
Saya-chan, say something.
Master, take it down, take it down.
~ Tori kuni shitaaji o tsukete ~
*Season the chicken meat*
~ Katakuriko nuri shite ~
*Coat with potato starch*
~ 180-do no abura no ame ~
*Once the oil is at 180 degrees*
~ Nageirete shimaeba ii ~
*Throw it in.*
According to your personal preferences...
...you can season it with ginger, garlic
or black pepper.
When frying the chicken,
fry it twice.
The meat won't be too tough
and it'll remain juicy.
Onii-chan, what else should I tell them?
Do it the way you like it.
Good night.
~ Yarusenai yuhi yori ~
*More than the dreary sunset*
To be continued...
~ Shinji reru asahi o mitai ~
*Rather see the sunrise to believe*
KOBAYASHI KAORU as 'Master'
~ Dakara sukoshi yume o mi sasete ~
*Let me dream a little*
HIRATA KAORU as 'Adachi Saya'
NAGAOKA TASUKU as 'Shosuke'
~ Ashita e mukau tame ~
*So I can go on tomorrow*
ADACHI TOMOMITSU as 'Det. Adachi'
YAMANAKA TAKASHI as 'Gen'
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
MATSUO SATORU as 'Goro'
MITSUISHI KEN as 'Det. Noguchi'
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Music: Satou Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by Suzuki Tsunekichi
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
Insert Song: 'Fried Chicken' and 'Kotoba (Uta)'
by Fukuhara Kimie
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Food Stylist: Iijima Nami
Screenplay: Mukai Kosuke
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
Based on the manga by: Abe Yaro
Directed by: Yamashita Nobuhiro
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*