~ Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ~
*Misty white breaths you exhale*
~ Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte ~
*Slowly blown by the wind now*
~ Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni ~
*Into the clouds in the sky*
~ Sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku ~
*Gradually fading away*
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above in the sky*
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
At the end of the day...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
...when people are rushing to get home...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
...when people are rushing to get home...
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
...that's when my day starts.
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
This is my only menu.
(tonjiru, beer, sake, shochu)
If a customer wants something else...
...I'll say "I'll make it if I can."
That is my business policy.
(Store Sign: 'Meshi-ya')
If you're wondering if I ever get customers...
...I do get quite a number.
SHINYA SHOKUDO
(The Late Night Diner)
=Season 2=
Among the customers
who come to my diner...
...many of them are female.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
Screenwriter, Tsukiko-san...
...likes to come here to drink alone.
The usual?
Here.
Itadakimasu.
Her favorite order in this diner
is hakuzai-zuke (pickled cabbage).
Here you go...
Tunamayo rice bowl.
I've tried to make this at home many times
but I just couldn't match the taste.
- Master, can I have sake?
- Sure thing.
They say each time one makes pickled
vegetables, the taste is always different.
But Master's pickles tastes
pretty much the same.
They say that things that are unchanged
are more difficult to change, right?
In the case of Master...
...it's not about being unchanged
but rather he won't change.*
(*she means no need for him to change)
Don't be so harsh, Tsukiko-san.
That was a compliment.
...Oh, that's right.
This time, can I have some more
so I could take it home with me?
This one, okay?
"Each person has a 'taste of home'..."
"In my case, I'm from Sendai..."
"If you ask me what food I would
like to eat before I die..."
"Sure enough, it's gonna be pickled cabbage
on a steaming pile of white rice."
"Even if I've been in Tokyo for quite
some time now..."
"I still have this very much like
an 'out-of-sorts' feeling, you know?"
Yeah, somehow it's different.
"Well, for people like me
living in Tokyo..."
"It might be due to that taste of home..."
Haven't eaten that for quite awhile.
You like that food, cab driver-san?
Huh? Yeah. Because I'm also from
Miyagi* Prefecture. (*Sendai is its capital)
Does customer-san have that, too?
The taste of home?
I have forgotten.
I haven't found that taste here in Tokyo.
It always tastes different
every time I eat it.
It may either be because of the salt
or the cabbage.
Here, cab driver-san...
...try eating this for awhile.
Huh?
Oh, pickled cabbage?
Watch the road!
Thanks!
I'm afraid...
...I might not be able to meet his taste.
It'll be alright, I assure you.
I also told him the directions on how to get here.
He might come any time.
Excuse me.
Are you perhaps screenwriter,
Maeko Tsukiko-san?
- Yes, actually.
- I'm such a fan of yours!
This is great! Um, I'm really a fan, you know.
I especially liked "Burabura."
"Burabura..."
I had a fight with the producer of that show...
But I didn't expect it would become a hit.
Eh? Is that so?
But I wasn't able to see it at all.
That's why I recorded it so
I wouldn't miss an episode.
Much thanks.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
- Hey, Tsuki-chan!
- Kosuzu-san.
- Komi-chan.
- Master, tamagoyaki and beer, please.
Comin right up.
Is Melbo okay?
He's doing really well!
Look, look, look.
Melbo is the offspring of...
...Suzu-san's pet cat Melulu.
Because they got to know each other here,
Kosuzu-san had let Tsukiko-san adopt the kitten.
It's just that...
I come home at night, right?
If I come home late at night...
he would bite and scratch me like crazy.
His bites, you know, they're quite painful.
- Really?
- Yeah.
That's odd.
When you adopted him, he was 3 months old...
Before that, he was playful
with his siblings.
It doesn't sound like playful biting though...
Ah! ...I know.
Cats also inherit their parent's traits, right?
Melulu, too, has a terrible jealousy.
I'm talking about a man, my dear, a man.
He can smell him on you.
Well, now... that's obscene.
You can't lie to a cat.
Perhaps it's true.
You're really keen, Kosuzu-san.
Ah... in life...
Any idea can become
a writing material, eh?
Tsukiko.
Don't worry about the deadline.
I'll take care of the things at my end.
Don't mind the things around you.
In any case, what I want you to
do is just to write.
I'm especially looking forward
to reading your work.
Alright.
So then, be counting on you.
Thanks.
- Good night.
Melbo, I'm back.
Perhaps...
...Melbo had known what
would happen later on.
(Maeko Tsukiko and TV Producer
caught in a late night kiss)
(Best-selling author Maeko Tsukiko
having an affair? Caught in a night-time
tryst with married TV Producer!)
("Exclusive inside scoop! Best-selling author of
'Burabura' and 'Summer Love,' Maeko Tsukiko...
seen kissing her producer on the street..."
"Her first scandal, said to be "of unparalled love..")
It's really shameless, right?
That writer most likely...
used sex to get the job.
Even though she's a writer...
She prob'ly has other talents, eh?
Welcome.
- Beer, please.
- Comin right up.
And also that producer...
...if he let him have her,
they can do business together, right?
Seriously?
For sure, it is.
That's like wielding power.
Abuse of authority, huh?
And I bet it's not only that woman...
Probably also models and actresses.
I'm sure he had his way
with many other women.
Really shameless.
Lucky guy though.
What do producers do, anyway?
Don't they only do odd jobs...?
Like procuring things.
Things like Cierpo tea.
- Thanks for the meal.
- Thanks!
Maeko-san had often told me
about the pickled cabbage here.
Is that so.
Has she been here?
Not recently.
"Shameless," huh?
Why can't a person be attracted
by another person's talent?
It just happened to be that...
I am that man and she's the woman.
I didn't mean to fall in love with her.
I was even aware that it was wrong...
...I couldn't help but be caught in it.
That's how it was.
The next time Tsukiko-san came to my diner...
...it was around a week or so after that.
Welcome.
Oh... Tsuki-chan.
Pickled cabbage and sake, please?
Comin right up.
I've been staying at a hotel in
the western end of the city.
It was my first time to live on canned food.
This world sure is a funny place.
This is the only time they called me
"best-selling author."
Melbo!
Nose-san was...
...the most understanding
person I've worked with.
He told me to write whatever I want...
He was the first producer...
...who felt a connection to my work.
I knew he has a family...
...but I didn't care.
Whatever it is you do,
it shouldn't have to become a writing material.
Eventually got me into trouble, huh?
Melbo!
- Oh, it's you.
- Have you seen a cat?
It was just right there...
Melbo!
Oh, no!
- How was it?
- Oh, Oji-san.
How's your cat?
His right hind leg is broken but
he'll heal soon.
He has to stay in the
animal hospital though.
- So he's safe now?
- Yeah.
That's good... Well, now, I'll send you home.
It was delicious, that pickled cabbage.
Oji-san.
Me, too. We're both from the
same hometown.
Is that so.
There's no use crying about it.
Yeah.
Last week, I went back there
and visited the sea.
I still saw crabs on the shore.
I thought those stuff had disappeared.
They're still alive, huh?*
(*meaning they survived the 2011 tsunami;
Sendai was one of the worst-hit areas)
Yeah.
~ Anata no namida wa aoi hoshi no yona ~
*Your tears are like blue stars*
~ Mizu o tataeru umi ni yagate kaeru deshou ~
*Soon return to the vast ocean*
~ Anata no kokoro wa ano yama no yuki no yo ni ~
*Your heart is like that mountain of snow*
~Fukaku tsumori tozasa rete iru no deshou ~
*Where your intentions are deeply buried*
You did it.
It's very interesting...
impeccable work.
It just oozed out...
Couldn't put the pen down since the start.
I'll immediately show this to the company.
I knew it... this is proof that we
should only continue working together.
No more...
Let's end this.
Wait a minute.
Otherwise, I will not proceed.
I see.
You will not bring it?
I can't receive it.
That book is really your own.
Tsukiko.
Thank you.
Six months later, the drama series
that Tsukiko wrote had begun.
("As Long as I'm Still Alive" premieres at 9 pm tonight)
Six months later, the drama series
that Tsukiko wrote had begun.
Your upcoming drama seems
like it's gonna be popular, eh?
Thanks.
You know, Master, I have a date today.
Again? Tsuki-chan, you never learn.
It's not what you think.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
Master, pickled cabbage, please.
Make it a large order.
Comin right up.
Before pickling the cabbage...
First, let it dry in a cool place for half a day.
Its sweet taste will be condensed.
Then, according to your liking, you can add
kelp and dried chili when soaking it.
It'll become even more delicious!
So then, have a good night!
~ Yarusenai yuhi yori ~
*More than the dreary sunset*
To be continued
~ Shinji reru asahi o mitai ~
*Rather see the sunrise to believe*
KOBAYASHI Kaoru as 'Master'
~ Dakara sukoshi yume o mi sasete ~
*Let me dream a little*
ICHIKAWA Miwako as 'Maeko Tsukiko'
TANAKA Tetsushi as 'Nose'
~ Ashita e mukau tame ~
*So I can go on tomorrow*
HOTARU Yukijiro as 'Take'
AYATA Toshiki as 'Kosuzu'
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
UNO Shohei as 'Komichi'
HIRATA Kaoru as 'Adachi Saya'
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Music: SATOU Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by SUZUKI Tsunekichi
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
Insert song: "Nakanaide" by FUKUHARA Kimie
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Food Stylist: IIJIMA Nami
Based on the manga by: ABE Yaro
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
Screenplay: MUKAI Kosuke
Directed by: KOBAYASHI Shotaro
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*