~ KOBAYASHI Kaoru ~
Opening Song
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
~ YOU ~
~ Den Den ~
Directed by OIKAWA Takuro
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
and people make their way home,
my own day begins.
[~ Traditional Tonjiru ~ 600 yen
~ Beer ~ 600 yen, ~ Sake ~ 500 yen
~ Shochu ~ 400 yen
Max. three drinks per customer]
My menu is all there.
The possibility of getting
served anything else...
as long as it's possible,
my business model.
I am open from midnight
to seven of the morning after.
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
How is business doing?!
Well enough, I'd say.
~ WITHS2 4th Anniversary Special ~
SHINYA SHOKUDO - midnight restaurant
Episode 8
Yakisoba (fried noodles) Sauce
Quite windy tonight.
Every time the cold spell comes,
I feel nostalgia for this.
Not so fast!
This is mine.
You can spare
me a little, can't you?
- Just a little.
- Yeah.
2 ml.
2 ml?!
Thanks.
Come on in.
She always
came with the wind.
Yakisoba sauce with
fried eggs on top, please.
Here, special yakisoba sauce.
Bon apetit.
Seems like you
enjoy that quite a bit?!
Master!
The one who just went out...
Was she Kazami Rinko?
Who's that?
She used to be a idol, you know!
Now she's showing
up all over movies and TV.
Now that I think about it,
she was a little familiar.
Really?
What did she eat?
Yakisoba sauce with fried eggs.
It's Rin Rin, all right!
It's her for sure.
Kazami Rinko.
Born Morinaka Rinko.
Born September 3, 1966
in Kochi Prefecture.
Favorite color, blue.
Favorite food?
Yakisoba sauce with fried eggs!
Suddenly starting to feel snarky...
Why do you know all that so well?
We were members of
her fanclub, back in the day.
Member no. 44 and 45,
to be precise.
First Erect-san, now Rin Rin.
Must be quite demanding.
Erect-san was our god.
Rin Rin our goddess.
Eh?! Never heard of her?
Don't tell me you don't know
"Blow Off the Annoying BOY"?
What kind of title is that?
Kosuzu-san, you just
don't get it, do you?
What is that about?
I like it, why?
Do you?
What are you, a fool?
Don't waste time flattering
these country bumpkins.
Don't say that.
"Those brats acting all
cute make me puke,"
"I'll do it my way."
"Annoying, Annoying BOY,
get the hell out of the way."
"I'm going straight for your heart."
"Annoying, Annoying you are!"
"Annoying, Annoying
BOY!"
"Pesticide, Shoot!"
"Liars are totally uncool"
"I'll remain true to myself"
"Annoying, Annoying BOY,
get the hell out of my way."
"I'm going straight
for your family register"
"Annoying, Annoying you are!"
"Annoying BOY!"
"Pesticide, Shoot!"
Two grown ass men weeping like that.
But I guess that, to them, Kazami
Rinko meant their youth itself.
Rin Rin was always
such an energetic character,
but she also had it
really hard growing up.
Right.
Her father disappeared
with huge debts left to pay,
and it went all awry
for her until she debuted.
You know...
I certainly appreciate Rin Rin,
but how about you order something?
Yakisoba sauce with fried eggs.
Same for me.
Yes.
And then, about a month passed?
Even on that day....
she came with the wind.
Yakisoba sauce with fried eggs.
You seem to like that a lot.
I often had this when I was little.
The sadness stamped on
her face made me feel so bad,
I instantly became a fan of hers myself.
After that, she kept coming
by every now and then.
Master, is it true that
Kazami Rinko is coming here?
Ume.
Salmon.
Tarako.
Thanks for that.
Even celebrities are
not all that special, all right.
Isn't it a little annoying as well?
She had this cloud
over her head...
We're much better as women.
Right?!
Careful... Are you okay?
Falling all over the place...
Rin Rin?
She was there until a moment ago.
The Ochazuke Sisters as well.
The hell with ochazuke!
Did they make another scene?
Seems like you're destined not to meet.
Yakisoba sauce...
With fried eggs.
Coming.
Master!
Thanks for that.
I only have a 10,000
yen bill, is it all right?
Sorry.
I lost my wallet today,
so I don't have the change with me.
Pay me next time.
How much was in it?
Money wasn't much,
but my driver's license
and card were in it.
That's so unlucky.
So... Next time.
Sure.
Master.... Rescue me!
My body can't handle it anymore.
Master!
Let's go!
Excuse me.
This is yours, right?
I found it last night,
but as you were working,
I thought if someone like me came in,
it'd be a little awkward.
Thank you.
Wait...
If it's okay with you,
allow me to...
No, No.
That wasn't my intention.
It's okay, I mean it.
I'm fine.
Then...
Let's do this.
Still haven't had breakfast, right?
Then, eat it here.
But... I'm not that hungry...
Here you go.
Warms you up inside.
~ Today, the press conference
for the film "The River's Song" took place ~
~ Lead Kazami Rinko
expressed her thoughts ~
"Because the protagonist went
through things I experienced myself,"
"I am trying to take advantage
of such experiences to make this..."
"the most realistic
portrayal of such a character."
Kazami Rinko...
She's a fine actress.
Sometimes, she even drops by.
She was here last night as well.
But she always orders the same thing.
Yakisoba sauce with fried eggs.
I guess she loves it.
Do you know that?
(*River in Kochi Prefecture)
If you add green laver from Shimanto River*,
yakisoba tastes even better.
Ahh... Is that so?
It's a whole different flavor.
Later,
when that actress comes,
have her try it out.
I'll do that.
It's green laver from Shimanto River.
Yes.
So good...
Makes you feel alive.
Dad.
Back then,
why did you abandon me?
That...
Thanks to you, I....
Cut!
Let's take a break.
Yes.
We'll take a little break.
We're taking a break.
- Break.
- Little break.
Excuse me, Kazami-san.
If you will...
Yes...
- Because of you...
- Cut!
Again.
I'm sorry.
Where did you find that doll?
It was over there.
You got lucky.
What is it you don't
like about my acting?
On a superficial level?
Does it lack feeling?
It's just all wrong!
The dialogue, the expression
on your face, the mood!
It doesn't move you a bit.
I told you more than once
that I hate using idols!
Oi... I'm not going
to compromise here!
That's out of the damn question!
My entire life is
on the line here!
Come on in.
Yakisoba sauce with fried eggs.
Coming.
About this movie I'm shooting...
It's about a father and his daughter.
I see.
After being abandoned by her father,
on the day she reunites with him,
the daughter confesses all her feelings.
Well...
It's the kind of film where
nothing much happens.
Just a father and daughter story.
She was abandoned, you know?
But says that she doesn't resent him.
On the contrary, she's thankful.
When I meet my father...
Will I really be able to
tell him something like that?
Do you resent your father?
Can't say...
Here you go.
Bon apetit.
This...
This fella told me.
That if you take yakisoba sauce...
and add green laver
from Shimanto River to it,
it tastes even better.
Bon apetit....
How is it?
Great.
Even the man who told me about this...
said he's a big fan of yours.
Here we are!
Yummy!
Rinko's favorite,
green laver from Shimanto River!
I'll sprinkle it all over.
There... you go!
I love the yakisoba you make me.
Great!
I...
don't resent you, Dad.
Thanks to you, I....
Dad.
Thank you.
Oji-san, can't see a thing!
Oi! Oji-san!
After that performance,
Kazami Rinko...
was praised for having
become a much better actress.
Seems like she's been invited
to a film festival abroad, as well.
But...
~ Kazami Rinko Wins Blue Arrow
Best Actress Prize for "The River's Song" ~
(*younger colleague/friend from same school)
So what happened to your kohai*?
No matter how busy,
she keeps coming with the wind,
from time to time.
Yakisoba sauce with fried eggs.
Coming.
~ to be continued ~
Here's your one
point advice for yakisoba.
Before the noodles parboil,
it's wise to pour some
hot water over them.
If you do so, excess
fat will be removed,
and it will benefit the sauce as well.
So...
Good night, everyone.