KOBAYASHI KAORU
MITSUISHI KEN
SHINOHARA YUKIKO
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
INOZUKA KEN / OHO SAYOKO / NATSUME SHINYA
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
ABE TOMOKO / SAKATA MASANOBU / IKEDA KOKOROYUKI
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
ABE TOMOKO / SAKATA MASANOBU / IKEDA KOKOROYUKI
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
NAKAGAWA TOMOAKI / TSUJI OSAMU / KUSUTO / IKEGAMI SANTA
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
TAKAHASHI HIDEYUKI / TAKATO YUKI
KOIKE ARINORI / SAKATA NAOKI
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
ODAGIRI JOE
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
ODAGIRI JOE
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
...That's when my day starts.
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
Director: MATSUOKA JOJI
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
Director: MATSUOKA JOJI
Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne
Always seems like a thing of the past
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
[MESHIYA]
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
EP 9: "Liver with Chinese Chives
and Chinese Chives with Liver..."
- Over here at Shinjuku 02...
- Please, man.
Yeah... yeah...
What's "false accusation"?
Right.
Okay...
Yeah, I'm counting on you.
Good evening, are you
waiting for someone?
I was sleeping here.
Sorry sorry. I'm sure you're in a bad mood
if we woke you up from your sleep.
But you do know this is
not a place to sleep.
Are you coming home
from your side job or something?
I don't have ta tell ya.
No, it doesn't matter.
It's just that the shrine caretaker notified
us.'Cause this is within shrine grounds.
Why am I the only one
who's got to suffer like this?
There's plenty of suspicious guys out there.
I'd be fine with this if you
questioned everyone the same.
Linda, you better go to the
pet salon tomorrow.
Ah, sorry about this.
Thanks for the hard work, guys.
Hey, you're being questioned
by the police, huh?
This is the pits, man.
No matter how many times I told em I was sleeping
here... They just don't believe me at all.
Here's your "O~i Ocha" (tea product).
There's also a Snickers bar.
Thanks, man!
Hey... if you're gonna lie...
don't even think about it.
I ain't lying.
Then, cooperate openly with them.
'Cause we're too busy and all.
But, w-wait... You're leaving already?
'Cause once I get home, you're gonna
call me again to bring you something.
Thanks for the hard work.
Boys, let's go.
'Night, guys.
Good job, man.
So, you won't mind
cooperating with us?
Come on.
"Go ahead."
We've just searched all over but we couldn't
find any. Should we let him go?
Wait, you can't just do that!
Hey... what are you up to?
If we weren't able to stop that dealer,
there'll just be more drug dependents again.
Still, just because we beat
them to the punch...
...why should those narcs complain about it.
That scrambling for taking credit
is so outdated.
Ah, I'm so hungry.
Listen, in here, we remove our badges
'cause it's a place for eating and drinking.
We don't talk shop.
Deka (Detective) is so particular huh.
Since everyone makes you nervous.
Though nobody's around.
Here, thanks for the wait.
This here's Chinese Chives with Liver.
While this one's Liver with Chinese Chives.
Mine's the Liver with Chives.
And mine's the Chinese Chives with Liver.
I wonder if these two were
mutual enemies in their past lives...
They just can't get along.
It's always like this,
every time they come here.
After just coming home,
and feeling sleepy...
...there was a man wearing a suit
standing outside the window.
I was too scared to close the curtains,
and couldn't move...
Then, your underwear was stolen
during that time, right?
Yes.
How come you didn't report it immediately?
Even if we investigate,
a week has already passed so...
You were scared right? 'Cause you
don't know what that guy will do.
If I report him to the police,
I thought he might retaliate...
I understand how you feel, but
please try to have a bit more faith in us.
Yes, but for example,
even if you were consulted about stalking...
...there have been many incidents
that you weren't able to prevent lately...
I agree. You can't depend on someone
who you don't find reliable, right?
Zip it, will you?
But it's true, isn't it?
There's no point to being a cop
if no one believes in us.
'Cause cops are always too late.
She's troubled because the system doesn't
make a move unless something happens.
That issue has nothing to do with this.
Why not? It has everything
to do with it.
Right from the start, when you were
looking at her with that kind of eyes...
...you thought she was at fault,
because she was being careless.
What kind of eyes?
Am I right?
How to put it...
You look at me with kindly eyes
but also a bit lewdly...
Something like that.
Ah? Lewd--...?
Buy anpan (bread with sweet filling) and milk*.
(*Common snacks of TV cops while on a stakeout)
What?
There's a convenience store down
the main road, right?
I'm not hungry.
Just go.
Where did she wander off to?
Pete's sakes...
This isn't her first time to run errands.
It's the police.
Captured! Mission complete!
Look, you...
Dirty old man...
Lewd, right?
You, too huh?
It worked according to my plan, didn't it?
It was just a fluke, don't do that again.
Gimme back my 1000 yen.
- Hey!
- Good evening!
Ah, hello! Izumi-san. It's been a while.
Are you patrolling?
That's your job, isn't it?
As usual, it's quite stuffy in here.
You're also with Noguchi-san?
Then... you guys are working together?
We're not getting along well.
Say, I wonder if he's having menopause.
What do you think?
Hmm, well...you see, for me...
where that is concerned...
I can't very well speak freely
because of my position.
- Okay, see you around.
- Oh, you too.
This isn't altogether bad either.
Hey Master, do you have some liver?
There's enough for just one person.
Then, cook half of it as Chives with Liver,
and the other half as Liver with Chives.
I don't think it's possible.
Just go on home.
I don't want to. Since you saw me naked, I think
it's only right that you treat me to some food.
Did you see?
No... you...
No, um... there was... a, um...
It doesn't mean anything since it was
your own personal undercover operation.
Why not? It got some
results, didn't it?
You get results using correct
investigation techniques.
It's 'cause you say such things,
people are mocking us as "tax theives".
Natsuki.
What?
What are you aiming for?
Harry Callahan.
"Played by Clint Eastwood."
"A detective who uses extra-judicial violence
in order to perform his duties."
"Harry Callahan, fictional character."
You're such a pain in the neck.
For someone who stood his ground against the Yakuzas;
won the Chief's Award 3 times...
...and was a candidate for the Commissioner's Award,
Det. Noguchi has already lost his edge, huh?
Here you go...
Your last bottle of alcohol.
Noguchi-san is a defeatist,
an old-fashioned naive guy.
Eh?
What I'm trying to say is...
if I could just fix that part of him...
Stupid... masses? He tells me to quit acting like
I'm a representative or an ally of the people.
It's often said that "a spat is proof that
they get along well"... So you're not like that?
Nope, not at all.
They say a good partnership is something
that gets along even if they fight often.
But I can't get along at all
with Noguchi-san.
Sorry for bothering you with all this, Master.
Oh, Mom? How's your health?
Are you having your walks everyday?
I see... Have you talked with
the doctor already?
What?
Don't worry about me.
Even if I'm already gettin old, I'm more
comfortable being single.
Check up? Oh, it's every year, right?
Please take care of Dad
as well with his diabetes.
You should worry more about yourself.
Noguchi-san is at it again.
Well, it's love sickness.
If you need me, please call me anytime.
But you seem to be a busy man.
No, I'm free during my days off.
Say, Noguchi-san, my birthday's coming up.
Guess what my zodiac sign is.
Is it cow? ...Tiger?
Ding-Dong!
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
It's someone's birthday.
When I was handling cases
of gang violence...
I arrested a yakuza who killed
someone for insurance money...
The husband at that house was
the victim of that incident.
Her daughter was still small at that time, she'd
be at the station consulting me on various matters.
I heard that today is her daughter's birthday.
Our work is finished once
we arrest the criminal...
But for the victim's family, they have the
rest of their lives to live with it.
Why are you making it
sound like a good story?
We are uninvited guests, you know.
Detectives sympathizing with victims
only spells trouble.
Besides, what you're doing...
...is in violation of Article 3
of the Stalker Control Act.
This isn't a matter that
can be defined by logic.
Even you're tailing me, aren't you?
So in other words...
You're interested in the dead husband's widow.
If I may make that observation.
They're saying your usual love sickness
has begun again.
Shut the heck up, witch!
An object of sympathy turning into love...
You're not a middle schooler, you know.
This is what you call mixing
your public and private life.
Preaching to people about not crossing boundaries,
when he himself is doing it.
I wonder if that person's
not cut out to be a cop.
This may just be my opinion but...
Aren't you talking a bit too much?
Wonder if our partnership
will be dissolved.
You've always been like that up to now.
What?
Dissolving a partnership...
This one doesn't sound
like your first time.
There's a shortage of personnel. They
can't find anyone who commensurates with me.
Really now...
Is that what you really think?
Yes.
As long as you think that way, that'll be
the message you'll convey to your partner.
I hate it when a person writes
someone off so easily.
Sorry... if I spoke out of turn.
A few days after that...
Why can't I eat Liver with Chives?
Today, I called for a woman
whom I wanted you to meet.
She won't like you if you smell.
Who is it?
Good evening!
- Hana-chan.
- Good evening.
Missus!
What's going on here?
She said they have to thank you
for everything you've done for them.
Please sit down.
Thank you.
I thought I must properly
convey my thanks to you.
Then Natsuki-san said she'll be the one
to arrange the meeting place.
After that time,
I tried to think of various ways...
...how I could help you out.
You've become thoughtful huh.
It's still too early to be surprised.
What, what is it?
Good evening.
He's my fiance.
What!
We're now living together...
I'm so glad to meet you. You've looked
after them a great deal. I'm really grateful.
Daddy.
Not yet.
Guragura kuru... Guragura kuru*.
(*In Fukuoka dialect, it means "I'm so pissed")
He just finally resolved a very difficult case.
I wonder if you're just tired.
Anyway, what would you like to eat?
Love is blind...
A heartbroken cop?
You're not right? You'd be disqualified as a cop.
Didn't you notice it?
She... she wasn't wearing a ring.
They've been engaged for 3 months.
No way...
Feels refreshing right?
It's a fresh start.
What do you mean fresh start?
Have a clean start, starting tomorrow.
'Cause we're buddies, aren't we?
Guragura kuru...
Thanks for the wait.
Thank you, Master.
We'll both share this.
Here you go.
["Gura-gura kuru" ...chagrin, anger; an expression
used mainly in Kyushu, representing disappointment.]
If it's just Chinese chives
or just liver...
...it somehow seems
unsatisfactory and dull but...
...if taken together,
they'll become delicious many times over.
"Deka (Cop). During the Meiji Era, police
did not wear police uniforms."
"Instead, they wear kimonos with 'kakusode*'"
(*angular-shaped sleeves)."
" 'Kakusode' in reverse is "Desokuka"..."
"And from there, the first and last syllable are taken,
and they came to be known as 'Deka'."
After seasoning the liver,
add cornstarch and oil...
That way when you fry it,
they won't likely stick together.
Please try it.
You'll get over it soon.
I wonder if my approach was wrong...
'Master'
KOBAYASHI KAORU
'Noguchi'
MITSUISHI KEN
'Natsuki Izumi'
SHINOHARA YUKIKO
'Drug Dealer' - INOZUKA KEN
'Stalked Woman' - OHO SAYOKO
'Stalker' - NATSUME SHINYA
'Widow' - ABE TOMOKO
'Fiance' - SAKATA MASANOBU
'Daughter' - IKEDA KOKOTOYUKI
'Bald Cop' - NAKAGAWA TOMOAKI
'Short Cop' - TSUJI OSAMU
'Uniformed Cops - KUSUTO / IKEGAMI SANTA
'Gang Leader' - TAKAHASHI HIDEYUKI
'Gang Members':
KOIKE ARINORI / SAKATA NAOKI / TAKATO YUKI
'Kogure'
ODAGIRI JOE
Original work:
"Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
Screenplay:
MANABE KATSUHIKO
Planning:
ENDO HITOSHI
SHIBANO MASAYUKI
Producers:
TSUITSUI RYUHEI / OSANO TAMOTSU
ISHIZUKA SHOGO / TAKEZONO MOTO
OP Theme Song:
"Omohide"
by SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI
Theme Song:
'Yakimochi' by TAKAHASHI YU
(Warner Music Japan)
Food Stylist:
IJIMA NAMI
Art:
HARADA MITSUO
Title Logo Design:
BAY BRIDGE STUDIOS
Sound Supervisor / MA:
ASARI NAOKO
Photography:
OTSUKA RYO
Director:
MATSUOKA JOJI
Planning:
AMUSE
MBS
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT
GEEK SITE
A 2014 production of:
AMUSE / SHOGAKUKAN / TOEI / KINOSHITA GROUP
GEEK PICTURES / MBS / RKB
This drama is fictional