KOBAYASHI KAORU
BENGAL
KANO RYU
KOMIYA TAKAYASU
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
SAKUMA YUI / OKAYAMA YUTA / MOTOYAMA AYUMI
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
NAKAYAMA YUICHIRO / UNO SHOHEI
KOBAYASHI ASAKO / HIRATA KAORU
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
NAGASHIMA EIKO
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
NAGASHIMA EIKO
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
...That's when my day starts.
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
Director: MATSUOKA JOJI
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne
Always seems like a thing of the past
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
[MESHIYA]
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
EP 7: "Freshwater Clam Soup..."
Say, that boardwalk over there...
Every Saturday morning, Mr. and Mrs. Hiraga...
...would go out walking and stop here
to eat breakfast along the way...
...for a month now.
Good Morning, Master.
Good morning.
Since I started eating breakfast here,
I feel my body has changed for the better.
The breakfast here is nothing special.
It must be your morning walks, isn't it?
Perhaps, it's because of the clam soup.
Everyone says that freshwater clam soup is
a good midsummer dish for the body.
Right?
Master...
Please, say that I've been
here the whole time.
What's the matter, Mine-kun?
Well, I attended a mixer...
How to say this... there was a girl there,
we hit it off well...
- I unintentionally went with her to a hotel...
- "Unintentionally" huh...
I was drunk, and had accidentally fallen asleep...
"Accidentally", huh...
When I woke up, I had 32 missed calls
and 20 messages from my  girlfriend...
You mean the girl you've been
going out with lately?
Then, I'll tell her you unintentionally
spent here the whole night.
Do you have to put it like that... Anyway she's coming
here now so please just say that I was here.
See? I told you I'm here, right?
Hey, how about eating some breakfast? Ok?
Master!
I told you, it's not what you think, I swear...
Just quit that act, and come on!
Then, what happened to Mine-kun?
Who knows... I haven't seen him since.
There's no way I'd forgive a guy for cheating.
Saya-chan, if you say such a thing,
you won't be able to get married.
Why?
There's no man who wouldn't cheat.
That's not true, I won't cheat.
Yes you will. If you find yourself
in the right time and circumstances.
Men always think, "If I had a chance..."
But the couple who comes here on Saturday,
I don't think they're like that.
Right, right. The Hiraga couple.
They get along well, don't they?
You get married, occasionally have spats
and hate each other but...
You both get to watch your children
grow up and leave home.
Then, it'll just be the two of you,
quietly and slowly spending your days together...
I yearn to have a life like that...
Me too.
You guys are really naive, huh.
Hiraga-san.
Oh... Hello.
Welcome.
Here you go.
Fancy seeing you here alone
in the middle of the night.
We were just talking about you,
about you being a model couple.
My wife has gone back home to Hiroshima.
It seems that a grandchild was born.
Congratulations!
Well, it is a grandchild, but it isn't mine.
Which means...
My wife had a daughter and a son from
her two previous marriages...
It was her married daughter who gave birth.
I see... um, how did you meet your wife?
Last summer, we had a class reunion
in our hometown.
That's where we met again after 40 years.
Feels like fate, huh?
Um, it was my first marriage.
Last year, I too was invited to my class reunion.
Tsk... wonder if I should have gone.
You should have.
And then?
"She hasn't been doing too well
after giving birth."
Then you don't have to worry about me.
"Say, are you eating properly?"
Yeah. Just worry over things at your end.
"Thanks."
Bye.
"White, 12 of 10."
"10 seconds."
"20 seconds."
"1... 2... 3... 4... 5... 6..."
"20 seconds. 1... 2...3... 4..."
Thanks for waiting.
Are you sure you'll only eat that?
Yeah. Actually, I just finished
eating with a co-worker...
But for some reason,
I don't feel like going home yet.
What would you like to drink?
I'll pass. I become a pest
when I get drunk.
Excuse me, another glass of beer.
Sure thing.
Are you... um, this is just a hunch...
...um, is your work related to "Go?"
Ah, I knew it.
Master, this person appears on TV...
Let's see... Teshigahara Mariko-san.
Really...
You're a score keeper in the
televised game of "go", aren't you?
This is the first time someone recognized me.
But the truth is I want to be recognized
as a professional Go player.
I'm aiming to be a professional player,
being a scorer is just a part-time job.
Still, you have a nice voice.
Do you like Go?
Not at all.
I have no idea how it goes.
I always fall asleep when watching it.
I haven't eaten momiji manju* since elementary school.
(*maple leaf-shaped cake with sweet bean filling;
Specialty of Hiroshima)
It's my first time to eat it.
Thank you for this treat.
Considering we just met here.
- Are you on a business trip?
- Yes.
This guy here is the only classmate
of mine who made it to Tokyo.
You know what, Master? This guy here
is like the Cupid of Love.
Cupid?
He aggressively insisted that I attend our
junior high school reunion.
But thanks to him, I got to meet my wife.
So then, Mizue-chan, right?
When we heard that she came back,
we all got together the other day.
I heard her daughter wasn't feeling so good...
so it's Mizue-chan who's taking care of the baby.
If you have spare time, you oughta
go and see her.
I'll just be a nuisance. Besides,
it's an important time at work.
She'll be back next week anyway.
Oh, here, here.
Oh, is this Koucchan?
Yeah, it's Kouichi. When I told him
Mizue-chan came back, he came right away.
They were once rumored to be a couple
back in high school, right?
Your wife was popular, huh.
She was garish. She wore her skirts up to here.
That's why I didn't expect that
you'd end up with her, Yoshio.
Ah...
Mizue-chan went through
various relationships but...
Finally she has found her last man in you.
I'm happy for you.
"White, 12 of 15."
"10 seconds."
"20 seconds."
"25 seconds."
"28 seconds."
"This is your 8th time for consideration.
You have 2 consideration times left."
He looks down, doesn't he?
Just heard awhile ago that
his wife hasn't yet returned.
Looks like... her son this time,
had a motorcycle accident.
Thanks for waiting.
Do not know whether it's true, that he fell down with his
motorbike and got hospitalized for a fractured clavicle.
We got married after she came to Tokyo but...
I still wonder if she's more
comfortable over there.
...that's why, maybe she's lying to me.
Mizue was a girl who developed earlier...
She was sexy, that's why,
I had always wanted her but...
Many things have happened in her past.
I heard she had done some things*...
(*sex industry)
What on earth are you saying.
"It doesn't matter whatever happened in the past..."
That's what I thought...
Hey... just wanna ask if your son's
collarbone has gotten better...
You're going out?
"I'm going to eat out with Koucchan..."
What... The two of you?
"I'm going to consult him regarding the accident,
like insurance procedures and the like."
"Because Koucchan is in the car business
so he knows some details."
Really...
Lucky you. You got plenty
of men to help you.
"What's that supposed to mean?"
"Why would you say such a thing?"
No reason. If you like, you don't have
to come back anymore.
After all, your son, grandkid
and friends are all there...
...including your old boyfriends...
"The heck is that?"
"What the blazes did you just say?"
"I wantcha to... say it again!"
You only talk in dialect
when you're in trouble!
"Well, you've been whinin' and quibblin'
for a while now."
"Gimme a goddurn break!"
"Ya got somethin' to say, say it clearly!"
At least...
At least, send me a message every day.
Are you really that busy that you can't do as much?
Was that Yoshio?
That idiot!
Excuse me, another bottle please.
Yep, coming.
What? You had a fight?
Yocchan is a very kind man,
but inside, he's also insecure.
You never had a
discerning eye for men.
What're you sayin.
During those days,
you're counted among those men, are you not?
Master, one more bottle.
I only serve up to 3 bottles.
- Welcome.
- Good evening.
Ah! Mariko-san.
[Introduction to Go for
40 years old and above]
Master! Give her a drink. My treat.
Uh, look here...
You've really been studying, huh.
It's great, right? Look...
You've learned this far, huh?
I'm okaaa~y!
Okay, okay...
Hang on a bit.
But I didn't expect you'd get married to Yoshio.
I thought that I made a smart choice this time.
It's possible that we may make some stupid
choices again now like we did in the past.
Koucchan...
I...
...don't do that kind of thing anymore.
It's just a joke.
Are you really serious,
bringing me to this place.
What are you saying at this late stage.
You don't even know my name.
It's Mariko-san, isn't it?
Is there any proof that
that is my real name?
When... when men and women do it, they don't
have to know each other's names, do they?
I hate strategizing...
What are you gonna do...
You have 1 minute to consider...
10 seconds...
20 seconds...
25 seconds...
Here's your change.
Hello. I'm sorry you had to see
us in a weird moment the other day...
Right now, we're going
to see her parents.
I see.
I finally realized it...
that she's the woman for me.
Well, good luck.
Yes. Thanks and see you then.
Thanks.
He's great.
While I'm... such an idiot.
Gimme liquor.
Sorry... I'm closing up now.
I'm ashamed to face Mizue.
What happened?
Master...
I... m-m--...
...made a mistake.
So what are you gonna do
when you see Mizue-san?
Hiraga-san, with freshwater clams too...
If you don't properly get rid of the sand,
you won't be able to make delicious soup.
Welcome. It's already done.
I must apologize to you.
The night we fought on the phone...
That night, right?...
I'm the one who has to apologize to you.
What! As I thought, you and he...?
Of course not!
That night...
I did some reflecting...
I needlessly gave you the wrong idea...
It was wrong of me to
make you jealous.
I should have given you a
bit more consideration.
Can you give me a chance?
It may take some time but...
I want to prove my feelings.
I'm gonna do my best so...
...please stay by my side.
Let's eat before it gets cold.
Master...
It's delicious.
There's more for seconds.
When removing sand from the clams,
add a bit of salt to fresh water.
Let the clams open completely and darken...
Then simmer over medium heat,
and add the miso when it's done.
"Remaining cooking time is 10 seconds."
"3... 2... 1..."
"Boo~m!"
'Master'
KOBAYASHI KAORU
'Hiraga Yoshio' - BENGAL
'Hiraga Mizue' - NAGASHIMA EIKO
'Yoshio's former classmate' - KOMIYA TAKAYASU
'Koichi' - KANO RYU
'Teshigahara Mariko' - SAKUMA YUI
'Mine' - OKUYAMA YUTA
'Mine's Girlfriend' - MOTOYAMA AYUMI
'Hachiro' - NAKAYAMA YUICHIRO
'Komichi' - UNO SHOHEI
'Rumi' - KOBAYASHI ASAKO
'Saya' - HIRATA KAORU
Original work:
"Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
Screenplay:
MUKAI KOSUKE
Planning:
ENDO HITOSHI / SHIBANO MASAYUKI
Producers:
TSUITSUI RYUHEI / OSANO TAMOTSU
ISHIZUKA SHOGO / TAKEZONO MOTO
OP Theme Song:
"Omoiizu"
by SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI
Theme song: 'Yakimochi'
by TAKAHASHI YU
(Warner Music Japan)
Art:
HARADA MITSUO
Title Logo Design:
BAY BRIDGE STUDIOS
Sound Supervisor / MA:
ASARI NAOKO
Organization:
TAKAHASHI TOSHIHIRO
Line Producer:
TAKAHASHI JUN
Photography:
OTSUKA RYO
Lighting:
KIMURA AKIO
Director:
MATSUOKA JOJI
Planning:
AMUSE / MBS
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT
GEEK SITE
A 2014 production of:
AMUSE / SHOGAKUKAN / TOEI / KINOSHITA GROUP
GEEK PICTURES / MBS / RKB
This drama is fictional