When people finish their day
and hurry home,
my day starts.
My diner is open from midnight
to 7:00 in the morning.
They call it "Midnight Diner."
PORK MISO COMBO, BEER, SAKE, SHOCHU
That's all I have on my menu.
But I make whatever customers request,
as long as I have ingredients for it.
That's my policy.
Do I even have customers?
More than you would expect.
MIDNIGHT DINER: TOKYO STORIES
SALMON AND MUSHROOMS
Here you go.
Here you are.
Everyone's so quiet.
Autumn is the best time for good food.
Here you go.
Grilled salted salmon
and mushrooms sauteed in butter.
I've been waiting for it.
This fragrance...
-Thank you.
Master, another whiskey sour, please.
Sure.
Mr. Uehara and Kimie are a married couple
who runs a barbershop
called Barber Uehara.
Sometimes they come here together.
The mushrooms are delicious.
The salmon is delicious, too.
Where are you two from?
I'm from Nemuro in Hokkaido.
I'm from Nagano.
Deep in the mountains of Kiso.
That explains your tastes.
My dad would often send me out
to hunt for mushrooms in the fall.
As a kid, a fisherman my family knew
used to give us fresh salmon every year.
By the way, Kimie,
you said you might travel to Shanghai
with your friend.
Are you going?
Yes, I decided to go.
When?
Day after tomorrow.
It's a five-night all-you-can-eat tour
to eat crabs.
I'm so jealous! I love Shanghai crabs.
This is the best season for them.
Here you are.
Are you staying home,
Mr. Uehara?
Yes.
Kimie has always wanted to go to Shanghai,
but we had to prioritize the business.
-It'll be a nice break.
-Yeah.
Well,
what a thoughtful husband!
It's only one week, so I'll be fine...
on my own.
That's what Mr. Uehara said,
but the day after Kimie left for Shanghai,
he started coming to my place
almost every night.
I'm fine when I'm in the shop,
but when I'm home alone,
I get restless and anxious.
It makes me want to go
somewhere with people.
Another beer, please.
Sure.
Kimie is out spreading
her wings in Shanghai,
so I think it's okay
if you do some unwinding, too. Right?
Don't worry about it.
Actually,
I just went to pachinko for
the first time in a long time.
I lost 30,000 yen.
You've unwound too much.
I got a little too deep.
Thank you.
Is Mr. Uehara going to be okay like that?
Don't worry about it.
Kimie will be back in a few days.
Welcome.
Good evening.
So you two are childhood friends?
We used to be neighbors.
When I was looking for someone to
teach my new staff how to put on kimonos,
we crossed paths again.
It was such a surprise.
It's been decades since we last met.
You teach how to put on kimonos?
Yes.
I lived in Kansai for a long time
after I had got married,
but my husband passed away last year,
and I came here.
Here you go.
You're very good.
Master, some pickles, please.
Sure.
My name is Sayoko Kagami.
It's nice to meet you.
Maybe it's just me, but...
you look like you've regained your youth.
That's amazing!
Can you tell?
Could it be love?
No!
I've been getting shaves.
Shaves?
You know Mr. Uehara who was just here?
He's a barber.
He's actually really good at it.
When he touches your face,
you can tell he has softer hands
than other men.
Especially the balls of his fingertips...
Welcome.
Are you closed already?
No.
I don't have a reservation.
Could I just ask for a shave?
Of course.
I'm sorry.
My earlobes are sensitive.
Should I stop?
No.
Keep going.
Yes.
Here's your change.
I'm sorry.
I've made you close late.
No, don't worry about it.
I heard about you at a restaurant.
Is that so?
It was better than expected.
Thank you very much.
Can you join me for dinner?
If you don't mind.
It's on me.
As thanks for staying open late.
No, it was nothing...
Actually...
I'm on my own tonight.
Please?
DINER
Were the Shanghai crabs good?
Yes, I ate as much as I possibly could.
This mooncake is really good.
In Japan we eat dango
while gazing at the moon,
but in China they eat these mooncakes.
Mr. Uehara was acting
a little strange while you were gone.
Really?
He's no good without his wife around.
Here you go.
Shanghai crabs are good,
but salmons are still my favorite.
This salmon is caught from wild
in the Sea of Okhotsk.
I'm so excited!
By the way, the woman who came here...
What's her name?
The childhood friend of the hostess.
Mrs. Sayoko, who teaches
how to put on kimonos.
Her.
Did she go to your shop?
No.
She was a real mature beauty, wasn't she?
That kimono sure suited her.
Master, can I have some rice, too?
Sure thing.
I'm glad to hear
you were able to relax, anyway.
Indeed.
I'm sorry for leaving everything to you
at the shop.
It was nothing.
Must be nice...
One moment please.
Hello, Barber Uehara.
I see. Just a shave?
At 3:00 tomorrow.
And your name?
Mrs. Sayoko Kagami.
My apologies.
We're looking forward to seeing you.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Are you okay?
I saw you dropped your razor.
I must be tired.
Did something happen while I was gone?
What do you mean?
I won't get mad,
so please just don't lie to me.
I'm sorry!
Kimie...
I...
I'm sorry.
This is the first time I've...
It's your fault.
Touching my face like that...
I completely lost my senses.
There are some things we have to do...
even if we know they're wrong.
Yes...
I'll go...
take a shower first.
Yes.
Can you...
put on kimonos?
No...
Men used to know how to do it.
They always made sure
a naked woman went home as a lady.
So, he's completely terrified.
His hands shake so much
he can't even hold a razor.
What a fool. It's so pitiful.
A former gangster's wife...
She must have kept the room dark.
But you'd think he would
still see her back, though...
No, normally, you'd definitely see it...
What's he doing now?
He left.
He's probably staying
in a capsule hotel or something.
Master, beer, please.
Sure.
Everything had been
going almost too smoothly.
We don't have kids,
so it's just the two of us
doing the same thing everyday,
over and over again.
Tell me, master.
What?
What sort of woman is Sayoko?
You met her, right?
Yeah.
Is she so beautiful that men
just can't help but want her?
I'm not sure.
She's coming tomorrow.
To the shop.
What?
I wonder how I'll feel.
Welcome.
I called in a reservation yesterday.
I'm sorry,
my husband is out on some urgent business.
I see.
Then...
could you do it for me instead?
Me? Are you sure?
Please.
You can, right?
Yes.
You're also very good.
Thank you.
I'll come again.
Ten years...
this shop has been open.
It was our dream...
to have our own shop even if it's small.
Is that so?
Therefore...
please don't come again.
Please.
My husband apologizes as well.
All right.
Give my regards to him.
Here you are.
That woman...
she knew that I knew.
But she fell asleep in the chair.
I was afraid my hands
would move on their own.
I'm glad you were able to talk things out.
Welcome.
I got on a train to go back to Nagano...
but I turned back halfway.
How selfish of you.
Sorry.
Try it if you like.
Salmon and mushrooms
are good on their own, but...
I think...
they're best together.
Come on.
Let's eat before they get cold.
No cheating next time.
Let's eat.
Cut a large piece of tinfoil,
and wrap up the ingredients tightly.
The aroma of the butter
will permeate the dish...
without losing the salmon
and mushrooms' flavors.
Master...
You wouldn't happen to know
a good barbershop, would you?
Don't tell her because the last place
prevented her from coming again.
I thought he might be good in bed, too.
He works with his hands after all.
What's so funny?
Can I talk to you for a minute?
What was it?
Let's not go there today.
Let's go somewhere else.
THIS STORY IS A WORK OF FICTION