~ Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ~
*Misty white breaths you exhale*
~ Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte ~
*Slowly blown by the wind now*
~ Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni ~
*Into the clouds in the sky*
~ Sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku ~
*Gradually fading away*
At the end of the day...
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above the sky*
When people are rushing home...
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above the sky*
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
That's when my day starts.
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
Do I ever get customers, you may ask?
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
I do get quite a few.
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
= SHINYA SHOKUDO (Season 2) =
"The Late Night Diner"
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
There are some customers who
make it a point...
...to come here because they want to order...
...a particular food they'd like to eat.
Here you go,
grilled sanma (mackerel pike).
I've been waiting for this...
That's why also in my diner...
I first heat up sanma...
...with sesame seeds and seaweed, then
I sprinkle it with szechuan pepper.
Good.
Welcome.
- Beer please.
- Sure thing.
I heard there was a new sale...
so I began lining up early this morning...
It was a one-day sale so I really
had to duke it out to get these.
What can you make from them?
Japanese-style grilled sardines...
And this... canned mackerel stir-fried
with tofu and bitter gourd.
You're really good.
You are surely the Master of creative cuisine.
Can we also ask for something?
It's still relatively okay to directly eat
canned pineapple.
But we want to see how you will cook it.
Will this do?
This isn't a pineapple dish...
...but sweet and sour pork
mixed with pineapple bits.
Well, sorry.
Anyway, we'll eat it now.
Delicious.
You don't get to see that
canned pineapple these days.
We just found it.
We were actually making an indie film
for our college's Film Club...
At that time, we were
scouting for a location...
To have closure, the woman who was killed
comes back to life so she can seek revenge...
...and to severely punish the professor with
whom she had an affair with...
...But the professor had escaped.
When the professor escapes,
he's running up the steps like this...
- How about it?
- That's a good idea!
What's this written sign mean?
What is it?
It says here 'Silk Path.'
Isn't that the 'Silk Road?'
But the Silk Road is in China, right?
- Yeah, that's right.
- It's in the desert.
What are those?
Were these thrown away?
But why are they stacked
up like this?
Maybe it means
we can choose from here.
What do they say...
the expiration dates?
It's totally safe...
I like this one.
Me, too.
I see...
But since it was arranged in a pile like that
don't you think it was rather strange?
You think so?
Well, looking at that perspective,
it does seem a bit strange.
Good evening.
Cold sake please.
Comin right up.
You want some?
I'm sorry... I just thought it
looked delicious, that's all.
It's okay, please go ahead.
Here.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Alright then.
It's delicious. I do love sweet
sour pork with pineapple.
Go ahead then.
Please have some more.
Alright.
You look like you're feeling sad
about something.
I dunno if she's pretending to smile
or she wants to cry...
...Just like me.
Kikuno-san... do you remember me?
You're Genki-kun, full of 'genki' (good health).
Can you play the heroine in my movie?
- 'Movie?'
- It's for our college's indie film club.
But I don't know how to act.
It doesn't matter.
Why me?
Because you seem lonely...
and also beautiful.
Let me think about it.
If you decide to accept...
Yuuki will be absolutely thrilled.
So, excuse me then, I'll
go back to my part-time job.
What was that about?
Great, you're here.
Do you remember me?
You're the person of 'yuuki' (courage), Yuuki-kun.
I want you to be the actress in my movie.
Isn't it Genki-kun's movie?
He's the cameraman.
I'm the writer and director.
So why me?
Because you seem sad, and moody.
And beautiful.
- Well, I'll think about it.
- If Kikuno-san will play the role...
I think Genki will surely feel
motivated to film the movie.
Sorry, but I have to go back to
my part-time work now.
Welcome.
I thought you said you're gonna watch a
late night movie? (Note: there are theaters
in Tokyo that show movies late at night)
Aren't you supposed to be at work?
Why'd you have to choose Kikuno-san?
You're the one who said
she's the best one for the role.
Well, anyway...
You can't confuse casting as
a way to pick up girls.
I just wanted to make good movie, okay?
It's not like I have some
ulterior motive.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
Can you do something with this?
Sure thing.
I'm not confident about my acting
but I'll give it a shot.
Really?
But why?
Because you said I'm pretty.
You'll really look great on film.
This is the script.
Do you like canned corned beef?
Yeah, I suddenly had the craving for it...
...so I took it from the offerings.
'Offerings?' As in from a grave?
Well, something like it.
Whose was it?
Mine.
My grave.
So you got it from your own grave.
Yes, it's weird, isn't it?
Were you able to call Kikuno-san?
"The number you're trying to reach
is no longer in use..."
"Please try checking
the number again."
How's your movie coming along?
We didn't want to look
for another actress any more.
We made drastic changes to the script
so we're taking out the heroine part.
But we won't be changing the
filming location. It'll still be in Yarimizu.
We'll just have to shoot it fast... like something
similar to the movie, 'Stand By Me.'
'Stand By Me...'
...Isn't that the movie about
a search for a dead body?
Yeah.
Did you know that Yarimizu is
one of Tokyo's most haunted places?
Oh, yeah?
In 1973...
...a college student was killed
and buried there.
She was having an affair
with her professor.
Their secret rendezvous was
a cottage in Yarimizu.
An affair?
Just like in your script, isn't it?
But their secret meeting was exposed.
As a matter of fact...
...it was the girl herself who snitched on
the wife by writing her a letter.
It was a foolish thing to do...
...but she had no other choice, right?
She found out she was pregnant.
But she didn't want the professor to
divorce his wife...
Instead she wanted to break up with him...
So out of desperation, he killed her.
Then, he and his family committed family suicide.
Her body was buried in the summer...
(Note: This is apparently based on a true story)
...and by the time it was discovered,
it was already snowing in wintertime.
(Note: This is apparently based on a true story)
She was wearing a pink dress.
Pink dress?
The two of them had been eating
canned food inside the cottage...
...while enjoying their torrid
love affair, huh?
The tabloids reported that there were...
...lots of empty cans left in the kitchen.
Speaking of which...
...didn't she say there were offerings
of canned goods by her grave?
So you mean Kikuno-san is...
...A ghost?
It's because we stole some of
those canned goods...
So then...
What is it?
Nothing.
What? Say it.
Actually, when I shot a video of that site...
Tomorrow, we should go
and give back canned pineapples.
Yeah, and maybe incense sticks, too.
Thanks for the meal.
So early...
you're leaving for somewhere?
You know what?
I was having an affair with my teacher.
While I was checking out the Silk Road*...
(*old Japanese silk trade route,
now a historical site)
...I learned that a college student was killed there.
(*old Japanese silk trade route,
now a historical site)
She's an 'another me.'
By the way...
I didn't mean...
...to play around with those guys
who were my age.
I just thought that if I make a
movie with them...
...I might be able to forget my teacher.
But when I read the script...
...it was about punishing the professor
she had an affair with.
You didn't want to punish him?
Sensei didn't seduce me...
...I seduced him.
So to end it...
...I have to be the one to do it.
I don't wanna be killed.
I don't want to kill either.
So I thought the only
thing to do was to kill myself.
But I couldn't do it.
So what're you gonna do?
I'm going on a trip.
I'll go to the sea and do some thinking.
Don't think of anything stupid.
You haven't had breakfast, right?
Yeah.
Here you go...
Special tuna mayo bowl.
Itadakimasu.
It's good.
You think she really was a ghost?
Just a customer who was
running away from home.
I really wanna see her ghost.
Whose ghost?
The female college student who was killed.
I liked her, you know...
...we were in the same seminar.
But my rival was a middle-aged guy...
...It was so frustrating.
Hey, long time, no see.
Hi... I'd like some beer please.
Sure thing.
You're looking tanned and
in much better spirits.
I had plenty of 'genki' and 'yuuki.'
- What're you doing?
- Something I learned over there.
- Master, can I borrow a match?
- Sure.
- Here.
- Thanks
Can you turn off the lights?
I had been doing volunteer work.
By the sea I saw...
...this mountain of garbage that made
me break out in sweat when I realized ...
...that my troubles were so little...
...that killing myself over such things
was the lowest act...
I feel so ashamed.
Welcome back.
You mix canned tuna with
finely-chopped onion, mustard...
...and mayonnaise.
And if you prefer it, you can add a little miso.
Then, simply serve on top of a bowl of rice.
Your tuna mayo bowl is done.
Please make something out
of this, Master.
Oh, we wanna eat sweet-sour pork.
So then, good night.
Goodnight.
~ Yarusenai yuhi yori ~
*More than the dreary sunset*
To be continued
~ Shinji reru asahi o mitai ~
*Rather see the sunrise to believe*
KOBAYASHI KAORU as 'Master'
~ Dakara sukoshi yume o mi sasete ~
*Let me dream a little*
SAORI as 'Kikuno'
SHIROMORI OKARYU as 'Genki'
~ Ashita e mukau tame ~
*So I can go on tomorrow*
MAENO TOMOYA as 'Yuuki'
SHIRO as 'Yuzuki'
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
FUWA MANSAKU as 'Chuu-san'
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Music: Satou Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by Suzuki Tsunekichi
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Food Stylist: Iijima Nami
Based on the manga by: Abe Yaro
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
Screenplay: Arai Haruhiko
and Arai Misa
Directed by: Yamashita Nobuhiro
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*