KOBAYASHI KAORU
YAMANAKA TAKASHI
TSUMIKI MIHO
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
SERIZAWA MEIJIN / AYATA TOSHIKI
FUWA MANSAKU / MATSUSHIGE YUTAKA
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
UNO SHOHEI / HIRATA KAORU / TAKAGI KEN
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
...That's when my day starts.
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
Director: YAMASHITA ATSUHIRO
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
Director: YAMASHITA ATSUHIRO
Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne
Always seems like a thing of the past
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
[MESHIYA]
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
EP 8: "Sauteed Burdock Root..."
Wouldn't it be better to rewrite your menu?
Change it to something like
"Porkish flavored miso soup."
Or "Pork soup impersonation."
Da hell's your problem?
Gen-san, do you like "kinpira" (sauteed veggies)
because you're a "chinpira" (thug)?
Just let it go. She doesn't know anything at all
about you getting teased in the past.
I'm sorry if I said something rude.
'Cause you're a woman,
I'll let ya off da hook.
If you were a man, I'd make you
bungee-jump off the Sky Tree.
Master, give Gen-san a drink...
I don't want it!
But let me treat you as a way of apologizing...
Gen-chan doesn't drink.
Despite having a scary face...
Be quiet.
But the beer...
He hasn't touched it.
What do you call that kind of thing again...?
Even though someone has a scary face,
yet he doesn't drink...
- It's "deceptive appearance"
(also, "mere front"), right?
- Ya wanna have a go, punk!!
You have till after I finish eatin to think of
the Buddhist name you want on your grave! Baldy!
I'm a Christian! I will repent!
What're ya sayin! I don't get cha!
I'm sorry!
Don't try changin your religion!
Do you have Kinpira Gobo*?
(*chopped burdock root,
sauteed in sugar and soy sauce)
I do.
I'm glad. Then Kinpira Gobo and
unheated alcohol right away please.
Sure thing.
Thanks for waiting.
This really is the way
that kinpira must be made.
Why is that?
'Cause it won't get crunchy unless
you cut it into strips.
I thought so too... Kinpira
should be shredded, right?
You like Kinpira, too?
Long time no see! Ichikawa-sensei.
You taught English at
Kawakita High School, didn't you?
I did, actually...
I'm Hayashi Gen.
You were our adviser in the handball club.
Are you the Gen-kun who was always
getting into fights?
I had eyebrows back then.
I didn't recognize you!
You've become quite a man, huh!
How many years has it been?
I don't know. I'm just a dumb guy.
No way!
Even though I call myself an interpreter,
compared to entertaining clients,
it's more like doing a guide's work.
Well, your level is really different.
While guys like me live an obscure life
in some rundown Shinjuku area such as this.
Do you know, Baldy?
She lives in New York,
the capital of USA.
Washington DC is the capital of the US...
Hah?
It's New York.
Coming home for the first time in 10 years...
I didn't expect to be reunited with you
straight away.
I wonder if this is some kind of fate.
You say you live with
a person over there...
Is it your husband?
A female friend who's a
co-worker of mine.
Did you think that it would be pathetic
if I were still single at this age?
Of course not!
You...
...haven't changed at all since those days.
My goodness, you've become
quite a flatterer, too huh.
But I'm glad.
Gen-kun, let's go to one more bar.
Okay!
He was such a handful,
what happened afterwards.
Gen-kun took me to a good bar
that he said he knows but...
I love you!!
Gen-kun, sit straight or you'll fall.
I said it!
Kosuzu-chan, another glass...
That's enough.
Why say that?
Don't you know that this
is how much I love you?!
Gen-chan!
Lower your voice. You're
disturbing the other customers.
Besides, your teacher won't
like you, you know.
But I love her so much!
Ouch!
If you call yourself a man, shape up!
Please do it again.
Please beat some sense into me! Please!
Please!
Then what happened?
I had no choice so I was forced to
get him out of the bar and let him
sleep at the hotel I'm staying.
He was puking until daybreak.
Welcome.
He's my companion.
Good evening.
My homeroom teacher in high school
has turned into a middle aged fogey.
He's my idol teacher.
Like yesterday, only the other way around.
Yeah. Master, can we stay there.
And can you give him another glass.
Sure thing.
Sorry I'm late.
I made reservations in Atami.
That's great.
Excuse me.
"This was the only time, I felt sincerely
relieved that Gen-chan wasn't around."
I'm so lost, there's so much to choose from.
I guess folks over there prefer
flashy patterns, don't they?
Is your work really okay
about you being here?
It's really no problem.
Don't worry about it.
How about this one.
Sparklers, huh...
It's too simple, isn't it.
How about fireworks...
with a more explosive "bang!" pattern.
Oh, right. Since that person's a cat lover,
maybe a cat pattern will do.
Oh, if it's animals,
there's some over there.
Nice, it's like flowers blooming in the shadows...
so ephemeral.
Give it to me. I want to see it, too.
Hey, don't dirty it.
Oh, how cute!
Wonder if it really suits Gen-chan.
Anyway...
...it suits me, doesn't it?
Gen-chan, does your teacher know
your line of work?
Told her I'm into liberal employment.*
(*Like free lance or self-employed).
Well, the yakuza is like liberal employment
in a way so it's not a lie. Right?
What a woman hates the most is
a guy keeping secrets from her.
I know that. I'm just waiting
for the right time to tell her.
Thank you.
When is your teacher going back?
She said she'll be here for two weeks,
I think that was 4 to 5 days ago.
Aren't you gonna call her now?
She's busy.
She goes out every night with old friends, and has
to take care of them when they get too drunk.
It sounds like she came back home
to say goodbye or something...
What does that mean?
Either way, you have no choice
but to wait for your turn.
After three days,
Gen-chan's turn finally came.
Tastes good, right?
Yeah.
You're not gonna drink today, huh.
I'm sorry. You saw my disgraceful behavior
the other day.
Hello.
Yeah... I'm eating now.
Okay, I'll call you later.
Don't mind me, I'm fine.
I'll just eat and go home anyway.
It's not that. I was planning to go to Atami tomorrow
with someone but I can't contact him at all.
I guess it's off.
Is he your boyfriend?
A guy from my past.
Anyway, his wife is scary.
Wonder what I should do now...
Um...
I wonder if I'm okay...?
...to go to Atami...
With you?
Are you okay with that? Going with such a hag.
Of course, it's fine.
You ain't a hag at all!
Imma kill anyone who calls you that!
He's even a handful here, huh? Master.
It's not just with his school teacher.
Thank you.
Don't be late tomorrow, okay?
I'm not a kid anymore.
Yeah. Good night.
Good night.
I'm sorry. I had a bit of a problem at work...
But it's okay. I can go with you tomorrow.
A friend of yours?
A former student.
I see. I'll help you to your room.
Are you angry?
Of course, she's angry, Senpai.
She's been waiting for your call.
So please...
...try to cherish her more.
Please.
Gen-kun...
You too Sensei, don't be so stubborn.
Just go with him so you'll feel happy.
Just buy me some dried fish
when you get back.
If you'll excuse me.
Don't go!
Why...
It's okay.
I'm being a fool, considering how he and I both
are already past our expiration dates.
Um, I've been hiding
something from you. Actually...
You're a Yakuza, aren't you? No matter
how much I look, I can't see you as
anything more than a respectable man.
You really don't mind if I am one?
In return, please stay with me tonight.
Huh?
I was going to hold off until tomorrow,
but I don't have a lot of time left so...
Let's enjoy it to the fullest.
Okay.
When I dropped out of high school to go to Tokyo...
Sensei's farewell words to me then were
"Come back a good man."
She's a good teacher, huh.
She then gave me her own lunch pack
and told me to eat it in the train.
There were other dishes in it but...
This dish's sweet and salty taste
was the only one that stuck with me...
I...
...want to quit the yakuza
and make her happy.
After I confided to Aniki...
...he punched me in the face and
told me that it's the other way around.
That, "The woman's the one
who'll make YOU happy."
She's leaving tomorrow, right?
Have you told her how you feel?
But...
I don't want to become
just another memory for her.
Welcome.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
That's just between us, okay?
What? What were you talking about?
More importantly,
how's your friend doing?
Huh?
Didn't you say you paid a visit to a friend
of yours who's hospitalized. Is she okay?
Yeah, I was surprised to see how
healthy she was. She'll be discharged next month.
Oh, that's great. Let's toast to it then.
Master, give us two glasses of beer.
Will you be okay?
Not drinking at an auspicious occasion,
what good is a man if he doesn't drink
in celebration of something.
When are you coming back again?
Not sure.
Gen-chan's gonna be lonely.
Can I have a smoke?
Over in the US, I heard that
it's frowned upon if you're a smoker.
I tried quitting when I went there,
but it doesn't matter anymore.
I can't remember anymore.
That time when I met him here, if he didn't
say he's Gen-kun, I wouldn't have remembered.
Are you planning to stay in the US forever?
No. This time, I'm going some place
farther away.
That's why I hope Gen-kun
will forget about me.
Hey, Gen-kun... Let's go.
Goodbye.
He was working earnestly when
I sneaked a look today.
Never expected he'd quit
the life of a gangster.
Isn't it almost a month by now?
I too want to have a love
that's worth changing his life for me.
In that case, eat this, Saya-chan.
If this is the answer to
my prayer, it'll do but...
(Note: Gen most likely asked here: "She's dead?"
Also, he's wearing the towel / head scarf
his teacher gave him)
'Master'
KOBAYASHI KAORU
'Gen'
YAMANAKA TAKASHI
'Ichikawa Chizuru'
TSUMIKI MIHO
'Chizuru's companion' - SERIZAWA MEIJIN
'Kosuzu' - AYATA TOSHIKI
'Chuu-san' - FUWA MANSAKU
'Ryu Kenzaki' - MATSUSHIGE YUTAKA
'Komichi' - UNO SHOHEI
'Saya' - HIRATA KAORU
'Customer' - TAKAGI KEN
Original work:
"Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
Screenplay:
MANABE KATSUHIKO
Planning:
ENDO HITOSHI
SHIBANO MASAYUKI
Producers:
TSUITSUI RYUHEI / OSANO TAMOTSU
ISHIZUKA SHOGO / TAKEZONO MOTO
OP Theme Song:
"Omoiizu"
by SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI
Theme Song:
'Yakimochi' by TAKAHASHI YU
(Warner Music Japan)
Food Stylist:
IJIMA NAMI
Art:
HARADA MITSUO
Title Logo Design:
BAY BRIDGE STUDIOS
Sound Supervisor / MA:
ASARI NAOKO
Director:
MATSUOKA JOJI
Planning:
AMUSE / MBS
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT / GEEK SITE
A 2014 production of:
AMUSE / SHOGAKUKAN / TOEI / KINOSHITA GROUP
GEEK PICTURES / MBS / RKB
This drama is fictional