When people finish their day
and hurry home,
my day starts.
My diner is open from midnight
to 7:00 in the morning.
They call it "Midnight Diner."
Do I even have customers?
More than you would expect.
MIDNIGHT DINER: TOKYO STORIES
CRAB AND TOSHIKOSHI SOBA
Just kidding!
Look! It's a doggy mailman!
Let go!
-Let go!
-Ouch!
Just what I needed!
Thanks for stopping me,
I almost lost a lot of money.
You won't last in this job if you
get mad at something like that.
But I much prefer the mascot uniform.
It's better than doing weird cosplay.
Is the pay different?
Cosplay is 100 yen more.
A little while back,
I was a cheerleader at a
home supplies shop in Ibaraki.
-For real?
-It was under the table.
The train fare alone was 2,000 yen.
That's like a day trip!
How much is this ramen, again? 10 yen?
No, it's 750 yen. Including tax.
Really?
What's your name?
-Noriko.
-Nori-chan.
I'm Gen.
I'll treat you tonight.
-Are you sure?
-Of course.
-Really?
-Yeah.
I haven't seen a
coffin-shaped piggy bank in ages.
It's for my winnings at the horse track.
It sure is hard to save money.
Your part-time job is rough, right?
It's a job where you don't need
to prove your identity, right?
It must be a rough group you work with.
But not the girl you're talking about?
Yeah... she's super hard-working,
almost as if this job is
the only thing she's got.
You make gratin so rarely!
There was a sale on macaroni today.
Try it.
It's delicious!
-It's warming me up!
-Hot!
By the way, Master,
how's this year's crab?
It should be soon.
My friend... is getting me some good ones.
I'm so excited!
I've got an idea, Gen.
Why don't you bring her here?
I'm sure she'd love to try Master's food.
That's true.
Yes!
This tempura is much better than
the ones you can find out there.
Do you have any more of these?
I gave them all away.
I'll bring some next time.
Here you go, fried udon.
When did I turn into a son-in-law?
What do you mean?
I showed Saori how to make soba,
and my mom said hers was better than mine.
Is it that different?
No, I think it's just a matter of taste.
But, in fact, some customers have asked
for Saori's soba instead of mine.
Our deliveries have even gone up.
Why's she so popular?
Your mother's happy about it, right?
She's calling Saori her "next-in-line."
You've been replaced!
I'm supposed to take over the business,
but now I've lost my motivation.
Thanks for the food.
Thank you for today.
Let's get something to eat.
That place over there is good.
What... That one?
-You know it?
-No...
I don't...
Let's go, then. My treat.
Aren't you hungry?
I am.
You are?
Then let's go.
Are you cold?
No, I think I caught a cold.
Here you go.
Master, this is the girl
I was telling you about.
Nori-chan.
Cheers.
Shall I turn up the heat?
No, I'm fine.
Order what you like.
He can make almost anything.
What do you want?
-I'll have...
-Stewed meat and potatoes, right?
It's been a while.
What?
-What is it?
-A few years ago,
this girl was involved in a marriage scam
with her older sister.
One of my customers fell victim to them.
I served a three-year sentence.
I meant to come sooner, but...
And your sister?
After getting out of jail,
she went back to Hokkaido.
I never imagined it was you
Gen was talking about.
Try my stewed meat and potatoes.
You haven't had it for a while.
Thank you.
Wow...
It hasn't changed at all.
This is it!
You've served your time,
so you don't need to be embarrassed.
Do you have any other work?
I tried everywhere,
but the three-year gap
in my résumé is hard to explain.
Write whatever, then.
I don't want to lie anymore.
I've already hurt enough people.
Master, shochu and oolong tea, please.
Sure.
Ready?
The key is snapping.
You have to tense up your wrist.
Shall we try farther away?
Excuse me. Sorry.
Ready?
Don't give me that.
Why are you skipping work?
I wanted some fried udon.
Are you busy?
Isn't that obvious?
You and my mom will
do just fine without me.
What? Are you pouting?
Maybe it would've been better
if we didn't get together.
Excuse me.
What a child!
It's Christmas Eve, and all customers
who purchase a cake worth over 2,000 yen
will be given a free macaron
of your choice!
Did you buy your cake?
Thank you very much!
We should get going.
-Good night.
Excuse me!
Yes?
Nice to meet you.
I have good news and bad news.
Which would you like to hear first?
Neither.
The bad news is you caught my eye.
That was unlucky.
But the good news will make you
forget all about that.
I saw the way you were working.
In a world where most people
are cruel and unthoughtful,
I see a golden halo...
glowing around your head.
Do you want to be a model?
I'm absolutely sure that
you would be a success.
Do you really think I would
fall for something like--
Let me give you...
your contract fee.
-What are you doing?
-Yes?
-Who are you?
-I'm...
What's this?
Ouch! Ouch! Ouch!
Stop it!
What are you doing?
Let's go, Nori-chan.
Hey!
Don't touch it! Go away!
I knew it was a scam, but...
when I saw the money
I couldn't control myself.
I'm so embarrassed.
I have a record, too.
I've served time.
We need to take care of ourselves, right?
Yes.
It's a little early, but...
here's a Christmas present.
For both of you.
Are you sure?
By "present," you mean it's free, right?
Let me know if you want more.
There are lots.
Let's dig in, then!
Thank you!
Delicious.
What's this?
This is the real deal!
Master, it's amazing!
This is free, right?
Welcome, welcome!
Japanese! Japanese!
Traditional goods. Very lucky.
You can choose anything you like.
They're great for souvenirs!
-Must buy. Must buy.
-Must buy.
Thank you very much!
-Happy New Year!
-How much?
What's it called again?
That scam where men
show off a bunch of money...
to fool women into selling themselves?
The soul-snatching scam.
SOUL-SNATCHING SCAM = SOUL SCAM
That's where that other scam was busted two years ago.
You think scam artists
always use the same locations?
People like that think
they're smarter than us.
That's been my experience.
Good evening.
Sorry to call you at such a busy time.
You'll need help if you want to make
even more soba than last year.
Usually I'm given some,
but I didn't get any this year.
I want to make sure I have enough.
I'm hungry...
Saori made the soba today.
"Proprietress-to-be of Sobasei."
I'm getting excited.
Soba tastes different
depending on how it's made.
Master, can you make
this year's New Year's soba with tempura?
Tempura was shop-bought,
if you don't mind.
Aren't you avoiding fried foods?
I'm going to at least treat myself
at the end of the year.
They just go so well together!
It's about time to boil the noodles...
Master!
What is it?
We had extra shrimp,
so I brought them to make tempura.
Thanks, but it's difficult to do it here.
Master, two hot sakes, please.
Sure!
The aroma of soba is wonderful.
The tempura is delicious, too!
Master did cook it himself.
-He's too good!
-Right?
You can't beat the tempura...
from a soba shop.
Is this from a soba shop?
This is amazing!
We need two more servings.
Sure.
Master said those were for us.
Good work.
Thanks. You, too.
It doesn't taste like real Sobasei
if one of us is missing.
Thank you.
Move along, please.
Don't stop. Keep going.
Careful, please.
If you stand still,
you might loose things in life.
What happened, Kogure?
I'm sorry for the bother.
I'll tell you later when
I stop by for some soba.
Step back, please. Don't line up.
Save the lining up for when you make
offerings at the shrine tomorrow.
It sounds like the police.
It's cold. Let's go back.
That's an unlucky spot.
The New Year is coming,
you should all go home.
Nothing to see here.
The guy with wads of cash!
I'm glad they got him before the New Year.
Let's leave this year's sins behind.
It's the New Year.
But...
they say you mix the year's bad luck
into the soba and eat it to get rid of it.
So, isn't it bad
we didn't finish it in time?
I don't think it's a problem.
Think of it like,
"Last year's bad luck is over,
and we'll do better this year."
I was really impressed with your work.
Thank you for your leadership.
I was just lucky.
Cops' intuitions...
are like human emotions:
you can't rely on them.
You know...
I get the feeling that...
this is my last case.
It's snowing!
It's freshly made!
It was difficult to get here.
Who wants to roll it out?
Can I?
-Like this?
-Yes, gently.
You should cut it.
What?
That's your job.
I'm here to grill it, not to cut it.
What is it?
Delicious.
It's so good!
-It's delicious.
-Here you go.
When people finish their day
and hurry home,
my day starts.
My diner is open from midnight
to 7:00 in the morning.
They call it "Midnight Diner."
Do I even have customers?
More than you would expect.