KOBAYASHI KAORU
TANIMURA MITSUKI
MITSUISHI KEN
SHINOHARA YUKIKO
AYATA TOSHIKI
FUWA MANSAKU
MATSUSHIGE YUTAKA
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
NAKAYAMA YUICHIRO / ANDO TAMAE / YAMANAKA TAKAHASHI
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
SUDO RISA / KOBAYASHI ASAKO / YOSHIMOTO NAHOKO
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
KIYOBUMI KANEKO / UNO SHOHEI / YOSHIMI YUKIHIRO
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
KIYOBUMI KANEKO / UNO SHOHEI / YOSHIMI YUKIHIRO
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
SHUHEI TAKAHASHI / KAWASE YOTA
OGURA KENTO / ISHIZAWA EMI
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
SHUHEI TAKAHASHI / KAWASE YOTA
OGURA KENTO / ISHIZAWA EMI
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
ODAGIRI JOE
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
...That's when my day starts.
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
Director: MATSUOKA JOJI
Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne
Always seems like a thing of the past
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
[Pork Miso Soup Set ¥600, Beer ¥600, Sake ¥500, Shochu ¥400,
Alcoholic drinks are limited to 3 servings]
These are the only items on the menu.
[Pork Miso Soup Set ¥600, Beer ¥600, Sake ¥500, Shochu ¥400,
Alcoholic drinks are limited to 3 servings]
If one orders something aside from these...
...I'll make it if I can.
Such is my business philosophy.
[MESHIYA]
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
EP 10: "Crossing the Year Soba..."
On New Year's Eve, I open
the shop earlier than usual.
Why, you ask?
There's quite a number of customers
who spend New Year's Eve at my shop.
That's why I have make to
preparations ahead of time.
So you were born in Aizu (in Fukushima), huh?
It's pretty obvious from my
license plate, isn't it?
Well, yes.
Is there a problem with
the prefecture number?
I wonder if you were taught this in school...
Don't you know the "Beware of incoming guns and
outgoing women" policy? You know...
"Outgoing women" as in women leaving.
(Note: During the Edo period, guards are tasked to watch out for guns coming in the capital, and warlords' wives leaving which might be signs of a rebellion against the Shogunate)
How should I know...
I like Urabandai (in Fukushima).
My uncle's second wife's cousin is
from Nekoma (also in Urabandai, Fukushima).
But I only stopped for a minute...
The law is strict, isn't it?
Can you please overlook i~t?
Those words aren't altogether bad.
So it's okay?
I can't help but like the sound of it.
When someone is driven to a corner,
he stretches out the last syllable.
Here you go, sir.
Welcome.
You're open even on New Year's Eve?
It's "no leisure for the poor" for you, too huh?
Do you want to eat Crossing-the-Year Soba?
I just made a fresh batch.
Already been given enough soba.
You can have it.
Besides, I only eat udon.
Thank you.
In exchange, I'll treat you
to some benishoga tempura.
Maybe next time. I'm busy today.
You have work?
Well, something like that. This period
is a good time to make a profit.
See you.
Kasumi-san! You're leaving already?
You reacted too early.
In life, timing is everything.
You can't rely on luck alone.
Well then, Happy New Year.
Happy New Year, too.
In Osaka, they eat
Crossing-the-Year Udon instead, right?
Well, I wonder...
Master, can you give me
Kasumi-san's soba?
She didn't make it though.
It's okay.
I'll feel that a bond between us will be
born through that soba.
I don't mind though.
Good evening.
Welcome.
How rare of you two
coming in together.
We just happened to meet at the station.
It's handmade soba.
My client gave it to me.
Mine, too. My boss makes exquisite soba and
insists that I should try it.
So you want me to cook them?
He wants to know what I think of it.
Same for me. We'd like to eat it later, so
we'll leave this with you now to take care of?
Thanks.
It's true that homemade soba
is popular, huh?
It's become the hobby of the retired man.
There's been a lot of training
courses and even lessons on DVD.
It also doesn't require much money,
and you do get kinda fixated on it.
Its meaning is quite profound
as well, isn't it?
But still I wonder if we'll become like
that too when we get old.
We definitely will, once things
start to not go so well at home.
But even if we don't have a family...
Though it's New Year's Eve,
we're here, right?
We're spending it together
again this year, huh?
- It's good.
- Mine, too.
- So early!
- Welcome.
Here, Master.
Don't tell me this is...
I got it from a patient.
He said he was able to get soba from the famous shop in
Nagano that you're only able to get enough for one person.
Can you cook it quickly?
Master, make mine with tempura.
How about you, Kimi-kun?
With egg for me.
Sure thing.
- Delicious, right?
- It sure is!
It's quite firm and tasty.
Let's exchange for a bit.
Kimi-kun, can I eat the yolk?
Sure.
There's nothing to do anymore.
Why don't we just drink?
Yeah.
Master, ginger ale and beer.
Sure thing.
Wanna play?
You don't, right?
What's with you, boys?
Sitting together with long faces like that.
Come on. Let's play.
- You want to play?
- Yeah. We do, right?
Oh, of course.
Let's play.
Oh, you're the Old Maid.
No peeking please.
Okay okay.
Kimi-kun, which one will you pick?
Master, gimme hot liquor.
Sure thing.
It's quite cold outside.
You should just stay at home and sleep under
the kotatsu. You're going to catch a cold again.
No mistaking that.
You went around town?
Just a while ago, I ended up spending
the otoshidama* at the pachinko shop.
(*money gifts for children; it probably means he
gambled away the money meant for his grandkids)
My chest already feels cold.
Do you wanna join in?
Really, guys. What're you doing
on this New Year's Eve...
This ain't a middle school excursion.
There's nothing to do.
Well, even so.
Oh, I almost forgot...
Excuse me for a while.
Master, I received this from my hometown.
It's made with soba flour
so it's a bit dry but...
I still want to eat it sometimes.
If you could please cook it for me...
Thanks for waiting.
Okay, time out first. Time out.
Aren't you gonna chew?
Chuu-san, you might choke on it.
You see, the way to savor soba is
to let it slide down your throat.
Welcome.
Good evening.
Crossing-the-Year Zaru Soba* please, for three.
(*without soup)
Oh, can you make it to go?
You want MY soba?
Well, of course.
Sure thing!
This wasabi was raised in a clear stream,
a natural product of Amagi (Shizuoka prefecture).
Please.
You can either dissolve it in the sauce
or put it on your soba.
Thank you~.
It's handmade soba with authentic wasabi.
Isn't this quite a luxury?
We usually only eat soba
from stand-only stalls...
In the past, soba was originally food for common people.
It's shameful to not eat it at those stand-only stalls.
Now is the time that it's super spicy.
Please don't slurp it all at once.
You shoulda told me earlier!
The year is already ending.
Sliding to home base... safe!
- We made it in time.
- Welcome.
Kosuzu-san, what about your shop?
I want to spend the New Year here, so I kicked out
my stubborn customers and closed the shop.
Master, one bowl of soba please.
- How about you, Koucchan?
- Can I have jumbo size?
Of course. Master, one jumbo bowl please.
- Sure thing.
- Can I have hot soba?
Me too!
This time, I want the ones you made, Master.
Same goes for us.
Guess I'll have some, too.
Make it light.
Sure thing!
Everyone, I wish you all
a Happy New Year.
Happy New Year!
Hoping for your continued patronage.
- Best regards, too.
- Let's continue to get along.
- Let's have a great year.
- Peaceful year to you.
Thank you so much.
Here you go.
Well, so then... Instead of a New Year's
greeting, let's make a toast.
- Hang on--
- Wait for us!
Thank you~.
Then, to a new start... Cheers!
Cheers!
[Alcoholic drinks are limited to 3 servings]
[Happy New Year]
Is it okay, Master?
This is my New Year's gift to you all.
Ryucchan!
It's ready.
You try it.
Go ahead! Go ahead!
- I do wanna try!
- Do your best!
Do your best!
Ready, set...
I'm doing it! I'm doing it!
Next, Master.
Go, Master!
No thanks. I have to make
the preparations now.
For this?
(*To make zoni or rice cake soup)
Then, I'll do it instead.
You can do it, Sister!
You're affected by these
lovebirds beside me, right?
Don't worry. 'Cause you'll meet a good man
this year, and get married.
It's not that.
It's just... I feel so happy
being with everyone like this.
You're right. This is what you call
"an irreplaceable time."
Yeah, I think so too.
And, to think that sooner or later,
everyone of us will die one by one...
Life is really...
...Ephemeral.
- Right?
Why be so sentimental?
Being sentimental doesn't suit you ladies.
You still have more...
..."meters" or um... "kilometers",
there's still... so much more ahead...
Eh? Oh, no!
Oh, God! You okay!
Kosuzu-san!
Ready, set...!
Huh? Did you hear a firing shot?
You're just hearing things.
Shall we drink?
We mustn't drink.
Excuse me. There's some middle-aged guy
on the side of road, who dislocated his shoulder...
...after high-fiving many people.
He kept moaning,
"It popped out! It popped out!"
Well, we better pop it back in!
Yeah. Where's this guy.
This way.
This isn't altogether bad either.
Master, second helping of zoni, please!
- Me, too!
Oh, me too!
Sure thing!
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
...That's when my day starts.
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
Master, is mine not ready yet?
Ah, wait just a bit more.
- Okay.
- It'll be ready soon.
Welcome.
Good evening.
Mm. It's really delicious.
Is there anything you want?
Could you sing "Don't Say Anything"
once again? For my wife.
Master, give me menchi!
Do you yourself find this interesting?
To be honest, it's boring.
You said that you'd quickly
become a mangaka and go pro!
When the time comes that you feel you
really want to draw...then you should draw again.
Can we see each other
with the premise of marriage?
My feelings, you see...
are not that simple.
Being scornful?
If you do not become strong,
you won't live, right?
President.
Beniten.
My mom said..."Don't become
just a cheap mistress."
The truth is I hated vermicelli salad.
But since Shiga-kun loved it...
...I thought, I'll come to like it, too I guess.
Shiga-kun told me he loves me.
What?
Cabbage Rolls take time and effort.
Your boobs were exactly like mine
when I was younger.
You're like a balloon who floated
from one man to another...
You're not qualified to say
whether a man is good or bad!
Your mother had taught me her recipe.
I had wanted to eat
my mom's Cabbage Rolls.
Thanks for waiting.
Everyone says that freshwater clam soup is
a good midsummer dish for the body.
Do you like Go?
I have no idea how it goes.
I always fall asleep when watching it.
It's possible that we may make
some stupid choices again...
Can you give me a chance?
If you don't properly get rid of the sand,
you won't be able to make delicious soup.
Do you have Kinpira Gobo?
But I love her so much!
Ouch!
Don't go!
Mine's the Liver with Chives.
And mine's the Chinese Chives with Liver.
But you also look at me a bit lewdly...
He's my fiance.
Guragura kuru.
This isn't altogether bad either.
Excuse me, excuse me please.
Huh? What's happening?
We just received a tip-off.
They said it'll become a movie.
Well, it's about time!
If there's anything you like to order...
I'll make it if I can.
Such is my business policy.
If you ever come to this area...
and chance upon this "Meshi-ya"...
...Feel free to come in!
'Master'
KOBAYASHI KAORU
'Kasumi' - TANIMURA MITSUKI
'Noguchi' - MITSUISHI KEN
'Natsuki Izumi' - SHINOHARA YUKIKO
'Kosuzu' - AYATA TOSHIKI
'Chuu-san' - FUWA MANSAKU
'Ryu' - MATSUSHIGE YUTAKA
'Hachiro' - NAKAYAMA YUICHIRO
'Marilyn' - ANDO TAMAE
'Gen' - YAMANAKA TAKAHASHI
'Miki' - SUDO RISA
'Rumi' - KOBAYASHI ASAKO
'Kana' - YOSHIMOTO NAHOKO
'Hachiro' - KIYOBUMI KANEKO
'Komichi' - UNO SHOHEI
'Koucchan' - YOSHIMI YUKIHIRO
'Kimitoshi' - SHUHEI TAKAHASHI
'Driver' - KAWASE YOTA
'Couple': OGURA KENTO / ISHIZAWA EMI
'Kogure'
ODAGIRI JOE
Original Work:
"Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
Screenplay:
MANABE KATSUHIKO
Planning:
ENDO HITOSHI
SHIBANO MASAYUKI
Producers:
TSUITSUI RYUHEI / OSANO TAMOTSU
ISHIZUKA SHOGO / TAKEZONO MOTO
OP Theme Song:
"Omohide"
by SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI
Theme Song:
'Yakimochi' by TAKAHASHI YU
(Warner Music Japan)
Art: HARADA MITSUO
Title Logo Design: BAY BRIDGE STUDIOS
Food Stylist: IJIMA NAMI
Sound Supervisor / MA: ASARI NAOKO
Organization:
TAKAHASHI TOSHIHIRO
Music:
SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI / FUKUHARA KIMIE
HINAMI KEISUKE / SUMA
Photography:
OTSUKA RYO
Lighting:
KIMURA AKIO
Subtitles by WABI-SABI SUBS
Translation:
EARTHCOLORS
WILKI
Spot Check / QC: WILKI
Editing / Timing / Styling: EARTHCOLORS
Special thanks:
RUELL
VAMPIREXxX
XOXO
Director:
MATSUOKA JOJI
Planning:
AMUSE / MBS
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT
GEEK SITE
A 2014 production of:
AMUSE / SHOGAKUKAN / TOEI / KINOSHITA GROUP
GEEK PICTURES / MBS / RKB
This drama is fictional
Thanks for watching~!