KOBAYASHI KAORU
ISHIBASHI KEI
FUCHIGAMI YASUSHI
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
...That's when my day starts.
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne
Always seems like a thing of the past
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
EP 3: "Simmered Taro and Squid..."
During days when I make too much
amount of some simmered dish...
...sometimes, I heat it up and let
the aroma waft throughout the shop.
Boiled taro and squid?
You got it. Acute sense of smell
as always, huh? Satomi-san.
I'll have that please.
Ah, me too.
Sure thing.
This is also my business tactic.
Master, it's delicious!
Glad you like it.
Somehow, these two make a good combination.
Order something,
don't hold yourself back.
No... Somehow, I don't feel like eating.
As I thought, you're not suited for it.
Is he a newbie?
He's undergoing training. Sasaki-kun.
Honestly...
I didn't expect that much
cheating and adultery...
...to happen so often.
It's human instinct, isn't it?
It's 'cause we whitewash
the shackles of marriage...
...that's why it becomes a hassle.
What do you guys do?
Private investigation agency.
We investigate cheatings and such.
Oh, you're investigators huh.
No wonder, you have a keen nose.
But Satomi-san...
...why did you try this kind of work?
I can't talk enough about such
a thing with just one bottle of alcohol.
Master, give us more alcohol.
I only serve up to 3 bottles, okay?
Though he did say he couldn't hold his liquor,
didn't expect it to be this early.
Pathetic, huh?
He graduated from a top university...
...and seemed to be doing his
work properly at first but...
...somehow, he suddenly became
afraid to go to the office.
Why?
He says he was probably unsuccessful
in establishing human relations but...
Of all things...
...he wants to quit his job of
investigating the dark side of people.
Sasaki-kun, wake up.
We're going home.
Are you all right?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Taxi!
That kind of gal is the
"handsome" type of woman, right?
But a gal like her...
...doesn't want to become someone's partner.
Still, I wasn't sure what
goes on between men and women.
I never bought a takarakuji (lottery ticket).
It's like buying "a castle in the air". Right?
That kind of thing is a "tanuki*", isn't it?
(*craftiness; also, raccoon dog).
"Tanuki"?
It's just a "kara-kuji" after all.
Look... if you take away the
"ta" from "takarakuji"...
Oh, then it's "karakuji" (losing ticket)...
Geez, Chuu-san, I can't laugh at your puns,
they're too confusing.
You just lack education.
Good evening.
Welcome.
- Hello.
- Hey.
Master, beer please.
She's the "handsome" woman
I talked about before.
Here you go.
That guy from before, was he okay?
He got really drunk.
I was surprised.
...Sasaki-kun was a virgin.
Eh?
Missy, you did it with him?
Well, kinda.
But it was his first time.
He's no longer coming to work.
Nor replying to my emails...
I wonder if it made matters worse.
Was it a good thing...
or a bad thing...
Hasn't he been here?
He hasn't.
For now, I'm waiting for his reply.
Sasaki-kun.
Did you read my messages?
Satomi-san...
Um...
Can we...
...see each other
with the premise of marriage?
What?
Huh? Why do you want to get
married to me?
Because that night...
Are you stupid?
We only slept once.
Satomi-san, don't you like me?
You slept with me
and yet you're not interested in me?
Why are you saying stuff
that a woman would say?
In the first place, I have no interest in marriage.
My feelings, you see...
are not that simple.
Am I right? She's "handsome", isn't she.
She's too "handsome".
That kind of woman may readily
open up her body but... not her heart.
A long time ago, there was...
...a pure girl who never suspected anyone.
That girl had a wonderful fiancé.
One day, the girl had seen her fiancé...
...get inside a cab by chance...
Feeling mischievous...
...she thought to try and follow the cab.
It's 'cause the girl loved detective dramas.
And then...
...what happened?
The girl...
...saw where her fiancé does his cheating.
From then on...
...she tailed the fiancé on a daily basis.
Eventually, she got addicted
to the tailing itself...
That's how she came to work
in a detective agency.
And... the fiancé?
The girl collected proofs of cheating...
...claimed palimony,
and canceled the engagement.
Sasaki-kun.
Yes.
A person cannot survive if he is not strong.
Here. Next is a cheating investigation.
Why do people make mistakes?
I'd like to think that if mistakes are impenetrable,
it would become the correct answer.
You have a point.
Say, why don't we let
Sasaki-kun handle this one?
Him?
Yeah.
It'll be his graduation exam to
become regular employee.
Is that Karei no nitsuke (simmered flounder)?
Sorry. Here you go.
I was close.
Difference is that it's "Kareh", huh?
(Curry or "karee" and "karei" almost sound the same)
Weren't you totally way off the mark?
How's work going?
Well... it's tiring but...
somehow, I'm doing okay.
However, Satomi-san...
...had been cold to me ever since that day....
Really? When she came here
alone the other day...
...she praised you by saying,
"He's been working really hard".
Is that true?
Hopefully, if my next investigation will go well...
...I'll formally be recognized
as an investigator.
And then, once again...
...I'm going to confess to Satomi-san.
I see... She praised me huh?
Master, hot liquor please.
Will you be okay?
I want to drink.
Thanks for the hard work.
It's Yoshino.
- Welcome.
- Good evening.
Did you wait long?
No.
Thanks.
You investigated it well.
This person was my former fiance.
Two years ago, I met him by chance
for the first time in 10 years.
Life is a mystery, huh?
Though I broke up with him for cheating...
Now I'm the one who's... Right?
Don't you think this is bad?
His wife and children, and all...
Not at all.
Well then, what is this for?
This work of ours.
This so-called "Wanting to know the truth"...
...Isn't it human instinct?
I don't...
...get you.
I realized that I am more at ease
betraying people than be betrayed.
For the last 10 years.
Once I report this...
...do you know what will happen?
Of course.
Is that okay with you?
Yes.
Please let me ask one last question.
Why are okay with this guy...
and not me?
Maybe we're like taro and squid.
We go well together. Somewhat.
Excuse me.
No need.
Is that okay?
Am I contemptible?
If you do not become strong,
you won't survive, right?
These are... the photos.
It seems Sasaki-kun, as promised,
had submitted his report.
As expected, Satomi-san was
fired from the agency.
And then, some time after that...
When I was organizing the data...
...I noticed that.
She knew we were being tailed.
It was only a matter of time
before the wife finds out...
...even without resorting to
investigation agencies...
...she doubted me considerably...
I too thought it's better if I got caught somewhere...
I had also thought about it seriously...
...that if we continue to be together,
I'll be headed for a divorce.
Then why...
if Satomi-san knew you're being tailed...
That night, in the hotel...
At first, she was crying...
...and was saying...
"I betrayed my old self".
This is her way of taking responsibility.
Also for me... and for you...
...she made herself become the bad guy.
She showed herself to me on purpose.
She was a good woman.
A great deal more of a man than me.
This one's on the house.
To celebrate your promotion.
Women...
...I really don't get them.
Oh, well.
But...
...she has made me a man, I think.
I see.
I will for sure...
...find Satomi-san.
Is there anything you want to eat?
Boiled taro...
...and squid?
Your nose is getting a bit keener, huh?
Hey, Daigo, let's go!
Yeah, I know.
Wow...
Cool.
Wow~! Cool!!
That was awesome!
First, slightly boil the squid, than remove.
Before the taro are done cooking,
put back the squid again...
...and cook until the taro becomes
soft and not hard.
By the way, instead of using
hot water for taro...
...use the boiled squid's seasoned liquid so
you won't get bothered by the taro's sliminess.
Thanks for waiting.
I smell a woman somewhere*.
(*Probably a hint from the upcoming movie
which will have Tabe Mikako in a guest role)
'Master'
KOBAYASHI KAORU
'Satomi'
ISHIBASHI KEI
'Sasaki' - FUCHIGAMI YASUSHI
'Ex-Fiance' - FURUTACHI KANJI
'Chuu-san' - FUWA MANSAKU
'Kaneko' - KIYOBUMI KANEKO
'Komichi' - UNO SHOHEI
'Co-worker' - NONAKA TAKAMITSU
'The wife' - NAGAI WAKABA
Original work:
"Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
Screenplay:
MUKAI KOSUKE
Planning:
ENDO HITOSHI / SHIBANO MASAYUKI
Producers:
TSUITSUI RYUHEI /OSANO TAMOTSU
ISHIZUKA SHOGO / TAKEZONO MOTO
OP Theme Song:
"Omoiizu"
by SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI
Theme song:
'Yakimochi' by TAKAHASHI YU
(Warner Music Japan)
Food stylist:
IJIMA NAMI
Art:
HARADA MITSUO
Director:
KUMAKIRI KAZUYOSHI
Planning:
AMUSE / MBS
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT
GEEK SITE
A 2014 production of:
AMUSE / SHOGAKUKAN / TOEI / KINOSHITA GROUP
GEEK PICTURES / MBS / RKB
This drama is fictional