KOBAYASHI KAORU
ANDO TAMAE
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
NAKAYAMA YUICHIRO / UNO SHOHEI
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
RYUKYU TARO / MOTOI HIROYUKI
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
SAGARA AKIRA / MOROHASHI REIKO / YAMAGUCHI MIYOKO
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
SHIBATA RIE
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
...That's when my day starts.
Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne
Always seems like a thing of the past
Director: MATSUOKA JOJI
Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne
Always seems like a thing of the past
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
MESHIYA
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
EP 6: "Cabbage Rolls..."
When the autumn chill comes, there are many
customers who'd order cabbage rolls.
I prepare lots of pieces beforehand.
After all, it's quite a
time-consuming process.
How long has it been now?
Almost three months by now.
Surprisingly long, huh?
But the guy this time is unusual...
considering that Marilyn's types are good-looking guys.
The man I look for is not his face...
but his mind and fingers.
His name is Kimitoshi-kun but...
he's working in a nearby osteopathic clinic...
Marilyn seemed to have met him there
after feeling tired during her dance practice.
Here you go, Mari-chan.
So neat! You really do have god's hands.
Here...
Ah...
Marilyn has "removed your bones"* too huh?
(*Marilyn has him whipped)
I'm sure you knocked him out by your dancing.
No...
He has never seen me dance.
Says he doesn't wanna.
Well, what I mean is...
I can understand your feelings.
Like you gotta have courage, or be prepared for it...
Um... have you seen her?
Yeah, but only as much as we paid for.
Good evening.
Hello, hi...
Master, have you already made them?
The cabbage rolls.
I did.
Delicious!
Here, thanks for waiting.
My mom always made that before.
You have a caring mother, then huh?
Cabbage rolls take time and effort.
But I didn't like it at that time.
Why?
She'd make cabbage rolls for me before going
to some guy's house and spending all day there.
Because she felt guilty leaving
her kid alone in the house...
...that's why she'd cook up
some elaborate dish.
She quickly falls in love with men
and easily gets tired of them, too.
Oh, sorry... We're supposed to be eating dinner...
I'm okay. Since you're a "hito-suji"*.
(*Multiple meanings: awkward, common,
devoted, straight-laced)
[Marilyn: Performance canceled today]
She went back to her home in Fukushima?
Yeah, it seems near Koriyama...
Apparently, her mom had suddenly
been hospitalized so she hurriedly...
I see. I thought it was
Marilyn who got sick.
And then? Is her mother all right?
Well, I don't know yet...
But she just told us the other day, that
she's not in good terms with her mom.
I heard that the 2011 earthquake prompted her
to contact her mother for the first time in 10 years.
Welcome
Mari-chan, you came back so soon.
Master, shochu with hot water.
Oh, make it on the rocks. And cod roe.
Medium rare.
Sure thing.
We were worried about you. Just now we
were asking Kimi-kun about you.
Is that so.
So how's your mom?
Turns out there was nothing wrong with her.
Regardless of it,
his hands seem pretty fast.
No matter how busy, he'll do it.
Mariko?
You came all the way home, huh.
You called me up and said,
"Come home quick", didn't you?
This is my daughter, Mariko.
She lives in Tokyo.
She's a dancer, a dancer!
No wonder, she looks like a polished lady.
More importantly, how's your health?
Oh, Yuu-chan, Yuu-chan...
This is Mariko, she came back to see me.
So you're Mariko.
It's good that you've come back.
She was saying stuff on the phone, that she has no
one to rely on so I went there in a hurry and yet...
...she had a guy.
Anyway, it's good she's doing fine, right?
Said to be neural gastritis, presumably from
build-up of stress, though she's not that type of person.
Kimi-kun, gimme a shoulder massage?
I'm sorry...
It will end soon.
Marilyn had gone to her hometown...
But it seems it wasn't
much of a good scene.
[Marilyn: Late Show]
Lady, this isn't the kind of dancing
that women should be watching.
Good evening.
Welcome.
Aren't you late!
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
I'm sight-seeing as a way to celebrate my
discharge and have come to see you.
This is too sudden...
My place is not ready to accommodate you.
I already got myself a room at a hotel.
I'll have no time for you since
I'll be on stage most of the time.
I also have a late show today.
Chuu-san will be my tour guide.
Leave it to me.
I splurged at the hotel, and got myself
a double bedded room.
I guess it still feels lonely
sleeping all by myself.
I'm weak against a woman with
a touch of salt (sass) and sex appeal.
I wonder if this is okay.
Master, thank you!
Huh? Is he your boyfriend?
You came all the way to Tokyo only to get
caught by such a typical country hick...
Aren't there others besides him?
You're like a balloon who floated
from one man to another...
You're not qualified to say
whether a man is good or bad!
Kimi-kun, let's go.
Um, but...
Marilyn!
I wonder when was the first time
I came to Tokyo.
Was it during a high school trip...
I can't remember anymore.
Tokyo has changed immensely.
Mariko, too... she has changed so much all
the while we didn't see each other.
It's a struggle too even if you grew up here,
since everyone is coming to Tokyo.
Marilyn really thinks of her audience.
No matter what, even if her health is bad,
or even if circumstances have stopped...
...she'll perform on stage because
her audience is waiting.
The only time she was absent...
...was the time she visited you when she
returned home the other day.
Oh, right. Chuu-san, let's go see
Mariko's dance now. The late show.
Can't women see it?
No, that's not it but... For a mom,
there are stuff that a daughter...
Master, bill please.
Sure thing.
You do say she's a stripper, but there's no way she's
gonna bare everything right?
Well? You can't leave work?
Just tell them anything.
At any rate, please come.
I don't have the heart
to do this alone.
Chuu-san, is it this way?
Sheez, come on, let's go!
It's like "chirarism*", isn't it?
(*The art of giving a glimpse of
something like a part of an underwear)
No. If I have to say it,
it's more like "realism".
- Marilyn!
On second thought, I guess this is
too much for me to take.
Please stop!
Mari-chan, please don't
do this anymore!
Is it supposed to be like that?
Don't embarrass me.
I guess I wasn't able to stand it.
Even if it's strip teasing...
it is my vocation.
Don't ever stop my performance.
But I am also a man so...
If you're a man, you should
accept everything about me.
Excuse me.
Oh, it's the boyfriend!
That was a cool thing you did awhile ago.
I thought you should have
done that from the start.
Sorry to disturb.
Did you have fun seeing your daughter naked?
Did you see me?
You might not know it but I can see
the audience very clearly.
It's not just the face that a child
inherits from her parents...
Your boobs were exactly like mine
when I was younger.
But how long are you gonna
do this kind of work?
I swear... you've never recognized anything
that I've done.
Even in the hospital, what was that?
"My daughter, the dancer."
It's fine to call me a "stripper".
I will dance even if I become an old woman.
You're still so obstinate.
You haven't changed at all
since you were a kid.
Go home already.
My next performance is gonna start.
It was good.
After a few days...
- I see. You'll be taking the bus home tomorrow.
- Yeah.
But is it really okay, with Marilyn and all...
It's fine. After all, we'll just gonna
start arguing again anyway so...
Anyway, for now, I've told her already
that I'm getting married.
What?
You're getting married?
You see, my current boyfriend
had proposed to me.
I've dated a lot of men but...
I wonder if this one's the last.
Is that so. I see...
What kind of person is he?
He's the plainest guy
I ever dated, but still...
Yuu-chan somehow, isn't like the other guys.
So he's different.
Yuu-chan has a weird taste,
he wants to marry a sick person.
Sick person!?
Actually, I came to Tokyo
for a health check-up.
Check-up?
Check up for what?
It's already over. I went
as soon as I got here to Tokyo.
Then what happened?
Then, I will wait for the results back home.
If it's not metastatic cancer, there's no
need for anti-cancer agents.
It's bad if you don't tell Marilyn such
an important thing.
Until now, I've always lived my life selfishly,
I don't want to rely on her at this late stage.
Here you go.
This...
After Marilyn saw this...
...it brought back memories of how
you made this often for her.
I wonder if such a taste...
...is something she has never forgotten.
Has Mari-chan been here?
Nope.
I see. There's something I want
to apologize to her for.
Well, her mother just left a while ago...
She's headed to the station,
and will be going home today.
Is that so...
Eri-san, I...
Chuu-san, I really want to thank you.
I got to see Mariko, and
see that she's doing fine...
It's all thanks to you.
I was just some drunk guy.
Take care of yourself.
Oh, right. Why don't you come
and visit me next time!
Kimi-kun...
Marilyn-san, flowers for you.
Huh?
Oh... put it there.
It's ten minutes before show time.
See you later.
Okay.
[At least, take care of your body. I may be
an incompetent mother but I wish for us
to be mother and daughter until the end. ~Mom]
What's this about?
It's from your mom.
I already know that.
Master of Meshi-ya had informed me, that
your mom was going back home this morning.
Then I went to see her off.
You didn't have to do that!
The truth is your mom came to Tokyo, in order
to have a precise check-up at a university hospital.
But, since she didn't want to trouble you,
she lied to you by saying she was here on a sight-seeing trip.
Then she gave me money
to buy you some flowers.
Your mom lowered her head to me...
...she said "Please take care of Mariko"
and bowed her head over and over.
She's such a fool.
I will accept...
...everything about you.
"Next up is Marilyn-san..."
Marilyn-san, it's your turn.
Okay.
Results from the precise check-up seem
to show no findings of metastatic cancer.
Then a month later,
Eri-san got married.
I heard that only the bride and groom, Marilyn
and the rest of these people were at the ceremony but still...
...Eri-san was very happy.
What's with this pouty face, Marilyn
at such a happy occasion.
They fought again.
It's because she said my clothes look miserly.
Then, her mom said,
"You'd look better naked."
Thanks for waiting.
I'm digging in.
Was it like you had in the past?
Your mother had taught me her recipe.
I had wanted to eat
my mom's Cabbage Rolls.
When making in advance, do it like this
so it will be easier to roll.
Handle it delicately and with great feeling.
It's bad if you don't treat women like that.
When you place them in the soup, don't touch
them while they're cooking or else they will crumble.
So then, good night.
'Master'
KOBAYASHI KAORU
'Marilyn / Mariko'
ANDO TAMAE
'Kimitoshi' - TAKAHASHI SHUHEI
'Chuu-san' - FUWA MANSAKU
'Hachiro' - NAKAYAMA YUICHIRO
'Komichi' - UNO SHOHEI
'Yuu-chan' - RYUKYU TARO
'Theater Staff'- MOTOI HIROYUKI
'Eri's friends':
SAGARA AKIRA / MOROHASHI REIKO
YAMAGUCHI MIYOKO
'Eri'
SHIBATA RIE
Original work:
"Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
Screenplay:
MUKAI KOSUKE
Planning:
ENDO HITOSHI
SHIBANO MASAYUKI
Producers:
TSUITSUI RYUHEI / OSANO TAMOTSU
ISHIZUKA SHOGO / TAKEZONO MOTO
OP Theme Song:
"Omoiizu"
by SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI
Theme Song:
'Yakimochi' by TAKAHASHI YU
(Warner Music Japan)
Food Stylist:
IJIMA NAMI
Art:
HARADA MITSUO
Title Logo Design:
BAY BRIDGE STUDIOS
Sound Supervisor / MA:
ASARI NAOKO
Planning Cooperation:
OKAMOTO JUNYA
Organization:
TAKAHASHI TOSHIHIRO
Line Producer:
TAKAHASHI JUN
Photography: OTSUKA RYO
Lighting: KIMURA AKIO
Director:
MATSUOKA JOJI
Planning:
AMUSE
MBS
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT
GEEK SITE
A 2014 production of:
AMUSE / SHOGAKUKAN / TOEI / KINOSHITA GROUP
GEEK PICTURES / MBS / RKB
This drama is fictional