Opening Song
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
STARRING
Kobayashi Kaoru
Otoo Takuma
Kuwajima Marino
Kirishima Reika
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Kirishima Reika
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Directed by Matsuoka Joji
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
Directed by Matsuoka Joji
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
As the day comes to an end,
and people make their way home,
my own day begins.
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
Max. three drinks per customer
My menu is all there.
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
Max. three drinks per customer
The possibility of getting served anything else...
as long as it's possible,
my business model.
I am open from midnight
to seven of the morning after.
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
How is business doing?!
Well enough, I'd say.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
Midnight Restaurant
(*Fried pork cutlet, onions, and egg over rice)
Episode 6
Katsudon*
So that's what I
told you, just be honest.
Will it be all right?
Of course it will!
He's always honest
and to the point, right?
Right.
Chu-san, can I
have my tamagoyaki back?
Ohh...
He should be here by now?!
Wow... Tasty!
This stock is just killer.
Here you go, divided in half.
Nice!
Where is this from?
Hm... From the mart down the corner.
(*Eastern Hokkaido province)
For Atka mackerels, the ones
from Rausu in Shiretoko* are the best.
Wow... You sure know a
lot about mackerel, don't you?
I've always liked fish
ever since I was little.
Bon apetit.
Yummy!
We need to go right after you're done.
You should be asleep by now.
Good evening.
Ohh! Testosterone is
starting to fill the air now!
Today was a big day for me.
Master, can I order something?
Yeah...
Here... Kill the thirst with this.
Thanks.
- Here.
- Thank you!
Ahh... It's great.
0:32 of Round 8,
a killer KO punch.
How did you know?
He was at the match,
and told him the finish.
And he didn't even ask for it, right?
Thank you very much.
Ahh... It was just...
Don't just sit there
mumbling, and ask him!
Ahh... I was wondering...
whether you would like...
You know, your photos.
Of you training at
the gym, for instance.
Could I give it a shot?
He just got started in that field,
but he always says he wants
to publish a photobook with a boxer.
Will it be all right,
using someone like me...
Thank you very much.
I'm counting on you.
Here... A toast.
Let's have one.
(*Middle-aged man (lit. Uncle))
Oji-san*, what
happened to your face?
Mayu...
I'm sorry.
I'm a boxer.
Is that something like K-1?
It's a tad different...
You know the sport well?
(*combat sports*)
She's a huge kakutogi* fan.
Every time he wins a bout,
Kat-chan comes
here to eat katsudon.
Ahh... His name is
Kawada Katsutoshi.
Be nice to him.
Looks tasty...
Master. Give me
one as well, nuki-style.
Nuki?!
Means without rice.
I see...
Mom, did you know that?
I'll get a double one
with rice.
You can just call it
a normal "double katsudon."
Is that so?
You'll pardon me,
but we're open from midnight.
Because it's a "Midnight
Restaurant," I guess?!
Brought you an invitation,
to Komichi-san's exhibition.
He's doing it at a
tavern in Golden Street,
and I'm touring the
neighborhood to give out invitations.
Komichi-kun?
He's spending all day at the gym.
Not just me, he's shooting photos
of all the other boxers at the gym.
Will twenty invitations be enough?
Earlier on, Akemi-chan
and Mayu-chan came by.
Ohh...
K-1?
Looks like they saw your last bout,
and came here asking for katsudon.
Really?
Then, next time they come by,
tell them I'll treat them.
How about you tell them yourself?
Akemi-chan works
at a snack bar nearby.
She'll probably be there tonight.
Forget it.
That would be much too direct.
Is the bar close?
Yeah, let me draw you a map.
Ahh... Forget it. I need to
go back to the gym anyway.
How about...
her husband?
Her husband died,
and she lives alone with Mayu-chan.
They live around Ohkubo.
I didn't ask you that...
I asked you nothing!
Here....
Bon apetit.
Sorry for troubling you so much.
No... Not at all.
It's great!
I want to go cheer
for you at a boxing event.
Really?
Then, I'll invite you.
Still, coming alone
would be a tad awkward,
so come with your mother.
- All the better.
- Give it a rest.
- Uhh?!
- Why, you can't?
We'll come to cheer for you.
But we'll pay our
tickets like everyone else.
If I win the next bout, I'll
treat you two to some katsudon.
I'll have to!
You must win.
It's a promise.
Then, here's my finger.
"It's a promise, if you break it,
eat a thousand needles."
"It's a promise!"
Here is my number.
Ahh... Yes.
When the bout is announced,
you can call me at this number.
Master. How about Akemi-san's?
Making it.
Wow!
Isn't it amazing?
~ Japan's 4th Ranked Lightweight ~
Samejima Toru
~ Lightweight ~
Kawada Katsutoshi
~ Samejima Promises
3rd Round KO of Kawada ~
Can I have some water?
Komichi-san...
He's been working so hard,
I'd hate to show him my B-game.
I was...
thinking about quitting my job.
It's just that, if I don't give it my all,
winning will not be easy.
You can be quite
dense sometimes...
Right?!
Can't say I'm not.
But I'm putting everything
on the line for this bout.
It could very well be my last chance.
Want to have breakfast?
I need to make up my mind.
Otherwise, I'll never be able
to escape from this situation.
I think I'd just keep stalling
until I can't do this anymore.
Everyone thinks I
will get knocked out,
but I will make sure it doesn't happen.
I will keep my guard
up until the middle portion,
and then go at him with a
killer punch near the end.
I reserved a seat for you.
I'll wait for you here.
I'll open earlier,
and will be waiting for you.
Give it to someone else.
Should I?
By the way...
Don't laugh and just listen.
Yeah.
You know...
I'm thinking of proposing
to Akemi-san on the ring.
Like Rocky did.
They lure you somewhere
and then ask you to sign.
Should we go see that?
Uh?
Forget that!
But, you know?
Samejima, if he wins this,
he'll get a title shot.
Kawada has no chances of winning.
That's for sure.
Against Samejima, it's only natural.
But, I hear they're showing it
live on TV?
Yeah... It's a big chance for Kawada.
Excuse me...
Want another bottle of this?
- Yeah.
- Shochu?
- Sure.
- All right.
But if he loses, Kawada
might even consider retiring.
- Will he go out with a bang?
- Might be what he's looking for.
Good evening.
Come on in.
No customers tonight?
Yeah...
Is Mayu-chan home?
She's sleeping at a friend's.
She's so excited.
Her friend's got
really great parents,
and lacks nothing.
Bourbon on the rocks.
Sure.
Sometimes, I feel like all
this is getting tiresome, Master.
Mayu keeps growing,
and her tuition is no laughing matter.
And I'm not getting
any younger myself.
You know, Kat-chan?
He quit his job, saying he
wanted to focus on training.
I wonder what he plans
to do in case he loses.
And whether he's even
thinking about his future...
To him,
boxing must be the
most important thing in his life?!
Now, it has to be.
But give him some time.
See how Mayu-chan listens to him?
That's because she doesn't
remember her father's face,
so she might feel affinity
for a gentle man like him.
You'll go support him, right?
Don't know.
Isn't this oolong tea?
That's a relief.
You still remember how it tastes like.
Master, give it a rest!
Go see Kat-chan's fight, will you?
All you need in this world...
is two people liking each other.
So....
Win for us and let's
go have some katsudon.
Golden Rookie Samejima is taking his
first step along the path to legendary status.
It is a fight even his opponent, Kawada,
had long been looking forward to.
Here's the gong starting our first round.
Kawada on the offensive!
Kawada is starting
to take the initiative.
- Down!
- Kat-chan!
1.... 2....
3..... 4....
Box!
This way.
You gave your best.
Everyone, thank you for
supporting me all this time.
Here... Kat-chan.
Good job.
Cheers!
Master.
Katsudon for me.
Mayu!
I'm hungry.
Is it all right with you?
Master.
Katsudon for three.
Coming!
Sorry for not keeping my promise.
You didn't lose.
We know that.
Right, Mom?
Still hurts?
This is nothing.
Don't tell me you're gonna cry?
Master...
This...
(*deep-fried pork part of katsudon)
Sadly, I ran out of tonkatsu*, so...
(*Donburi with chicken and eggs, but
literally means "parents-and-child" donburi)
Oyakodon*.
~ to be continued ~
Thank you for waiting.
Because the meat will get
cooked even more at the end,
turn it off a little earlier while frying.
Always be careful not to overcook it.
So, here's the recipe
for oyakodon as well.
Ohh.... We have no time?!
We became parents and child.
Good night everyone!
Good night.