~ Opening Song ~
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
~ KOBAYASHI Kaoru ~
~ LILY ~
~ ANDO Tamae ~
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Directed By YAMASHITA Nobuhiro
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Directed By YAMASHITA Nobuhiro
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
Directed By YAMASHITA Nobuhiro
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
As the day comes to an end,
and people make their way home,
my own day begins.
[~ Traditional Tonjiru ~ 600 yen
~ Beer ~ 600 yen, ~ Sake ~ 500 yen
~ Shochu ~ 400 yen
Max. three drinks per customer]
My menu is all there.
The possibility of getting
served anything else...
as long as it's possible,
my business model.
I am open from midnight
to seven of the morning after.
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
How is business doing?!
Well enough, I'd say.
~ WITHS2 4th Anniversary Special ~
SHINYA SHOKUDO - midnight restaurant
Episode 9
Horse Mackerel
~ Shinjuku Golden Street ~
For the last few days,
at the break of dawn,
this dandy obasan (old woman)
has been coming by for breakfast.
Thanks for that.
Can I have a smoke?
Not being able to smoke
after meals just kills you, doesn't it?
Anywhere you end up in Tokyo, they
shove "no smoking" signs down your throat.
The real burden is living here.
And it's getting worse by the day.
I've seen smokers last up to ninety,
who knows when nature will call you?
So what brought you here?
I left business to my son.
Life in the provinces can get quite insipid.
Provinces where?
(*The old name of
Kumamoto Prefecture in Kyushu)
Kumamoto in Higo Province*.
You have no accent at all.
I'm from Tokyo,
Kumamoto was just
my late husband's hometown.
I'm staying at a weekly down the road.
Will spend some time for myself.
Despite coming from Tokyo, that
horse mackerel is quite something.
Isn't it?
This fella I know from Numazu...
Morning.
Ohh... How's it going?
Just got back from a road show.
After spending all
night on the bus, I'm all stiff.
Beer.
Shouldn't you just go
home and have some sleep?
I need to get drunk.
All men need from women
are our bodies anyway, right?!
Sounds like you're down, all right.
Hi.
Are you part of a stage troupe?
No... dance.
I'm a dancer, Marilyn Matsushima.
Nice to meet you.
The hell is wrong with this?
You know?
I made it big,
thanks to her.
I used the machine
Yachiyo-san recommended,
and just tore down the house.
Ahh... It felt so great.
Yachiyo-san, go ahead
and drink. I'm treating you.
This is not a bar.
Only three glasses per customer.
Don't say that!
Let's just drink the night away
and forget real life for a moment.
But, tell me.
How did you find out which
one was the lucky pachinko?
Shouldn't let greed get
the better of you, for starters.
It will only ruin the experience.
And blind you into
making wrong choices.
Same goes for men, isn't it?!
The hell is that?
Ohhh! Marilyn.
So you're back?
Here I am.
When is your next gig?
I'll bring you flowers.
Thanks. I have
a couple of days off to rest.
I'd love to see you dance as well.
You?!
What kind of dance is that?
Well... how should I put it...
Where is she dancing?
I'll just show you.
Let's go, Yachiyo-san.
Master. Thanks for that.
Keep the change.
Thank you for that.
Ohh... Here you go.
That obasan...
Think I saw her somewhere?
That's awesome, Yachiyo-san!
That was really great!
You've got talent.
Guess it's just vestiges of the past.
Why, what did you use to do?
What?
For someone as old as I am,
there's plenty of past to talk about.
Yachiyo-san, here.
- Why? What's there?
- Come on.
- This way.
- Uh?
Yachiyo-san, you know?
I told you I was a
dancer, but actually...
I'm a stripper.
I wasn't trying to hide it on purpose.
Though... I suppose I did.
~ Shinjuku New Art ~
I've been on my
very first road show,
to an onsen (hotsprings)
district in the provinces.
I gave it my all to dance well,
but nobody seemed interested.
All they cared about
was seeing me take it all off,
like a stripper should, I guess.
But I always tell myself I'm
a dancer first and foremost.
So you must
have your share of fans?
Sure do!
Whenever I'm performing, you can
see the list of bouquets at the entrance.
You must really be something.
Want to have a few
more drinks at my place?
- Really?
- Yeah.
Great!
Hey! Marilyn.
- Good evening.
- You've become friends and all, already.
Master.
Beer and...
Mari?!
We meet here, of all places?!
Kazama-san, you two know each other?
We went to the
same acting school, didn't we?
Wow! Marilyn, have a seat here.
That's great, Marilyn.
You were a big star's classmate?!
Komichi-san, give it a rest!
She modeled
for me once, you know?
With her body, she was the perfect fit.
Yeah...
Kazama-san won the praise
of this big shot on Broadway,
so he's going to star in a musical abroad.
Wow! You must
really be a great actor.
No, it's just a bit role.
Bit?! You're the lead's boyfriend.
- That's no bit role.
- I guess so.
May I?
Feel these muscles.
Gimme a hug, will you?!
So, Mari.
What's up?
Congrats.
But I hear you're
still in that line of work.
Sorry, that's right.
They don't call it dancing...
Still, it was a big shocker,
learning that my ex was prancing around
hall naked while pretending to dance.
What's so wrong
about being a stripper?
Does being in a
musical make you any better?
Let's leave.
Just a moment!
By any chance,
are you Rose Michiyo?
That's it!
I recall now.
I knew you were familiar.
You're Rose Michiyo!
(*mocking a famous line from Fuji TV's
hit show Anbiribabo/Unbelievable)
Unbelievable*!!
- She...
- Ohh... I know...
That neck line and those ears...
Rose Michiyo was one of the
top strippers about four decades ago,
but then disappeared without trace.
She's a legend in her field.
You know? I got into strip
shows thanks to you, Rose-san.
I'd rather not be
called Rose, thank you.
But how come you know her?
Back in the day,
I was a regular at strip shows.
Just so that I could
pick up hints from them.
Of course, Rose Michiyo
taught me all my moves...
She was second to none.
But why did you suddenly
vanish? I was so lonesome.
Because of a man, what else?
I'm a woman just like all the others.
This man must really be something,
to make you fall for him.
But he passed away pretty quickly.
History teaches us
that it's men who always end up...
ruining women's lives, isn't it?!
I've had my share of happenings,
but now I'm retired
and enjoying my time left.
With the money I
made "prancing around naked",
I brought up my kid.
You know, Marilyn-chan?
I haven't felt ashamed
about that a single time.
Yachiyo-san...
This world of ours, bitter and
sweet like the Nagara River.
That's beautiful.
If you want to keep coming here,
check the attitude at the door.
We'll get going, for tonight.
So you've been
around Shinjuku, as of late?
I was in Ikebukuro*.
[*means "pond bag"]
Bukuro (little bag)?!
Nothing sticking out of my pants,
but still have bukuro down there!
Master.
Some horse mackerel, please.
Coming.
(*in Japanese, this dish is called "Aji no
(the horse mackerel's) Hiraki (opening)")
Rose-san, you love
spread-out mackerel*, don't you?
Spreading out is a stripper's job!
She's making a good showing!
- That's a good one!
- She's got talent for this.
And I said don't call me Rose.
It's Yachiyo.
All right. Yachiyo-san.
I can take it from here.
Let me walk you to the station.
I don't like that kind of goodbye.
I'll just take a taxi.
Thanks.
So... Take care.
You as well, Yachiyo-san.
Keep your head up, will you?
So long.
- Hi, welcome.
- How are you?
- It's five thousand yen.
- Five thousand?
Yep.
- Is Marilyn still on?
- No worries, she just started.
- Here you go, thanks.
- Thank you.
Good showing!
Well spread out and all!
Marilyn!
~ To be continued ~
Skin for fresh,
and flesh for sea.
What's that?
Just an advice for when you grill fish.
Grill freshwater
fish starting with the skin,
and the flesh first for seawater fish.
Skin for freshwater,
flesh for seawater?
Catchy, isn't it?
- And salmon?
- Salmon...
Where do you start
grilling salmon from?
Salmon...
Ahh, also!
Before you start,
heat up your grilling net first,
or the fish will stick to it.
Look how she changes the subject.
So long, goodbye.
- Good night everyone.
- Good night.