Opening Song
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
STARRING
Kobayashi Kaoru
Kazama Toru
Tanaka Sogen
Sasaki Sumie
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Produced by Oikawa Takuro
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
and people make their way home,
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
my own day begins.
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
Max. three drinks per customer
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
My menu is all there.
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
The possibility of getting served anything else...
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
The possibility of getting served anything else...
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
as long as it's possible,
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
my business model.
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
I am open from midnight to seven of the morning after.
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
How is business doing?!
Well enough, I'd say.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
Midnight Restaurant
Episode 4
Potato Salad
The first thing I
prepare before opening is...
potato salad.
And that is because it
is much tastier if eaten cold...
than right after it is prepared.
Here...
And by the way,
talking of potato salad...
Come on in.
Potato salad.
Coming.
Here you go.
As of late, this fella shows
up every now and then.
More, please.
Coming.
He always ends up ordering
two servings of potato salad.
Pardon me,
but you're Erect
Ohki-san, aren't you?
No.
But...
That ring and
the birthmark are just...
I'm sure it's you.
You're "the"
Erect Ohki-san, right?
That's not me.
Uh? Really?
That's freaking great.
I saw you last night.
I said that's not me...
It's him, all right!
This man is the real Erect Ohki-san!
Take a look!
~ Erect Ohki vs 100 OL ~
Why would you carry
that around with you?
Because it's like a Bible to me.
So this "Erect Ohki"...
turns out to be a porn
actor of legendary charisma,
who starred in around 400 adult
videos per year during his prime.
Ohki-san!
Accept me as your pupil!
I'm counting on you, Ohki-san!
Give it a rest.
I want revenge against all the people
who treated me like a loser.
Please accept me!
I'm begging you, Ohki-san!!
And you are...
Tanaka.
Tanaka Yuichi, Sir.
Can you start right away?
Yes.
Thank you!!
I'm so thankful...
Seemed like his youthly
enthusiasm won over Erect Ohki.
And after that,
the two often came together.
- Potato salad.
- Traditional Tonjiru with extra rice.
Seems like Tanaka-kun was living up
to his reputation as an enthusiastic pupil.
I thought he would be up in arms
and out of there in a few days,
but he's got quite the perserverance,
despite what looks might suggest.
I see.
Here you go.
And it carries over
to his meals as well.
Ahh... Ohki-san.
So when you work with
an actress for the first time,
how do you usually approach her?
Enough... Just eat.
Just this, and then I'll eat.
I said eat.
But it's just...
It's your mentor's order!
I apologize.
Bon apetit!
Hot...
Ahh... Hot!
I'm sorry.
Are you all right?
Might pester him here and there,
but Ohki-san doesn't look too
bothered by having a new pupil.
Excuse me.
We're ready to go.
Erect-san, if you will.
Yes.
Should we get going?
- Here... How 'bout it...
- Feels so good...
It's so hard...
How 'bout this...
How about that?!
Ahh... Nooo...
I'm coming...
So it was, what,
two months after that?
Good evening.
- Come on in.
- 'Evening.
Can you serve him something
that can boost up his energy?
Thanks to your encouragement,
I'll finally debut tomorrow.
Ohh...
Congratulations about that.
- Give your best.
- Appreciate it.
I'll give my all.
Here.
Ready and served.
Your special stamina meal.
- Thank you.
- And also...
These for Ohki-san.
The second serving is on them.
We watched your
latest together, yesterday.
"Erect Ohki's
Juice Gushing Bonanza"
It was so hot.
Ohh... Thank you.
Just a token of gratitude, since
we heard you love potato salad.
Yes...
This potato salad's taste
brings back pleasant memories.
- He's! Eating it!
- I'm gonna cry...
Ohh... Thank you.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Ohh... What is it?
Uh? A stroke?!
Excuse me.
So?
Ohh... But it's
nothing serious, right?
I'm too busy to come there now.
Yeah....
All right then,
I'm hanging up.
Sorry for that.
What's the matter?
Ohh... Nothing special.
Didn't seem the case?!
Seems like my mother
back home collapsed.
But it's all right.
It's only a minor stroke.
Go tend to her.
It's all right.
We have a shoot in the morning.
- Bon apetit.
- You idiot!
Is some adult video shoot more
important than your own mother?
If you go now,
it'll still be all right.
Go while you still can.
Get out of here.
I don't want to see
your face at Yayoi's wedding!
Why did you have
to subject me to this?
(*Brother)
Onii-chan*!
Sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Still...
I wish you happiness.
Both my mother, brothers,
even my late father...
were all teachers.
Not to mention my sister's husband,
and his parents.
All teachers as well.
Would be awkward, wouldn't it?
If I showed up there.
After that day and
for the next twenty years,
I never returned to my hometown.
You must leave now.
Take the first train in the morning.
- B-but...
- I said it's fine.
Listen to your mentor.
You must go.
Yes.
Hello?
- Thank you.
- Come again.
Thank you.
Following your advice made
my mother really happy.
Really?
Is she feeling better now?
Yes.
They'll keep her at
the hospital for a while,
but seems like it was nothing serious.
Good to hear.
But... Ohki-san?
The other day, we missed each other,
as he returned to his hometown.
Hometown?!
Didn't he say it's
been twenty years already?
Why suddenly...
I have a shoot in two days,
and I can't reach him at all.
The number you dialed is not...
Tanaka-kun.
Ready to go?
We're all set.
All right.
Here... How 'bout it?
Do you like it?
- Can you feel it?
- It hurts! Ahh... Stop!
- My apologies...
- Cut!
Tanaka, what the hell
do you think you're doing?
- I apologize!
- Are you out of your mind?
You fucking amateur,
get the hell out of here!
Sorry!!
Congrats on your debut!
Thank you.
When it comes out,
I'll be the first to buy it!
I'll get two.
Thank you.
So how was it?
Ahh... Well, I let the ecstasy
of the moment capture me,
and I don't really know
what happened myself.
Is that so?
But I would have loved to
see my mentor witness it.
Still haven't reached him?
I called him to no avail.
- Come on in!
- Master!
My mother...
has dementia.
My sister called me,
and I've been down there
with my mother the last few days.
Young fella...
Say, where
do you come from?
From... Tokyo.
Ohh... Really?
Must have been quite the trip.
Getting all the way here.
It sure was.
Are you here for business or pleasure?
I came to see...
my mother.
Ahh... Is that so?
You know, I have a
son who lives in Tokyo.
But it's been so long
since he last visited me.
Don't know if it's work
that's keeping him busy...
Mother...
I wonder...
whether he'll pay me a visit this year.
Mother!
Mom!!
It's me...
I said it's me!!
Mom!
It's me, Mom...
That kiddo...
liked potato salad so much.
Mom...
Then, she was helped by my sister,
and they made
potato salad for me.
So...
How is it?
That rascal liked it so much,
he would keep asking for more.
He's so affectionate...
and caring, such a good boy.
But it was...
so salty.
So damn salty.
Master...
Accept...
my apologies.
Thanks to you...
Thanks to what you told me...
I was able to see my mother.
I apologize!
I'm sorry...
What are you saying?
Stop saying that!
Isn't that all the better?
Go visit her often.
Yes.
Here.
On the house.
Thank you.
So good...
Reminds me of home.
Maybe I'm getting old?
But, these days...
I seem to cry for the smallest things.
~ to be continued ~
And here's your one
point advice for potato salad.
Boil the potatoes without peeling them,
and you'll maintain their unique taste.
If you add the onions
while the potatoes are still hot,
they'll become soft and tasty.
Let's add mayo when
the potatoes have cooled down.
So that's the secret
behind a proper potato salad.
And so here we are...
Good night everyone.