Opening Song
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
STARRING
Kobayashi Kaoru
Ayata Toshiki
Ando Tamae
Matsushige Yutaka
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Matsushige Yutaka
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Directed by Matsuoka Joji
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
Directed by Matsuoka Joji
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
As the day comes to an end,
and people make their way home,
my own day begins.
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
Max. three drinks per customer
My menu is all there.
The possibility of getting
served anything else...
as long as it's possible,
my business model.
I am open from midnight
to seven of the morning after.
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
How is business doing?!
Well enough, I'd say.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
Midnight Restaurant
Episode 1
Red Wiener & Tamagoyaki
By the way...
(*Pork soup with veggies and miso)
Can you make something
else other than traditional Tonjiru*?
Like shogayaki (ginger pork) or something.
Ahh... sure.
Then, I'll go for that.
Coming.
Master.
I'm back.
Hi... You're back home?
How was Macao?
The manager there wanted me
to stay a little longer,
but I already had
the man of my destiny!
And that'd be a Japanese?
It's this Casino dealer.
You know, he's
just great with cards.
Now that I think about it,
your ex was a pianist, right?
For men,
knowing how to use these
is the most important thing.
This kiddo's name is Marilyn.
With what she calls "dance",
she often dazzles my
regulars as a top stripper,
at the New Art in Shinjuku.
Master, just give me some tarako*
and shochu** on top.
(*salted cod roe
**distilled rice liquor)
You want me to roast that tarako?
Yeah... Medium rare.
As our Marilyn seems to fall
head over heels pretty often,
she has the tendency of
taking after her new man's...
every peculiarity and taste.
Can't wait!
Marilyn-chan!
Good showing!
Seems like her new man...
loves medium rare tarako.
Here you go.
Medium rare.
Yummy!
Awesome...
Told you that medium
rare is the best for tarako.
Thanks for that...
'night!
Hi.
Ohh... long time no see.
The usual.
Coming.
Ryu-chan is pretty
famous around here.
Although first impression
sure was terrible, you know?!
Must have been...
not long after I opened.
That's impressive.
If I don't get clients to sign,
the alternative is cleaning toilets, so...
You just get used to it.
Want some fried mackerel?
But, I was...
Just to taste it out,
so it's on the house.
I'm in!
The hell...
Help me out, will you?
This the place?
The one where they cook
you whatever you order?
- You...
- Ahh...
I was just about to
go back to my store...
Oyaji*.
(*middle-aged man)
Escargots.
Can't do.
Then...
Swiftlet nest soup?
I don't have anything that expensive.
What the hell?
What is it you can do?!
Do you have Wiener?
Red Wiener sausage.
Sure do.
Want me to cut
them like an octopus?
How much is it?
If you add the bill from
the guy who left a little earlier...
2,000 yen.
Uh?!
Why does he
need to pay for him?
What's with the prices here?
Keep the change.
After that day,
Ryu-chan kept showing
up with alarming frequency.
Bon apetit.
Looks tasty.
The curious fella who
just barged in...
walked the straight
road for 48 years,
running a gay bar down the street,
Kosuzu-san.
May I?!
Bon apetit!
This old school taste is just...
Young fella.
I'd feel bad not
giving anything in return,
how about some of my tamagoyaki*?
(*rolled omelette)
I did give it a taste, though.
Thanks.
You're very welcome.
I...
really hate those Yakuza,
but you're different.
(*lit. kettle, pejorative slang for gay men,
originated in the Edo period)
I don't like okama* myself.
Ehh... What are you prattling about?
So stuck up...
Then, what, it's okay?!
You don't see that every day.
Kosuzu-san ending up like that.
~ Shinjuku Golden Street ~
Here you are.
Your tamagoyaki.
Ahh... It's here, it's here!
Ahh... the flavor...
Want a taste?
I'll get diabetes.
I tell you, I eat my
tamagoyaki all nice and salty,
with plenty of dashima (kelp)
soup on top, you know?
You silly...
That's no tamagoyaki,
it's just dashimaki.
So sweet and tasty!
What's so different?
Eat it at a sushi restaurant,
and it's called tamagoyaki.
At a soba (noodle) restaurant,
it's called dashimaki.
I see.
But, Kosuzu-san,
you really love that tamagoyaki.
For your skin, I bet?!
It's not because of that!
Did some past lover of
yours you can't forget like that?
Who knows...
Kosuzu-san.
Want me to roast
you some Wiener?
It's all right.
Ryu-chan already let
me try them out, good stuff.
Ryu-chan said the
same thing about that.
Really?
Thought he'd come by tonight,
but I guess he stood me up again.
Ahh... Master.
You'll excuse me,
but can you wrap this up for me?
The guys at the
bar might be hungry.
Fine with me.
When I have leftovers,
I always give them to a cat
that comes here from time to time.
Here you go.
I made you prepare
more than needed...
Sorry.
As the day comes to an end,
and people are
rushing back home,
they sometimes
get this uneasy feeling,
getting the urge of spending
the night somewhere else.
How should I roast
your tarako, the usual?
Don't roast it.
I'll just have it raw.
Wasn't medium rare
the best for tarako?
The hell does
he know anyway, that man?
You broke up?!
With that medium rare fella.
That mama's boy?!
Forget about it.
- Thanks for that.
- Thanks.
Ohh... Thank you.
Anyone who falls
for men twice as easily...
also grows tired
of them twice as fast.
How are you ever going
to meet a cool man that way?
Shut up, you okama.
Quiet, you kiddo.
Should be tasty
even if it's raw, I guess?!
You even fall for a Yakuza now...
You're losing your charm, Sis.
It's not that.
Marilyn.
Falling in love,
dying for love or whatever...
I already graduated from that
school of thought a long time ago.
Maybe because you lasted
a lot longer than you deserved,
you had more
time to experience?!
But if you fall for a Yakuza,
he'll probably run you dry?
Is Ryu-chan not coming?
He's probably busy
blackmailing someone?
That man is a righteous fella.
I can feel it.
You know what they say,
can't judge a book by its cover.
Still, isn't he a little too tall?
Yes, my apologies.
Right... About that,
we'll do whatever is possible...
Kenzaki!
It hurts...
Gen.
- Are you okay?
- It hurts so bad!
It hurts...
Aneki (Yakuza's "big brother")!
Aneki!
You bastard!
Stop there!
~ Imashiro gang Kingpin stabbed ~
Is gang warfare back?
The Victim - Kenzaki Ryu
Thankfully,
he wasn't seriously injured,
but Ryu-chan will have to spend
some time at the hospital.
Master...
I have a favor to ask...
First layer!
Second!
And...
third... one!
It's a buffet, all right.
I asked Master to make it for me.
Go ahead.
So I guess red
wiener and tamagoyaki...
are the two big stars of any bento*
(*home-packed meal)?
Is there any memory
those wieners bring back?
Everyone keeps some
kind of special memory...
buried deep down their soul.
Still,
one day, I want
to tell you everything...
about the memories that
tamagoyaki brings back to mind.
It's a relief
they didn't kill you.
Without you...
I'd just...
I know!
Isn't it time to go?
Got work to do.
This world of ours...
is made of ebbs and flows,
like the Sumida River.
Don't belittle life.
You have katsuobushi*?
(*dried fish scrapings)
I do have it, but...
I wanted some on top of warm rice,
sprinkled with soy sauce.
You mean nekomanma (cat rice)?
That was...
the first time she
came to my restaurant.
~ To be Continued ~
Everyone!
Fried eggs might
be simple to make,
but tamagoyaki is a
tad more difficult, right?
Still, don't just give up on it.
Shall we give
this challenge a try?
Make them scramble
over the frying pan,
and they'll grill gently.
Fold it sideways just like this,
push it aside,
and pour over.
When it starts making
bubbles, break them.
So, see you again!
Good night!