When people finish their day
and hurry home,
my day starts.
My diner is open from midnight
to 7:00 in the morning.
They call it "Midnight Diner."
Do I even have customers?
More than you would expect.
MIDNIGHT DINER: TOKYO STORIES
KITSUNE UDON
Is this the right street?
Or it could be wrong?
-Maybe this is the right one.
-It's the one, right?
Sorry.
Okay, this one...
Is this the one?
Look.
Yes, this is the one.
But there are only old people here.
Haruna, you go in first.
You wanted to come here, Akina.
That's true, but it doesn't matter.
You go first.
No, I can't.
Hey, you two!
Can I go in?
Please!
Good evening.
Welcome.
It's unusual for Marilyn
to bring young girls here.
Are they new dancers?
No, they aren't.
They were outside.
Master, my usual and shochu on the rocks.
Sure.
How about you two?
Can you make kitsune udon?
Yes, I can.
Two, please.
Sure.
Here you go.
Please get me a role in the next audition.
Even a small role.
Please.
What do you two do for a living?
We are trying to be
voice actors for animations.
We have an audition tomorrow.
We're making a wish on kitsune udon.
Right?
Yeah.
Making a wish?
I heard his kitsune udon would
bring you good luck, correct?
I've never heard of it before.
A friend who had this dish
had a successful audition.
I saw it on Instagram.
It's by luck.
It's just an ordinary kitsune udon.
Is that so?
But they could be right.
Because he offers a deep-fried tofu
to the shrine every day.
That's right.
Never say never.
-Let's eat.
Delicious.
It's so good, isn't it?
Hey.
You could notice my dialect,
on that last line, couldn't you?
You'll be fine
if you are careful about intonation.
"That night, on the bridge..."
"On the bridge..."
"On the bridge."
I'm not so sure any more.
No worries. You're okay.
-Really?
-Say it again.
"On that night, on the bridge,
I saw a man running--"
"On the bridge."
-"On the bridge."
-That's it.
You sound good!
I'll treat you both tonight
'cause I'm a good person.
Really?
There's no such thing as a free lunch.
I think you should just thank her.
We both didn't make it.
I see...
It didn't bring you good luck.
They say voice-acting jobs
are very hard to get.
But Haruna was
one of four final candidates.
An entertainment management company
talked to Akina personally, though.
That's great!
You both have moved forward
toward your dream a little.
It did bring you luck.
Here you go.
Two deep-fried tofu today?
A special treat from me.
Great!
Let's make sure we bring him
better news next time.
-So nice to be young. I'm so jealous.
-Let's eat.
Don't be silly.
You're still young, Marilyn.
Don't bother.
About six months later...
Good evening.
Welcome.
Long time no see.
Could I have kitsune udon?
Sure.
I heard you've got a job as a voice actor.
Haruna told me the other day.
Yes.
Not exactly as a voice actor, though.
I joined an idol group of voice actors.
So gigs and fan conventions only.
It's not my ideal job.
But it could lead to something else.
That's the spirit!
Has Haruna been here lately?
Yeah, sometimes after her part-time job.
You haven't seen her?
Not much.
It seems she's having
a difficult time auditioning.
Why don't you give her a call?
Not now.
Because the more I try to cheer her up,
the worse she'd feel.
We're really sorry.
Yes.
Yes. We will be more careful.
We are terribly sorry.
Yes.
Kitsune udon?
No.
No point in me making a wish.
What's wrong?
Welcome.
Warm sake, please.
-Are you okay?
-Yes.
I'll go home right after one drink.
He is Mr. Nobuta.
He is a manga artist
who became very popular a few years ago.
He hasn't been doing well
recently, though.
Here you go.
Money doesn't make you happy.
Again?
I can't get back the money I spent
on the woman, or her love, either.
Master, what have I got now?
Work.
Go home now and do it.
That's harsh.
What?
You're Mr. Yukio Nobuta, aren't you?
I'm a huge fan of yours.
-Ah, is that so?
-Yes.
-Women always say that.
-What?
But usually,
they just happen to know my name.
Are you a student?
No. I don't think you'll believe me,
but I watched your animation on TV
when I was a high school student.
I'm trying to be a voice actor.
You're so typical.
People think that they understand
everything by just reading some.
If you understand that much,
you should write!
Mr. Nobuta.
Cut it out.
But...
It's true.
UNTIL IT BECOMES LIGHT
YUKIO NOBUTA
Why do you have this?
It was 30,000 yen on an online auction.
I saved money and finally got it.
I've read all your books.
Until It Becomes Light.
I heard you can't find it,
even in the secondhand bookstores.
This is my very first book.
It didn't sell well,
and later it was out of print.
I see.
I watch God's Miso Soup on TV every week.
I also read the one in
STEP magazine every week.
Well, I haven't published
any episodes in it lately.
Publisher says animation
will take over comic books.
How come you don't write?
Because I can't.
They'll probably cut me off soon.
But I guess it's better
than writing bad ones.
You can't tell if it's bad
until you actually write.
I always fail auditions...
and I wonder if I'm really suited
for voice acting.
But you never know until you do it!
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
You're right.
But the truth hurts me at the moment.
I'm terribly sorry.
We can't compare my problems with yours...
Master, this is for both of us.
Give me the change next time.
Sure.
Setting is now complete.
Do you have any more concerns?
Yes.
Yes. Thank you very much.
We'll play the message.
Hello, Haruna?
I wonder how you're doing.
I haven't seen you at auditions lately--
How's your work these days?
I think I'll quit.
My production company told me...
they'd end the contract
if I can't do well.
I understand now.
I'm happy enough just watching animations.
I don't want to end up hating it,
trying to get a job in the industry.
GOD'S MISO SOUP STARTS AGAIN
Have you read this?
Yes, of course.
Mr. Nobuta said the other day,
"I could make it, thanks to Haruna.
I learned from her that you'll never know
until you do something."
I got this from him.
He asked me to give it you.
GOD'S MISO SOUP
VOICE ACTOR AUDITION FOR A NEW CHARACTER
Yes. Thank you.
Thank you.
You've got a gig and a fan convention
right after this audition.
Yes.
I'll be there after I finish
another appointment.
Thank you.
-Don't be late.
-Of course not.
-Please have a seat.
-Yes.
-Excuse me...
-Sorry.
Long time no see.
SHOTA
I'm sorry...
...but I couldn't do it.
In this world, some can make it,
and some cannot.
I'm the one who cannot.
"Don't decide if you can't do it!
You do know...
SHINO
You just don't want to fail."
"But...
SHINO
You never know the outcome
until you try doing it."
Thank you very much.
She was good.
Next, Ms. Haruna Honma.
Yes.
I'm the one who cannot.
"Don't decide if you can't do it.
You do know...
You just don't want to fail.
But...
you never know the outcome
until you try doing it."
Thank you very much.
Wait. One more time.
Please start again from page two.
Tone down a little this time.
Can you do it?
Yes. I'll try.
-Please start from the beginning.
-Yes.
Thank you so much.
I have high hopes for you.
I'll try my best.
Thank you so much!
Keep up the good work.
Sure.
Congratulations, Haruna.
You were great.
I just wanted to tell you that.
Thanks.
But I was not that good.
I voiced my feelings, not the character's.
You need to express that
as a professional.
But I'm so happy you've got the role.
That's not true.
I'm so gutted!
I'll try much harder to catch up with you.
Sorry.
For what?
I was so jealous of you, Akina.
We've been good friends for so long.
I should have been happy for you instead.
We have our future ahead.
Thank you.
I need to go now.
Okay.
See you. Bye.
Bye.
You just don't want to fail.
But you never know the outcome
until you try doing it.
Yeah.
On Koro Koro Sendari Matogi Sowaka.
Great work!
I don't usually watch anime,
but it was great.
Such a small screen, though.
Here you go.
Master's kitsune udon...
It did bring us good luck.
Yeah.
Master, thank you so much for that.
Not me.
You both have tried so hard.
I was the first one
who treated you this dish.
If asked about this in an interview,
do mention me.
-Yes.
See. I told you,
"There's no such thing as a free lunch."
You're so serious. I'm just kidding.
Eat before the noodles get soggy.
-Let's eat!
Here you are.
-Thank you so much.
As for a deep-fried tofu,
you can remove excess oil
by pressing firmly with a sheet of paper.
If you cook it with enough seasoning,
the juice goes into the soup,
and it's delicious.
Here you go.
Oh, dear...
Master, don't you have any good ideas?
In another slump again?
Don't say that.
I must suffer to create something great.
Right?
What are you doing?
We're making a wish for your good work.
-Good night!