~ Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ~
*Misty white breaths you exhale*
~ Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte ~
*Slowly blown by the wind now*
~ Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni ~
*Into the clouds in the sky*
~ Sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku ~
*Gradually fading away*
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above the sky*
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
At the end of the day...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
When people are rushing home...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
When people are rushing home...
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
That's when my day starts.
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
This is my only menu.*
(*tonjiru, beer, sake, shochu)
If a customer wants something else...
...I'll say "I'll make it if I can."
That is my business policy.
If you're wondering if I ever get customers...
...I do get quite a few.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO (Season 2) ~
"The Late-Night Diner"
Sometimes, I eat this myself.
So I make plenty of it.
- How is it?
- It's delicious.
It's just like 'mother's cooking.'
Mine made it a bit sweeter though.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
Oh, good thing you're here!
- You wanna eat "nikujaga?" (meat-potato stew)
- That would be great.
Chiaki-san, do you want some?
I'll leave it to you, Kanemoto-san.
What she, I mean Chiaki-san's saying is...
...I'm a nice guy.
- Tastes good.
- Really?
- What's wrong?
- It's beef, right?
That's how we make it back home...
You don't like it?
It's embarrassing, actually.
At my home, we couldn't afford to buy beef.
So we used pork instead.
Even sukiyaki, I always associate it with pork.
Every household has
different circumstances.
...Right, Master?
- Yeah.
From now on, you can eat beef all you want.
I'm so happy...
Then, next time, I'll make you meat-potato stew.
But if it's beef, I wonder if I can
make it taste good.
It's okay, don't mind it.
Just by looking directly at your face...
...I already feel full.
Kanemoto-san.
Chiaki-chan.
Life sure is something, huh?
That guy had lost his family, right?
So it means, as long as a person lives,
good things can still happen.
I've come to really believe in that.
But then, a beautiful woman like her...
...why would she marry such a
dull, divorced man like him?
There's plenty of better guys out there
that she can choose from.
Could she be tricking him?
She isn't a gold-digger, is she?
It's because you both have
tasted the bitterness of life...
...that it made you narrow-minded, you know.
- Try to be more accepting.
- I'm not worried about that.
Well, certainly, a good woman
like her is just too good for a guy like him.
She even told him, "I will make you nikujaga."
Me, too... I can make that, as a matter of fact.
You're saying I'm not considered a
good woman if I'm can't make
something for a guy, don't you?
And are you saying if a woman makes nikujaga
for herself, it means she's lonely?
No, nobody said that... Right?
Congratulations!
~ Happy Birthday to You! ~
~ Happy Birthday, dear Chou-san ~
Uh, I'm not Chou-san.
It's Chuu-san, actually.
Chuu-san.
"Happy Birthday..."
"...I send you my love, Chou-san."
("You can beat that prostatic hypertrophy!")
Oh, I'm sorry.
May I see it?
Oh, this is for another establishment
just across the street.
Thank you so much.
Sorry to bother you.
Please excuse me.
What the heck was that?
But.. she sure is cute, huh?
Don't say unnecessary stuff.
Of course, in the end,
all you men say that.
Well, excuse us if we're neither
young nor cute enough for you.
Master, take their orders please...
...It'll be my treat.
- Fine, make mine ume please.
- Sure thing.
Well, it seems you're getting the hang of it, huh?
How to deal with women.
That Birthday Cake Girl...
...had come two or three times since then.
Then, one day...
...she was asked to deliver what
didn't seem to be a birthday cake.
It's like those you see in yakuza movies, isn't it?
To celebrate it with a cake? I guess the
Showa era is long gone.
"Congratulations on your 3rd Generation
'Ryuumei,' President of Niwatori Entertainment!*"
(*a yakuza group)
Doesn't the kanji look strange?
It's not supposed to be "3rd generation 'ryuumei"...
It should be written as "3rd generation shuumei*"
(*succession ceremony)
That's right! It's lacking the radical 'eh.'
[ryuu (dragon) + eh = shuu (succession)]
What should I do?
Amazing~!
"Don't stop me, mother..."
"The ryuu* on my back, a mark is missing."
(*dragon tattoo)
Don't go stumbling through life, you know.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
You didn't make a mistake
in your delivery today, did you?
My shift is done.
I just wanted to thank him for last time.
He didn't come today.
I see.
Well, I'm hungry anyway.
What do you want to eat?
If I can, I'll make you anything you like.
Okay, can it be nikujaga?
- Can you wait for it?
- It's okay.
It'll be right up.
Delicious.
If I let it stew for a longer time though,
it would've been even more flavorful.
No, it's fine... it's quite tasty already.
At our house, we used pork for our nikujaga.
I come from a poor family, that's why.
I had a customer before who said that as well...
She said her family also used pork for sukiyaki.
We did, too...
I better talk to that person.
I was the youngest of six children.
Before leaving for college in Tokyo...
...we grew up in the Hokkaido countryside.
You got a big family, eh?
We're all in good terms with each other.
My elder sister worked as a consultant
at a large cosmetics company.
She traveled back and forth
across the country.
But about six months ago,
I lost contact with her.
Her remittances stopped coming.
The last time she wrote us a letter...
She said she's working in Shinjuku.
I thought I could find my sister here.
That's why I started working
at my part-time job.
At first, it felt very weird.
What about?
That many hostesses have the same birthdays?
There were so many.
Their customers, too... They know they're
being lied to, but they seemed pleased anyway.
Well, I guess, every day
is a person's "birthday."
But what is the truth, really?
I hope you'll meet her soon.
Yeah.
Uhm, about last time...
The world, fill it up... up... with all your might...
Don't be too particular
with life, you know.
Thank you very much!
Itadakimasu.
How is it?
It tastes delicious.
Sure enough, nikujaga...
...is something I've had since childhood,
its already embedded in my psyche.
Yeah, true.
Well, I hate it.
Two years ago, when my company
transferred me to Fukuoka...
...I met a woman.
She seemed a nice woman at first glance,
someone you'd want for a bride.
I told her I liked eating nikujaga.
She would come to my apartment to make it.
It tasted good.
Then we started living together.
But every single day, she
continued to make nikujaga.
I told her that maybe she could try
making something else.
What did she say?
She said, "I'm sorry I'm only doing nikujaga."
"Because I wanted you to like it,
I worked so hard to make nikujaga."
Touching, huh?
I, too was moved by her.
And I grew more and more...
Akiko, that was her name...
...extremely fond of her.
We understand.
And then, only after two months...
...Akiko took all my savings and disappeared.
Happy birthday!
~ Happy Birthday to you ~
Hold on a sec, onee-chan,
are you sure you're in the right place?
She's correct.
I ordered this myself.
What? Today's your birthday?
~ Happy Birthday, Goro-san! ~
Yosh, Go-chan!
Today, you get to be reborn...
Throw away the past, and soar high
like a phoenix.
- Thank you very much.
- You, too, join us in our celebration.
- But I still have work to do...
- No, it's fine...
- Take a drink, sit down, sit down.
- Go ahead, please.
- Master, beer please!
- Comin right up.
- Looks yummy, eh?
- Here you go.
Go ahead.
Really, I can only drink a little.
My face turns all red when I drink.
It only makes you look shy,
I don't mind it at all.
Oh, please let me pour it for you.
I hope you'll get to meet a nice woman.
No, I think I already met her.
Master, nikujaga please!
My girlfriend says she really wants to eat it.
Sure thing.
In fact, the two of us are now engaged.
Well, this is really a happy occasion!
Sit, sit!
Congratulations!
Again, let me introduce
my fiancee, Chiaki-san.
I finally found my life partner.
Tomorrow, we're going to
her home in Tokushima.
Premarital trip?
Does it even matter nowadays?
I'm surprised you even said that.
What did he mean?
You're not from Tokushima but from
Hokkaido, aren't you?
Since when have you become "Chiaki?"
You're Sachiko, right...Onee-chan?
- Onee-chan?
- Akiko!!
Chiaki...!
"Chiaki?"
Is this... a nikujaga scam?!
Who's Sachiko?
What "scam?"
Onee-chan, cut that out already, will ya?
You caught me.
You're still at it?
In the past, you were good at fake crying.
But you've now become terrible at it.
Stop blaming me.
Where's the nearest police station?
It's located right outside that street.
I'm really sorry for the inconvenience.
I will take responsilbility in
bringing her to the police.
I am truly sorry!
Ouch! Wait, my things...
Darn it... Alright, already...!
Wait, don't you think you
went a little overboard with that cake?
I'm all icky and sticky now.
Onee-chan, why the hell did you
have to encroach on my turf?
Because Master's nikujaga tastes too good.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, it really WAS delicious, wasn't it?
So good, it's should be a sin, right?
Sure brings back memories...
Being sentimental ain't our thing.
That's true.
The police station's there.
After that, the two did not show up there...
They seemed to have disappeared from town.
("The Nikujaga Scam Sisters Captured!... Up to
20 people victimized across the country...")
"The world..."
"The world" what?
Even he... was at a loss for words.
If you want your nikujaga to have a
richer taste, try adding coarse-grained sugar.
You can also try using sweet onions.
Oh, smells so good...
We have some important stuff to do.
So please, you can have it.
Sorry, but we have to go.
Really embarrassing.
So then, good night.
To be continued...
~ Heya no katasumi de bon'yari hikaru terebi ~
*From the corner of the room, the TV flickers*
KOBAYASHI Kaoru as 'Master'
KOCHI Machiko as 'Chiaki'
~ 'Ashita no tenki wa kumori deshou...' to ~
*'Tomorrow's weather will be cloudy...'*
MAEDA Aki as 'Noriko'
KANEKO Kiyobumi as 'Kanemoto'
~ Dareka ga tsubuyaita ~
*Someone muttered*
MATSUO Satoru as 'Goro'
ANDO Tamae as 'Marilyn'
~ Bokura wa uso tsuku yo ~
*We may lie*
FUWA Mansaku as 'Chuu'
UNO Shohei as 'Komichi'
~ Heiki de uso wo tsuku yo ~
*To lie without blinking an eye*
KOBAYASHI Asako as 'Rumi'
and ODAGIRI Joe as 'Katagiri'
~ Demo tadashii uso no tsuki kata ~
*But to use a lie properly*
Music: SATOU Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by SUZUKI Tsunekichi
~ Dekite iru no ka na ~
*Is something I'm not able to do*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
Food Stylist: IIJIMA Nami
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Based on the manga by: ABE Yaro
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Screenplay: MANABE Katsuhiko
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Directed by: MATSUOKA Joji
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*