~ Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ~
*Misty white breaths you exhale*
~ Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte ~
*Slowly blown by the wind now*
~ Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni ~
*Into the clouds in the sky*
~ Sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku ~
*Gradually fading away*
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above in the sky*
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
At the end of the day...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
...when people are rushing to get home...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
...when people are rushing to get home...
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
...that's when my day starts.
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
This is my only menu.
(tonjiru, beer, sake, shochu)
If a customer wants something else...
...I'll say "I'll make it if I can."
That is my business policy.
(Store Sign: 'Meshi-ya')
If you're wondering if I ever get customers...
...I do get quite a number.
SHINYA SHOKUDO
(The Late Night Diner)
=Season 2=
Everytime Ryu-chan comes to my diner...
...he always asks for this.
This one, right?
This one, too.
Yeah, yeah... this one's interesting, too.
Are you guessing the winning horses for
tomorrow's race?
We're guessin' who'll get picked
for the baseball season.
- Were you in a baseball team in school before?
- Yeah.
You didn't go beyond the first game?
Bet they made you sit and wait as
a substitute for a thousand years.
Did your baseball team make
a mistake gettin' you?
No, actually, I was quite good.
Because our captain...
Shingu had qualified, eh?
Lucky kid... he's still in a Tokyo high school.
Were you listening to me...?
Thanks for the food.
Thanks for coming.
...there wasn't much difference between
me and our captain's level of playing.
Is that so.
Good evening!
Hasn't Ryu-chan come yet?
Unfortunately, he left just now.
Oh, darn.~
It's because you guys walk too slow.
Is this the one?
Where Kosozu-nesan gets his tamagoyaki?
It's so like from the Showa era, right?
I know, right?
Such a nice diner.
This Ryu-chan fella...
he's Kosozu-nesan's sweetheart, right?
I have yet to see what he looks like.
Ryu-chan's the best-lookin
guy around these parts.
You seldom catch him around, you know.
If you say so.
Excuse me...
- Can I sit here, Onii-san?
- Go ahead.
Master, I'll have tamagoyaki and beer.
The fugitive was cornered
inside the theater?
Did you all leave then?
That's what we thought, too...
We were ready to leave early.
We were feeling anxious...
But then we thought against it...
Besides dancer-chan hasn't
removed her top yet.
Then before we knew it...
...the cop subdued
one of the customers.
He took a picture of it, too...
you wanna see, Master?
Are you gonna use it for your
next photo exhibit?
You must be joking, Master...
As a photographer, I will be
found suspicious if I do that.
Don't tell me...
...are you arresting us?
This isn't like those old detective movies.
Are you looking for someone?
No, sorry to bother you.
You're still not done yet, boss?
Nobody asked you to accompany me.
Besides, you got somethin'
to tell me.
Huh?
Told you no gambling on high school baseball
games but you accepted a bet from a customer.
Why did ya not tell me, huh?
No, you see...
H-He's a good customer...
He pays well...
Oww!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry...
I'm sorry.
Alright, stop that.
Using one's fists to teach someone
a lesson is so old-fashioned nowadays.
You obviously allow gambling.
But you still don't allow betting
on high school baseball games?
At least you have principles, eh?
What do you want from me, Detective-san?
Kumi is in the hospital.
I want you to visit her.
It's too late for me to meet with her now.
Komi-chan, congratulations!
Kosozu-san, where can I put this?
Kosozu-san, did you hear me?
Ryu-chan looks so handsome.
This picture makes him look
like a real man.
What're you doing?
Quit leering at it.
That's my Ryu-chan, okay?
You're right about him,
Kosozu-nesan.
That's him, huh?
What~? He was a baseball player in high school?
He played baseball from an elite school
in Fukuoka City in Kawasaki...
I heard that even professional scouts
have gone to see him play.
He was the number one slugger of Fukuoka.
Fukuoka isn't there
...it's in Kyushu.
But not surprisingly...
...when he was set to play in Koshien Stadium*...
(*venue for annual HS baseball tournaments)
...He had a fight with some local thugs.
He wasn't allowed to play anymore.
Bet his team-mates couldn't forgive him.
Got cut off... maybe because he didn't
consider the consequences.
That's what you get for mixing
up with the Yakuza.
Can't stand such people, right?
Master, thanks for the meal.
I'm putting my pay here.
Alright.
Are you gonna go back already?
I don't know the reason
for the fight...
You should be glad Ryu-chan
didn't hear your talk...
As much as possible, I don't wanna
hang around here with you.
Master, I enjoyed the meal.
Good night.
At the end of the day...
...people rush to get home.
But if you have something left unfinished...
...some nights, you may want to make a detour.
Master, I'm done.
Alright.
Welcome.
Ryu-chan isn't here.
I came as a customer today.
What does that guy often order?
I miss this stuff.
Manager* used to make these for us.
(*gofer - takes care of the needs of school's
sports team, usually girls)
... It's just like it, too - octopus with six legs.
(*gofer - takes care of the needs of school's
sports team, usually girls)
Ryu and I used to be classmates
in high school.
Did you happen to be in the baseball team?
That guy was due to play in Koshien...
On that day, he had a date
with Manager...
She was supposed to give him
a boxed lunch of sausages like these...
But unfortunately, at that time
he got entangled with some punks...
He was protecting Kumi, the Manager...
...he had no choice.
Did Ryu-chan bear a grudge?
It was a thing of the past.
But that wasn't the reason why he wasn't
allowed to go to Koshien.
It's because he was dating Kumi.
We were all in love with Kumi.
But she's gonna die soon.
Change for cash.
I didn't have the chance to tell you before...
She doesn't have enough time left.
She has recurring breast cancer.
She can't be saved anymore.
That's why today...
Be sure to visit her.
If you still refuse...
...we'll charge this guy of yours
with obstruction of justice.
...and I'm sure we can dug up more dirt
that we can charge him with.
So for the time being,
we're gonna take him in.
Go ahead.
Whatta surprise...
you're a religious guy, eh?
That's why it's Oinari-sama* right?... Go on in.
(*fox diety = protector of rice harvest/patron
of those involved in food production)
- You wanna know why?
- What about?
Why I always ask for red weiners?
It isn't really my concern...
But a classmate of yours did come over...
That detective told me about it.
It's too late to meet with her now.
She's dying... what do you say
to a dying person anyway?
There's really nothing to say.
But Ryu-chan...
To meet with her or not,
it's not for you to decide.
But rather it was
her wish to see you.
Mind your own business.
He works in a Shinjuku office...
Same as me, he's a government employee.
Sorry to drop in so suddenly.
It's no trouble at all.
She's looking forward
to meeting with Kenzaki-san.
I'm going back to work now.
Okay, take care.
Goodbye.
Ryu-chan, you look fine.
Well, in Shinjuku, he's the pack leader
of his group of stray dogs.... no?
In Shinjuku...
...I go to this diner that opens
from midnight til morning.
...and so does this guy.
When he's there, he only eats
octopus-shaped wieners.
He's still such a fool, isn't he?
I'm glad.
Wah~... he's at a loss for words.
Oh, phonecall.
I have to take this outside...
...HQ doesn't know I'm here..
And now the office is calling me...
Yeah, hello?
Noguchi-kun hasn't changed much, huh?
Finally you smiled.
Don't mind about the old days
anymore, okay?
Don't let such silly things bother you.
I don't care about that.
I think you still do.
Noguchi asked you several times
but you refused.
You silly man...
I thought you've matured a little.
You haven't changed.
You still are childish.
Running around in
that Yakuza world of yours.
After you dropped out and left school...
The students from other classes...
...and sometimes, the teachers, too...
blamed me for it.
That's the way it was, I guess.
But I...
...had no bad feelings
about it at all.
My feelings still haven't changed.
When I told Noguchi-kun that you were
just protecting me on that day...
Well, you know how Noguchi-kun is...
...Believing that you and I were dating...
He was in tears when he confessed
his love to me.
But I refused him.
At that time...
I just wanted to marry you...
I loved you.
Hello.
Right now, your mom is talking
with an important friend...
It's best to wait a awhile.
Oh... that man from the baseball team.
Yes... but he's really not
that talented in baseball.
I was the star athlete, and that
guy just likes to hang out with me.
Listen... You wanna
play catch with me?
But Noguchi-san, don't you have work to do?
There are some things in this world
that're more important than work.
C'mon, let's go.
Before I got married and lived here...
I went to Tokyo...
... to search for you once.
I went to the Harajuku crossing,
and to Shibuya Central Avenue.
I went to many places but didn't find you.
Of course, it's obviously not that
easy to find you.
Also when I got hungry...
I ate a super delicious beef bowl
for the first time.
Then I took the last bullet train home.
But I also thought it wouldn't be good...
...if we see each other again.
That day...
...if I didn't ask you out for a date...
...I wonder what could've been?
No use saying that now.
I also...
...wanna go to that diner and
eat those sausages.
Sure, anytime.
Thank you for coming.
I'll come again.
Okay.
~ Omoide de mo wasureta inara ~
*Should you have memories you wish to forget*
~ Sa atashi ga keshi gomu de keshite ageru wa ~
*I'll help you wipe them away with an eraser*
~ Anshin shite oyasumi nasai ~
*To ease the mind into a good night sleep*
~Kogoeru yona samui asa mo yureru daichi mo~
*Early icy cold morning, the earth shakes*
~ Karada ni kizama reta kioku ga ~
*Memories engraved in the body*
~ Anata o tsuyoku suru no deshou ~
*Not sure if it can make you strong*
~ Yagate wa tsuchi ni kaerou to wakatte ite mo ~
*In the end, even if we know we'll return to dust*
~ Kono kimochi wa doshitara doshitara ii no ~
*What do you think I should
do with these feelings?*
~ Atashi no uta wa nani ni mo
chikara nankanai kedo ~
*This song of mine is not so intense*
~ Anata no kokoro o sukoshi dake naderu
kurainara dekiru kamo ~
*But perhaps may offer comfort to your heart*
~ Omoide de mo wasureta inara ~
*Having memories you wish to forget*
('Salt for cleansing' = funeral goers are given salt
for dispersing to cleanse oneself from bad luck)
~ Omoide de mo wasureta inara ~
*Having memories you wish to forget*
~ Sa atashi ga keshi gomu de keshite ageru wa ~
*I'll help you wipe them away with an eraser*
~ Anshin shite oyasumi nasai ~
*To ease the mind into a good night sleep*
~ Yarusenai yuhi yori ~
*More than the dreary sunset*
To be continued...
~ Shinji reru asahi o mitai ~
*Rather see the sunrise to believe*
KOBAYASHI KAORU as 'Master'
~ Dakara sukoshi yume o mi sasete ~
*Let me dream a little*
MATSUSHIGE YUTAKA as 'Ryu'
MITSUISHI KEN as 'Noguchi'
~ Ashita e mukau tame ~
*So I can go on tomorrow*
NARUMI YASUDA as 'Kumi'
TOSHIKI AYATA as 'Kosuzu'
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
FUWA MANSAKU as 'Chuu-san'
UNO SHOHEI as 'Komichi'
KOBAYASHI ASAKO as 'Rumi'
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Music: Satou Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by Suzuki Tsunekichi
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
Insert Song: "Dekiru Koto" by Fukuhara Kimie
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Food Stylist: Iijima Nami
Screenplay: Manabe Katsuhiko
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
Based on the manga by: Abe Yaro
Directed by: Matsuoka Joji
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*