Opening Song
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Directed By Matsuoka Joji
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
As the day comes to an end,
and people make their way home,
my own day begins.
~ Traditional Tonjiru ~ 600 yen
~ Beer ~ 600 yen, ~ Sake ~ 500 yen
~ Shochu ~ 400 yen
Max. three drinks per customer
My menu is all there.
The possibility of getting
served anything else...
as long as it's possible,
my business model.
I am open from midnight
to seven of the morning after.
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
~ WITHS2 4th Anniversary Special ~
SHINYA SHOKUDO - midnight restaurant
Final Episode
Ramen
I see you've done
your share of killings.
In my past life?
No... The one before that.
When was that?
I'd say about a
thousand years ago.
We're in Kumano,
Wakayama Prefecture.
World Heritage and stuff?
As you sow,
so shall you reap.
It is the endless circle of life.
So you're leaving in
search of your identity.
A journey you've long been waiting for.
Keep the change.
Please.
You're heading into
a dark abyss, as we speak.
You alone have the key
to escape from such destiny.
Hey!
That day was the very first time
I saw Gen-chan coming by himself.
How about laver?
Sadly, I ran out of that.
You ran out?!
Ran out...
Ramen without laver,
does it make any sense?
Ahh... Shit!
Ahh... Hurts....
I told you I can't handle hot food.
Here.
I'll have laver
ready for you next time.
That uneasy look in his
face right before he left...
It made me quite nervous.
That night, Gen-chan stabbed a
young boss from a rival Yakuza gang,
and went into hiding.
~ 2 weeks later ~
Thanks for that.
Thank you.
Alone tonight?
They both stood me up and
went to a gokon (group blind date).
That's that, but what happened
to that Gen-chan fella?
AWOL.
He's quite the meticulous
fella, as I thought.
Yakuza live and die
by their word, after all.
Seems like he had made up
his mind to retaliate for what happened.
Aneki ("big brother" in Yakuza lingo)!
Aneki!
So by now he must be buried
somewhere in Tokyo and all.
I'm kidding!
Just a joke...
Why are you all so serious?
I hope he's doing just fine...
Kenzaki-san.
I'd like a word with you.
What's the matter, kiddo?
Come on in.
Hey there.
You're early today, Kosuzu-san.
Ohh... Kiddo, come on in.
Cute! Kosuzu-san,
is that your nephew?
How could he possibly have a
nephew, when he can't have children?
I have a seed,
don't you worry.
He was standing outside.
Kiddo, are you
here to meet someone?
I just thought that, if I came
here, I could meet my father.
Nice to meet you, I'm Kenta.
You're my father, aren't you?
If you want evidence, here you go.
You know who I'm
talking about.
Where is he now?
If I knew, I would
have already told you by now.
You'll pardon me, but
no smoking inside the car.
You know, we've had our share
of troubles as of late,
so we really didn't have
time to get intimidated by you.
Just tell him to turn himself in.
Here's your juice.
If it's not Master, then who?
This is the right address for sure...
Master, can I ask you a favor?
Was wondering if you could
deliver ramen to my bar.
Ask Chin-san instead.
All we have is instant noodles,
and they'd be cold before they arrive.
It's all right,
he can't eat hot food anyway.
Right?
I see, you've got a point....
That'd take all the taste out of it.
Forget I even asked.
I'll get back to work, then.
I'll see you later.
Eh?! Are you leaving already?
I just recalled
something I need to do.
Fine, see you.
But kids these days
are not like us back then.
They're not even snotty.
Of course not!
How far back is that?
What's wrong with that?
Aren't you hungry?
Want me to make you something?
Is this an abacus?
With peanuts?!
That's great!
You found peanuts
that all look the same?!
Makes you dizzy.
Can I touch it?
With care...
Dusseldorf?
Where's that?
In Germany.
Near that, they found
bones of the Neanderthal.
So he lived overseas...
That's quite something.
So, before leaving,
he thought of his real father, to whom
he sent birthday cards every year.
What a good boy!
I don't know how my father
looks like, and have no photos.
Ohh... Yuki-san.
Long time no see.
How are you?
So it was this much.
- Master. Ramen.
- Coming.
Ramen, again.
A strange night indeed,
with ramen orders piling up.
If you let it cool down
so much, it'll get bloated.
I can't handle hot food so well.
Come on in.
Ma... Master.
I wanted to see
who ordered the ramen.
Care for some beer?
I understand.
Who would ever like to have
a drink with someone like me?
So you let your aneki deal with trouble,
while you were sitting here.
I knew you would say that.
You can never go
back and erase the past.
What matters is how
you deal with the aftermath.
But...
I crossed a bridge of no return.
Isn't that just an excuse
made by people who....
refuse to solve their problems?
Thanks.
Oi...
Come eat some ramen at my place.
I have all the laver
you want tonight.
So you just slightly
stabbed him, right?
Then they'll just charge
you for infliction of injury,
and if luck's on your side,
suspend the sentence.
You're sure?
Guess so.
I wanted you to meet your father...
His son is here to meet him.
Hey...
Are you... Kenta?
How are you?
Nice to meet you.
Is there anything you'd like to eat?
Ramen...
All they have here is instant.
I can't have it at home,
so my mother doesn't like instant.
Master! Ramen!
Coming.
Like it?
Really?
We'll meet again, right?
Yeah.
I'll write you a letter next time.
Your address?
You can send it here as always.
- Be well.
- You too, Dad.
Aneki...
I can do it by myself.
I won't run, now.
Stick to me.
I'll write you for sure!
The address is here!
So one shouldn't be
unhappy during Christmas?
Well... Forgot it.
But it's just one day a year,
and I'm not excluding myself,
but spending it in
such a place is a little...
I'm sorry.
Oh! Ryu-chan!
Hey... Come on in!
His sentence was suspended.
Is that so?
I owe you so much in many ways....
Look at this!
- Crabs!
- Crabs...
Santa does exist indeed, Master!
Let's have it!
Fine!
Let's go wild tonight and have crabs!
This is what you call....
"Silent Night".
So you're finally going.
If I remain at a
nice place for too long,
I get the urge to
visit the complete opposite.
That's quite the burdensome disposition.
It troubles me as well.
On that note, here...
This is for my tab, all this time.
Just keep it.
If you're going to a new place,
you'll need plenty of things.
Please, take it.
I just think that, this time,
I will be away for quite a while.
I see.
So...
I'll take responsibility for that wound.
This world of ours!
Meanders and
wanders round and round.
Don't belittle life!
Come on in.
Even if not on the menu,
I'll make you anything you want.