Opening Song
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
STARRING
Kobayashi Kaoru
Tabata Tomoko
Taguchi Tomorowo
Odagiri Jo
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Odagiri Jo
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Directed by Matsuoka Joji
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
Directed by Matsuoka Joji
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
As the day comes to an end,
and people make their way home,
my own day begins.
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
Max. three drinks per customer
My menu is all there.
The possibility of getting
served anything else...
as long as it's possible,
my business model.
I am open from midnight
to seven of the morning after.
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
How is business doing?!
Well enough, I'd say.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
Midnight Restaurant
Episode 2
Nekomanma (Cat Food)
The first time she came...
was right around
half past six in the morning,
when I was about to close.
You have katsuobushi*?
(*dried fish scrapings)
I do have it, but...
I wanted some on top of warm rice,
sprinkled with soy sauce.
You mean nekomanma (cat food)?
You like it as well?
Yeah.
Can you...
wait a little while?
Yeah...
I'm a little short on money, though.
Since we're here,
should I make
it from fresh rice?
I suddenly got the
urge to eat some myself.
Really?
Yeah...
Bon apetit.
How is it?
After that day,
and right around the same time...
Hey!
Here I am again.
What is it you do until
this early in the morning?
Is it work?
Karaoke box.
You know...
Promise you won't laugh.
Yeah.
I'm an enka singer.
Although "unsuccessful" should
come before that, I guess.
I get no work,
but I still want to sing,
so I spend the whole
night singing there.
Even though they're not my songs...
Do you have songs
of your own as well?
Just one.
You won't find it
at most karaoke bars,
and nobody really knows about it.
Among our regulars...
there is this composer.
Really?
Bring your poster next time.
I'll hang it there.
Really?
As the day comes to an end,
and people are
rushing back home,
they sometimes
get this uneasy feeling,
getting the urge of spending
the night somewhere else.
Thanks for that.
~ Life, Wherever Fate Leads Me ~
Chidori Miyuki
What's this?
I live to witness this thing here,
now I've seen them all.
Want to buy one?
I even have a CD.
So you've completely fallen for her?!
It's this kiddo who often
comes by to eat nekomanma.
I like it, too.
Nekomanma.
That doesn't sound like
much of an answer, Master.
Does anyone sing "wherever
their fate leads them"?!
I hate that stuff.
What stuff?
You know the stuff they
sing in the southern end?
Of the street?
Yeah...
Who listens to that anyway?
Listening to them
will only make you sad.
Must be the same for her.
But that's where the next
popular star might come from.
Isn't that all the more cruel and sad?
"I might become a
star just like them!"
You know, spreading hope and the like.
Let's listen!
If I like it,
you can sell me one.
All we have here is an old radio.
Sensei...
How about it?
He's a composer, I hear.
The kiddo, does she
come here frequently?
Then, how about you have
her sing here instead?
That's an idea!
Let's do it, let's do it!
If she's good,
I'll buy her CD.
Could become a hit.
This world of ours...
is like the Nile's tide,
what goes around comes around.
Don't belittle life.
Still....
Is he curious to listen
her song or something?
Or maybe he just
wants to meet her?!
When they're young
and breathe, anyone is fine.
- Men are simple, aren't they?
- Yes!
(*rice with green tea and toppings)
Master, another round of ochazuke*.
- Tarako for me.
- Ume. - Salmon.
Coming.
Didn't you say so yourself once?
Time isn't kind
to anyone, darling.
- Like it's kind to you.
- Life, wherever fate leads me?!
Isn't it?
~ Shinjuku Golden Street ~
~ Enka's New Star ~
Chidori Miyuki
CONCERT
~ Free Admission ~
Wherever fate leads me,
wherever fate leads my life to.
From your childhood...
to your adulthood,
life goes wherever
fate leads it to.
Wherever fate leads me,
wherever fate leads my life to.
Finding a back alley...
and walking around in circles...
is what I enjoy the most.
I'm buying!
Give me a CD!
Here you go.
Don't know how to explain it,
but it has personality.
Still, your voice makes
quite the impression.
As for the song, I don't really know
whether it's sad or whatever.
But a young lady like you eating
nekomanma, isn't that a little strange?!
You're from the
northeast, aren't you?
How did you know?
Yeah... What they
call nekomanma in the western regions...
is usually rice with soybean paste.
But soy sauce is not too
good for cats' health.
Because it's too salty.
But without soy sauce
it would have no taste.
No, no way.
Because cats have weak
kidneys and don't sweat,
they really don't
need that much salt.
But I love salty foods...
Here... Miyuki-chan.
A present for you.
Why do you always
contradict each other?
Why do you?
Why do we...
If you think about it,
don't you get along just fine?
Stray cat.
Listening to your voice,
the words just came out naturally.
Sensei!
Miyuki-chan.
The most important thing...
is your desire to sing.
Never forget that, all right?
Thank you very much.
Men who cry never return.
A life of wandering filled
her days from the very start.
Once again, a stray cat...
wanders the street
which never sleeps, Shinjuku.
From a back alley far away
from the business quarters,
a woman wandering
the streets in search of a...
blossoming love a man
left withering in the wind.
Where am I headed now?
Here is newcomer Chidori Miyuki,
singing "Stray Cat."
From the lips of a
hostess who no longer knew love,
it listened,
in her lap's embrace.
She sang the old pleas of
men from her past.
Roaming the nights of Shinjuku,
was the stray cat.
Today we feature the hit singer
of "Stray Cat," Chidori Miyuki.
- Welcome.
- Thank you for having me.
~ Chidori Miyuki's "Stray Cat" ~
100,000 Copies Sold
In our fleeting everyday life,
~ Chidori Miyuki - 5 Straight Weeks on Top ~
Sad memories accumulate.
Ahh, are you there? Just a moment.
Giving your body and soul...
- He's in the parking lot.
- Yes.
Giving your body and soul...
To a lying man...
I can't really explain it,
but I'm just giving my best for now.
Roaming the streets of Shinjuku
Is the stray cat...
I've gotten used to waiting now
Chidori Miyuki
Entering Red & White Song Contest
I've gotten used to waiting now
- The Red & White Contest!
- She's something.
I've gotten used to waiting now
- The Red & White Contest!
- She's something.
To a woman...
Love is hell even if drenched by the bottle
The wet neon lights glowing in the dark
The very last time she
came to my restaurant...
was about a month before she died.
Miyuki-chan...
Do you have katsuobushi?
Bon apetit.
This taste is just...
Master.
Thank you so much.
Uh? For what?
If I hadn't come to this place,
I would have never gotten the chance
to experience so much happiness.
No words can express
how thankful I am.
Should I have one as well?
Can you?
Yeah.
It's not that cold.
Is it all right with you?
Yeah.
Remember Chu-san?
The one who bought your CD.
He always said that he'd get
your autograph next time you come,
so, sorry if I ask,
but will you...
~ Closed for the Day ~
I never expected it to happen
to someone as popular as she was.
Miyuki-chan really made it big.
She was the Miyuki-chan from this place.
The one we knew...
Wherever fate leads you.
Wherever it leads your life to.
From your childhood
to your adulthood...
it is wherever fate
leads you to, indeed.
It was quite the peculiar song,
but it sure suited Miyuki-chan.
You said something strange
happened this morning, Master?
~ Chidori Miyuki ~
Bravely Fights Illness Until Death
Miyuki-chan.
Glad you came.
~ To be continued ~
With katsuobushi, it's always
better to scrape it fresh.
But these days you don't
quite get the chance, do you?
Look at that!
I knew it!
This must be the best way to do it.
Good night everyone.