~ Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ~
*Misty white breaths you exhale*
~ Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte ~
*Slowly blown by the wind now*
~ Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni ~
*Into the clouds in the sky*
~ Sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku ~
*Gradually fading away*
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above the sky*
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
At the end of the day...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
When people are rushing home...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
When people are rushing home...
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
That's when my day starts.
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
Do I ever get customers, you may ask?
I do get quite a few.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO (Season 2) ~
'The Late Night Diner'
Today, I'm making cream stew.
I've been doing this business
for a long time...
...somehow, I've developed
the instinct for it.
Good evening.
Master, can you make cream stew?
That's what I'm making right now.
Good timing.
It sure is getting chilly!
Like I know that...
...pretty soon, when my customers come in...
...they will all be asking
for cream stew.
Yo.
Welcome.
- A cup of hot sake.
- Comin' right up.
- Master.
- You wanna eat that?
Can I have some please?
I got enough left for two.
- Suzuki-san, you want?
- I...uh..
No thanks.
You don't need to tear it.
- Here... Throw these away.
- You sure?
Nagata-kun here said he
won't publish it...
...so that makes these
wastepaper then.
Also these.
I'm only telling you to rewrite it.
The setting of a homeless man as
the protagonist was too outdated.
I think it's acute.
For me...
...I'm already
finished with it.
Well, don't blame me.
I need a drink.
Highball please!
Comin right up.
You do have a proper home...
but you just don't want to go back to it.
Homeless people are those
who don't have a home.
It is said, 'The happiness in a family
is a source of all evil.'
[a quote from writer, Osamu Dazai]
Suzuki-san, please write fiction like Dazai.
There is still a market for "I Novels."
(literary novels using first-person narrative)
Someone did say "Despite having
parents, a child still grows."
(A quote from writer, Sakaguchi Ango)
There are lots of incidents lately of
parents killing their children.
Strange how a child might
be better off without parents.
That's why... 'a child still grows
even without parents.'*
[*a Japanese proverb]
Is that your daughter?
The wife sends her picture to me
from time to time.
- Can I take a closer look at it?
- Thanks for waiting.
- Why don't you go back home?
- Ah? I already missed my
chances to go home.
Gimme a cigarette, too.
At first, I returned home every two days.
Gradually, it came down to weekends.
Then finally, only at the end of the month.
Before I realized it, I was no longer going back.
Pretty soon, ten years had already passed.
So it means your daughter
is now in college?
That's why a child still grows
even without parents.
Yeah, but your wife raised her up
all on her own, didn't she?
Pete's sakes.
- Careful now.
- Okay...one, two, three.
What's up!
- Good evening!
- Hello.
- Hana-chan!
- Long time, no see!
- Could that be cream stew I'm smelling?
- That's right.
- There's still enough left for one person.
- How lucky!
Lucky for you there was one customer
who didn't order it.
- Is it okay with you, Hoko-chan?
- Nah, you go ahead, Hana-chan.
- Master, I'll have tonjiru and beer.
- Comin right up.
Delicious!
Glad you like it.
It's ready-mix roux, isn't it?
But I did put in some butter.
...and sprinkled in
some green peas.
When I was in elementary school
during winter time...
...I was invited by my crush to do our
homework at his home...
...I stayed over for dinner and
we had cream stew.
At that time, I had thought...
..."I can't become his bride."
My mother had always made
this using ready-made roux.
If we use flour, it will either be too lumpy...
...or it gets burnt.
That's why I always think of this
as the taste of cream stew.
Hana-chan?
Oh, I'm sorry!
It's just that it has been so
long since I've eaten this dish.
I was remembering the times when my
family and I would eat mom's cream stew.
Hello.
Can you send a girl over here?
Can it be Kaede-chan?
I'm Suzuki, membership no. 5432.
Is it morning already?
Did I wake you up?
Have to get dressed for school.
Aren't you working yourself too hard?
Tastes great.
A morning cup of
roasted green tea.
Good, isn't it?
Some say that if you're able to grasp
the mole on the palm on your hand...
...you will be happy.
I think...
...I've heard about that somewhere.
Having a mole on one's palm is rare, isn't it?
But you know...
I can't grasp it.
When I was a small, I could grasp it...
Then, ever since my dad left us...
...I haven't been able to grasp it.
"Neither did Tyltyl and Mytyl* have parents."
(From 80's anime, 'Maeterlinck's Blue Bird')
"From their tiny hands, the blue bird
of happiness escapes."
"Elusive it may be,
they hold on to their dreams."
Don't belittle life, you know.
Is that your daughter?
She's pretty, huh?
I don't know where you can go
and get more drinks.
But in my diner, this will be your
last order of sake.
Her name's Sumire.
Like her mother, right?
If you'll excuse me.
Sorry.
I'm not open til 12.
What's with the outfit?
It's for my prospective job...
- Today, I've been hired unofficially.
- Well, congratulations.
Good luck with it.
I'm gonna graduate from the hostess club.
Next year, I'm also gonna
graduate from college.
I still have to submit some reports for tomorrow.
See you.
Maybe it's because she cannot
grasp the mole on her hand...
She ended up not getting hired...
...after they found out about
Hana-chan's hostess job.
Good evening, I'm from
the Milky Club.
Yeah, I was just taking a bath.
Just give me a minute, okay?
Sorry for the bother.
- May I have the payment in advance please?
- Yeah, I know.
Anyway, d'you drink coffee?
I have here organically cultivated beans.
It's very good.
It's home-roasted.
Having said that, I didn't roast it though.
Or maybe you prefer beer?
But maybe you're not allowed
to drink while working?
You ARE working, right?
Wait...where're you going?
I'll pay in advance, okay?
Don't you recognize me?
Sumire?... But why?
What're you trying to do, Dad?
I'm doing research work on call girls.
It's true! Right now, I'm writing a novel
called 'Sakura Night Cop.'
Liar...
You're despicable!
I had no idea since Suzuki
is such a common name.
I'm leaving right now,
you don't mind, do you?
- You want to ask for a different girl?
- Hold on a sec.
- What do you like, sir? We have lots
of other girls to choose from.
- Sumire!
What're you doing?!
I miss the sugary taste
of sweet potato.
Hello, Suzuki-san.
- Hana-chan!
- Welcome.
Why did you suddenly stop
working at the club?
We were looking for you.
How are you getting by
without money?
This is my daughter, Sumire.
Daughter?
Give me one, too.
You're a smoker?
You know nothing about me.
If your mother finds out what
you're doing...
...she'll surely kill herself.
Why didn't YOU kill yourself?
You want me dead?
You haven't been home so it makes
no difference whether you're alive or dead.
Sorry.
Will an apology resolve anything?
It was my fault.
If I hadn't left you guys...
...you wouldn't have become a call girl.
I'm sorry.
Mom never said a word against you.
And I hated it.
But I'm not like Mom.
And I'm not like you either.
I'll live my life independently
and positively.
If you're expecting me to
recognize you as my father...
...I'd rather blame you
than recognize you!
Come in.
Excuse me.
Please have a seat.
- I'm sorry.
- Wait!
Please sit down.
I'm still not done with the interview.
Suzuki Sumire-san.
Remember when you told me about
the mole on your palm?
I forgot to tell you...
to do it like this.
To put your palm on top of the other.
See? This way, you can grasp it.
It'll be fine, don't worry.
But isn't this cheating?
It doesn't matter... consider it
a shortcut to happiness.
Thank you, Hoko-chan.
Thank you.
After Hana-chan had grasped
the mole on her palm...
...Hoko-chan hired her as a contract
employee in his company.
Thanks for waiting.
Uh... one more bowl of this, please.
Comin right up!
Why?
Mom...
- Long time, no see.
- Same here.
It's very interesting.
You haven't read yet your dad's novel, right?
I will read it.
Me, too.
I'll fix it first.
You can read it after I'm done
rewriting it.
Cream stew's really suited
for this kind of weather, isn't it?
~ Samui yoru ni wa oishii shichuu ~
*Cold nights, with delicious stew*
~ Shichuu tsukurou ~
*Making some stew*
~ Kotokoto nimashou ~
*Clanging pots and boiling stew*
~ Mukashi-mukashi no... mama no shichuu ~
*Long long ago... my mother's stew*
Coat the chicken with flour
to have a thicker stew.
If you add thick cream or butter
with a bit of the roux...
...it'll have a deep richer flavor.
Here you go.
Smells good...
You guys should try it, too.
Well, good night.
Let's eat.~
~ Yarusenai yuhi yori ~
*More than the dreary sunset*
To be continued
~ Shinji reru asahi o mitai ~
*Rather see the sunrise to believe*
KOBAYASHI KAORU as 'Master'
~ Dakara sukoshi yume o mi sasete ~
*Let me dream a little*
FUKIKOSHI MITSURU as 'Suzuki'
ASAKURA AKI as 'Hana/Sumire'
~ Ashita e mukau tame ~
*So I can go on tomorrow*
TOKUI YU as 'Hoko'
FUWA MANSAKU as 'Chuu-san'
MATSUO SATORU as 'Goro'
KOBAYASHI ASAKO as 'Rumi'
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
and ODAGIRI JOE as 'Katagiri'
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Music: Satou Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by Suzuki Tsunekichi
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
Insert song: 'Cream Stew'
by Fukuhara Kimie
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Food Stylist: Iijima Nami
Based on the manga by: Abe Yaro
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
Screenplay: Arai Haruhiko
and Arai Misa
Directed by: Matsuoka Joji
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*