When people finish their day
and hurry home,
my day starts.
My diner is open from midnight
to seven in the morning.
They call it "Midnight Diner."
Do I even have customers?
More than you would expect.
MIDNIGHT DINER:
TOKYO STORIES
OMELET RICE
Everyone has forgotten
their umbrella somewhere.
But his case is extreme.
He is always soaking wet
whenever he comes to my joint.
Again? Just stay right there.
His name is Mr. Amamiya.
I hear that he is
a promising young physicist.
- Thanks. Omelet rice, please.
- Sure thing.
Here you go.
Let's eat.
Ah, I see!
Master, check please.
- Sure thing.
- Oh, no...
May I have my check, too?
You have to go now?
A conference is coming up soon.
I'm very busy.
Thanks for the meal.
Oh, no...
Thank you.
Another one...
Thank you so much.
I'm going that way.
Then take this umbrella.
My place is right there.
I'll be okay.
Hold on...
I may not be able to return it to you.
Can you?
- This is where I work.
- Okay.
I'm not asking you to be my customer.
Is that right?
This...
A champagne bottle.
Wait, what? What's going on?
You're soaking wet.
What happened?
This is not right.
It has to be this way.
It should be like this.
- Right there?
- Yes, I want to write it there.
- Absolutely necessary?
- Yes.
Thanks. I'll use this.
That's right. That's right.
It's Higgs potential.
HIGGS POTENTIAL IS A PHYSICS THEORY
PROPOSED BY PETER HIGGS.
Is that a permanent marker?
HIGGS POTENTIAL IS A PHYSICS THEORY
PROPOSED BY PETER HIGGS.
IT'S A DIAGRAM THAT LOOKS LIKE
A CHAMPAGNE BOTTLE.
I see. Now I got it.
IT'S A DIAGRAM THAT LOOKS LIKE
A CHAMPAGNE BOTTLE.
Your friend is a little strange.
I apologize.
Oh, no...
I can't take this home.
- Excuse me...
- Yes?
What a groundbreaking device!
This is wonderful.
How can I thank you? But...
How can I get this picture?
First you should finish it
before you forget it.
Right.
I didn't think
that you would actually come.
I just wanted to thank you in person.
It wasn't a big deal.
But...
I'm glad to see you again.
Are you okay?
You look sad.
I'm sorry.
To tell you the truth,
yesterday...
CHAPPIE
Mr. Amamiya,
thank you for coming today.
It's nothing, Rei.
My real name is Yoona.
Rei is just...
my name at the nightclub.
Yoona, huh?
Komichi, you've got
an old-fashioned toy, huh?
I hear that it's good for my brain,
so I bought it.
But it's too difficult,
so I'm just exercising my hands.
- Good evening.
Welcome.
Are you on an after-shift date?
Mr. Amamiya,
you are a guy after all.
An after-shift? What is that?
Wait, so... are you two actually dating?
Sorry.
We don't open until midnight.
Master, sorry to bother you
before opening.
I wanted to ask you a favor.
Is it...
done?
You did well.
- So her real name is Yoona?
- Yes.
She cooked it just for you, huh?
- That's so sweet.
- It was so delicious.
That's not good for my business.
- You should all learn from her.
- Mind your own business.
If we had someone special,
of course we would cook for him.
Right?
Master,
I've decided to move in with Yoona.
- Is that right? I wish you all the best.
- Thank you.
I'm going to see her family in Korea.
But when I told my mother that
Yoona and I were moving in together,
she told me to think about it more.
Is that her way of disapproving
the two of you?
Is she against an international marriage?
That shouldn't be a problem,
as long as they love each other.
But considering the cultural
and language differences,
I get why the parents
would be concerned.
My mother even said...
that I might be out of my mind.
But...
I should be out of my mind
if I'm in love, right?
It's not done perfectly.
Are you upset?
Thank you.
Mr. Amamiya has tried everything
to convince his parents,
but they haven't approved
of the marriage yet.
- Welcome.
- Good evening.
Today...
is my last day at work.
This is pickled eggplant.
I hope you like it.
- Delicious.
- Really?
I came to Japan...
in order to work and pay back
my father's business debt.
My parents...
ran...
a small diner.
But their business went south
when new restaurants opened.
Someone might see me
if I worked in Seoul.
I lied to my parents and said
I would become a translator here.
I really just wanted
to pay off their debt.
You've worked very hard.
And you paid it off?
My parents want to restart their diner.
They are very excited.
Good for them.
Have you told...
Mr. Amamiya about the debt?
I was going to tell him
once I paid it off.
I see.
Today...
- Your meal is on me.
- Really?
Then can I have another?
Of course.
Welcome.
What's wrong?
She left...
this letter.
TO MR. AMAMIYA
What does it say?
"I'm really sorry that I didn't tell you
about the debt.
When I told my parents
that I wanted to marry you,
they opposed it.
I will go back to Seoul.
And I will help my parents' diner.
I can't abandon my family
to marry you.
I'm really sorry."
Yoona...
After that, Mr. Amamiya devoted
his time to his research
and turned down meeting
with any potential marriage partner.
Is that...?
Look.
AMAMIYA, THE THIRD JAPANESE
TO EARN THE PHYSICS AWARD
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Let's eat.
I remember a diner in Seoul
that serves great omelet rice.
Really? They have omelet rice in Korea?
It's the female chef's signature dish.
She learned it in Tokyo.
Here you go.
This is the one?
- Try it. It's so delicious.
- Another one.
Welcome.
Finally, I found you.
I need you.
Wow, very romantic.
Old man, you are too old for that.
You do it in broad daylight?
Which one?
Watch your mouth!
It's none of your business!
What is he saying?
We are... totally in love!
We should go.
Mr. Amamiya.
I'm sorry, but right now...
I can't accept your love.
- Yoona...
- But please keep in mind
that I don't wish we had been born
in the same country.
Because I was born in a different country,
I was able to meet you.
Thank you for coming.
Here you go. Enjoy it.
May I grill the meat for you?
Here you go.
Thank you.
The jjigae is so delicious,
Mother.
Mother...?
It's premature for you to say that.
I hear that Mr. Amamiya is determined
to keep going to the diner
until Yoona's parents approve
of their marriage,
while doing his research in Seoul.
A life is like floating
and being carried away
by the Imjin River.
Love has no border.
Keep swimming to the end.
To make a fluffy omelet,
make sure you use a lot of butter.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Enjoy it.
Haste makes...
Waste.
Good night.
THIS STORY IS FICTION