~Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte~
*Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind*
~Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku~
*Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away*
~Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo~
*From up above in the sky white clouds reach down*
~Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru~
*To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by*
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
~Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru~
*To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by*
...That's when my day starts.
~Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru~
*To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by*
~Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne~
*Always seems like a thing of the past*
~Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
~Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
People call my eatery
'the late night diner.'
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
EP 1: "Menchi-Katsu"
"There are three 'fukuro' (bags) that are
important in marriage" speech*...
(*"The 3 Fukuro or Bags of marriage" is a
joke usually mentioned in wedding speeches)
Haven't heard that for a long time.
Yet their marriage will soon turn into
a FUKURO-kouji (dead-end street) anyway.
- Right?
Just the other day, you were talking
stuff about pure love, weren't you?
Spoke fondly of one another,
got married...
A few years later, one will cheat
and they'll get a divorce.
Give back the wedding gift!
Let's see... What was that again?
There's "Kannin-BUKURO" (patience),
also, "o-FUKURO" (mother)...
And also... Kinnn~...
Stop with your jokes.
It's "kinchacku-BUKURO" (pay check).
It did sound bad.
Should be "iBUKURO" (stomach), after all.
Thanks for waiting.
Toyama-san, butter rice again?
Since you're a food critic, you should
try other sorts of dishes.
After trying out so many...
you have come to a conclusion. Right?
Welcome.
Good evening.
Oh, I thought it was someone.
Been so long since I had your menchikatsu*
and I've been craving for it.
(*Deep-fried, breaded cutlet)
Been wanting to come here for a long time but...
I had always been coming here
with Taiichan so...
...it feels awkward if I come here alone.
The "Taicchan" she mentioned,
died 8 years ago...
...he was this person's husband.
You see, I finally...
...overtaken Taicchan in age.
You wait, okay? I'll make it right away.
Mm! It's delicious!
It's really juicy.
Haven't changed at all, huh?
It's because it's the same recipe.
I was talking about you.
I'm relieved to see your face.
The day before he died...
...he suddenly said he wanted to
eat your menchikatsu...
I told him,
"Then we'll go after you get discharged."
I see. It was indeed
Taicchan's favorite.
Master...
I'm sorry...
You don't have to force yourself...
I'll wrap the menchi for you...
...and make it an offering for Taicchan.
Thank you. I will do so.
That was Kashima Misao, right? The singer.
What!?
At first, I thought she was somebody.
They were a couple who'd often
come here to eat menchi.
Even up til now, when we go to snack bars,
there's always someone singing her song, right?
~It's fine, it's okay...~
~Don't say anything~
That's right. "Don't Say Anything".
I memorized the chords to that song.
That was a classic.
"Taicchan"? Was he Tachibana Taizo?
Oh! They were known as the songwriting husband
and the singing wife, right?
Come to think about it,
there was such a couple.
She stopped singing after her husband died.
Sometimes she'd be featured in those "What happened
now to that person" articles in gossip magazines...
Most of them say she has firmly shut
herself up inside her house.
Since she loved him so much, huh?
Me too. I want to get married to a person who'll
always think of just me even when I'm gone.
My wife is different.
If I die, she's probably
gonna burst into cheers.
Master, I'd like some menchi too.
Sure thing.
We've got some karaoke rooms available.
How about it please?
How about it, ma'am? Would you like to try?
We're having "Those Classics" promo now...
featuring Kashima Misao songs.
You can have your own personal playlist.
Would you like to take this opportunity to sing?
How about it?
Welcome.
One butter rice.
Oh, on second thought...
Can you give me cold liquor?
Sure thing.
My wife has fallen ill.
She's in the hospital right now.
It's cancer.
She had surgery but I wonder
what's gonna happen...
Whatever I eat, I can't taste anything.
It's problematic considering I'm a food critic.
The missus is a bad cook, you see.
So I walked around, looking
for delicious food to eat...
Before I knew it, I came to be
called a food critic.
But I guess the wife's bad cooking
is the tastiest after all.
I bought tissues yesterday...
Oh! I forgot the nail trimmer.
I'll bring it tomorrow.
Say, there's a tree outside the window, right?
It feels like by the time all the leaves
have fallen, I'll be dead by then.
Don't say such nonsensical things.
Just kidding. Wanted to say such things
if I get to be hospitalized.
Come on now.
I've become scared somehow.
After you get discharged,
let's go out and eat something good.
Let's go to a stylish trattoria in Azabu.
They even have customers coming from Sicily.
Am I gonna be discharged?
The doctor too have said so.
But...
Is there anything you want?
Say whatever whim you like.
Well... there's a song I want to hear.
There's none?
None.
Sorry but it's out of print.
["Don't Say Anything"
Words and Music: Tachibana Taizo]
~Each time I'm nestled in your arms~
~I can hear the sound of your heart~
~Wo--...
Excuse me.
Please take your time.
Ah, oww...
Sorry! Are you okay?
Ka-Kashima-san...?
But... why were you at a karaoke place?
Actually, you see...
...I haven't seen myself sing.
As long as Taicchan watched me sing,
that was enough for me.
But when I saw myself in the videos,
is that really me?
I was like "So that's how I sang".
And then stuff like the heat of the spotlight...
...the thickness of the microphone,
I suddenly remembered a lot of things.
So then did you sing?
Along with your old self.
No.
You're not gonna sing anymore?
It's true that people who wish
to hear me sing are gone.
You know.... my wife
is in the hospital.
She's a bit younger than me...
I intend to take care of her but...
At any rate, I wanted to do something for her...
...but I can't do anything.
Just the other day...
...she told me she wants to hear a song.
She said she wants to hear
Kashima Misao's "Don't Say Anything".
I didn't know that she has a favorite song.
No, not just that. There might be many
other things I wasn't aware of.
Misao-san, please...
Could you sing "Don't Say Anything" once again...
For my wife.
I'm sorry but I can't.
I know I am being rude
by begging but...
She wishes to hear it.
I can't.
But why?
It's not okay! Telling me to sing
in order to encourage your wife.
You see, I promised in front
of Taicchan's coffin...
"I'm not gonna sing for people anymore!"
I'm sorry.
What for?
Well, apparently, CDs of the song
are out of print.
I knew.
I knew that what I said was a whim.
Don't cry.
I've no reason to cry.
Welcome.
Master, can you reserve the place for me
on the 17th? Are those hours okay with you?
Sure but what's up?
My wife's discharge had been decided.
And we're gonna celebrate a bit.
Glad to hear it. Congratulations.
Yeah well. From here on...
I'll leave it to you then.
Here you go.
You know, Master. I don't cry anymore
when I eat menchi.
Yeah.
I feel troubled each time you cry.
Suppose so.
Misao-san. You still don't want to sing?
When Taicchan was dying...
I was singing love songs on stage.
If I gave up singing and became
an ordinary woman much earlier...
...I wonder if I could have
been a better wife to him?
I wonder if Taicchan loved you more for being
a singer than an ordinary woman.
I came after hearing
from Master of "Meshi-ya".
Uh... Eh?
Oh... Kashima-san?
I thought it's better to speak
to you directly.
I'm really sorry that I can't sing.
Don't be. It's I who should apologize.
Asking my husband for
something that can't be done.
But because that person did a silly thing...
I got to meet you.
Thank you for coming.
Misao-san.
If you ever sing again...
...instead for others,
please sing for yourself.
You didn't tell me words like
you loved me but...
Your songs were your
love letters to me, right?
I got plenty of love letters from you.
But I feel scared and lonely...
I can't bring myself to "reread" them.
So unfair. When I let myself
loved you so much...
...you died on me.
You're so unfair.
That day, after considering the physical
condition of Toyama's wife...
...I decided to open the shop
as early as possible.
- It's delicious! Yum!
- Is that good?
- You want something?
- It's good. Thanks.
- Gimme some daikon.
- Daikon? - Oh, daikon! Here...
Well... it's time for the song.
Yes! We've been waiting!
A once-in-lifetime love.
A love that endures.
To be sung by a 3 star-voice...
...please listen to "Don't Say anything".
~Each time I'm nestled in your arms...~
~I can hear the sound of your heart~
~Words are not always enough~
~You can't convey everything~
~That is why, you've always
been the way you are~
~Quiet and shy~
~I like that about you~
~Whisper in my ear~
~The song of love~
~It's fine, it's okay~
~Don't say anything~
Thank you for listening!
That was nice.
Master, give me menchi!
Sure thing.
Seems these two people
have brought Misao-san back to life.
The percentage of meat is around
70% beef and 30% pork.
Use plenty of coarse panko (breadcrumbs).
Yeah, yeah.
This is nerve-racking.
To avoid splattering the oil,
gently put it in...
What's the temperature of the oil?
Huh? I dunno.
Ah! The menchi's gonna explode.
Ah, oww! Hot!
~Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo~
*Even if it's laughing or mad*
~Itoshikute shikatanakatta yo~
*I adore your face, can't be helped*
~Kimi no koto ga sukida yo~
*I love you*
~Korekara mo zutto kimi o dakishimetai~
*I want to hold you in my arms now and forever*
~Kimi o tsuyoku dakishimetai~
*I want to hold you tightly in my arms*
Original work:
"Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
'Master'
KOBAYASHI KAORU
'Kashina Misao' - MIHO JUN
'Toyama' - IWAMATSU RYO
'Kyoko' - WATANABE MAKIKO
'Chuu-san' - FUWA MANSAKU
'Rumi' - KOBAYASHI ASAKO
'Miki' - SUDO RISA
Screenplay:
MUKAI KOSUKE
Director:
MATSUOKA JOJI
This drama is fictional