Opening Song
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
STARRING
Kobayashi Kaoru
Sudo Risa
Kobayashi Asako
Yoshimoto Naoko
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Produced by Oikawa Takuro
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
and people make their way home,
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
my own day begins.
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
Max. three drinks per customer
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
My menu is all there.
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
The possibility of getting served anything else...
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
The possibility of getting served anything else...
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
as long as it's possible,
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
my business model.
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
I am open from midnight to seven of the morning after.
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
How is business doing?!
Well enough, I'd say.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
Midnight Restaurant
(*Rice with tea and toppings)
Episode 3
Ochazuke*
- Thanks for that.
- Thanks.
Master... More natto*.
(*fermented soy beans)
Coming.
You know, Master?
These days you
don't seem to come by.
Ahh... Is that right?
Next time, I'll come.
You said the
same exact thing last time.
Sorry.
This time, I mean it.
Should I believe that?
Adults are bad, aren't they?
- Her name is Jun-chan.
- Like Master would have the time...
(*Character from a famous manga
by Yamato Waki)
She is a new-half (transgender) running
a gay-bar called Murasaki no Ue*.
Sharing her partner
Yoshida-kun's love for natto,
the two started
dating because of that.
By the way...
You'll stay over tonight, right?
Ahh... Sorry.
I have a meeting early in the morning.
Uh?! Even if you
have one, it's okay!
Just stay!
Stop pushing it...
Come on.
All right.
As you wish.
Awesome!
Since the joys of the
palate transcend gender...
you really never know.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Anyhow...
Let's leave Jun-chan's story at that.
Come on in!
Our protagonists tonight
are these three ladies.
Ume.
- Salmon.
- Tarako.
Coming.
They are known here...
as the "Ochazuke Sisters."
Here you go, ume is ready.
Bon apetit!
Yukari... Did she really
want marriage that bad?
Maybe she had enough of her job?!
He's eight years older,
for God's sake!
- Have you seen his hairline?
- Right...
(*middle-aged man)
Already oyaji* material, all right.
If I really must tie the knot,
it'll only be with
someone ten years younger.
Right?!
They must be back
from the wedding party.
Quite a sight, isn't?
Grown ass women eating ochazuke,
bloated mug and all.
They'll hear you!
The hell I care?
Thanks for that.
- Tarako is the best.
- Ume is number one!
- Salmon is the way!
The ume's unique delicacy...
The perfect harmony of salmon and rice...
Tarako is no joke, either.
It's ochazuke, all right!
Right?!
On that note, wasn't
today's menu just a mess?
It was horrible.
They serve you those
tiny Hors d'oeuvre...
- It didn't even feel like eating.
- Right.
We sure packed those envelopes,
and look at what we get.
This is why weddings are the worst.
Right?!
Still, you know...
Yukari sure was pretty.
Yeah.
I've never seen
anyone so happy before.
So she indeed must be happy?!
She has to be...
Of course she is.
Next time.
Should we go to an
omiai (marriage meeting) party?
- Omiai party?
- Yeah.
This colleague of mine
has gone to a few already.
So what kind of people you meet?
Well...
But, I hear that these days
you can meet a lot of younger men.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Omiai party...
You two!
Have you listened to what kind
of nonsense you're prattling about?
Omiai party?!
The hell is that?
How can you compromise so cheaply?
- Still...
- Listen.
We pursue true love!
The great romances
you see on the big screen!
How can you just give up now?
I... guess so?!
Sure.
Pretty Woman!
Forever seeking the true romance!
Right!
(*short for Kekkon
katsudo, seeking marriage)
- Konkatsu*?!
- The hell with that!
- Omiai?
- Forget about it.
We accept no compromise.
True romance!
Our Prince Charming
is out there for sure!
Right?!
Master.
Another serving of ume.
- Salmon!
- Tarako.
Coming.
Same time and same company,
they drop by, and then...
Ume.
- Salmon.
- Tarako.
Enjoying their ochazuke,
they always talk about men.
- So we drank all night together.
- Really?
Aren't those two a
little on the cute side?
Cute.
Go have a word with them.
Give it a rest.
Only a cheapskate would
come to a place like this.
Guess so?!
Sorry.
It was about....
three months later?
Ume.
Salmon.
Ohh?!
How about the other,
the one always ordering Tarako?
Said her mother is sick,
so she had to go to
Kyushu and tend to her.
I see.
Not just that, I'm afraid.
Uh?!
Rumi...
The brat's going there
for an omiai as well!
Say what?!
Not to mention,
with someone ten years older.
Uh?!
Yeah!
Omiai...
in Kyushu?!
Yeah.
My mom is sick,
so I want to reassure her quickly.
- Really?!
- Yeah.
I just want to get married.
Because I'm the only child.
Really?!
Ha ha ha...
Best wishes!
Traitor!
I haven't contacted you since then.
Really.
That brat...
She's using her mother as an excuse,
but she was just feeling lonely.
Hmph! The same one who
always despised older men?!
It's a compromise, all right.
The brat gave up on true romance.
Ahhh... Drives me crazy!
She's done with us.
I'm never calling her again!
It's betrayal.
As vile as betrayals can get!
Master...
- Where is our ochazuke?
- Let's get moving!
I certainly feel what you're saying,
but don't take it all out on me.
The two remained
on good terms for a while.
When our "Ume Sister" Miki-chan
was hospitalized for ob-gyn matters...
Wow... Really?!
Seems like "Salmon Sister" Kana-chan
was always by her side.
I wanted to have this so much!
- Congrats on your recovery.
- Thanks!
All thanks to you.
I'm just glad you got better.
Hope I can keep counting on you.
Same goes for me.
From here on in,
Kana, you're
the only one for me!
Miki...
- Konkatsu?!
- The hell with it.
- Omiai?!
- Gimme a break.
No compromise.
For sure.
Pure love is in the air.
Right?!
People say that
women can't be friends,
but I always thought it
wasn't the case for these two.
Yet...
By the way, Master.
Are the Ochazuke Sisters
coming by, these days?
Now that I think about it,
I haven't seen them
in quite a while?!
- Told you.
- Yeah.
Uh?!
This other day...
They made a scene at my bar.
Seems like Salmon Sister is
going out with Ume Sister's ex.
Uh?!
According to her,
seems like the two...
had been frequenting
her bar pretty often.
Break it up with Mitsuhiko,
or you'll regret it.
Like you care?
Just let me be.
Of course I care.
What are you, jealous?
Uh?!
You're just jealous, it's obvious.
The hell are you prattling about?
Why would I?
Why would you...
Listen, why should
I ever be jealous?
Let me think...
Enough with that.
I'm just telling you for your sake.
And why don't you
mind your own business?
As if you were the
one who dumped him first...
What is this?
Makes you feel uneasy, I bet?
Seeing me experience true love.
The hell are you doing?
Let go!
What are you doing?
Excuse me... Ladies...
Don't do this... Don't!
Please stop.
You fucker!
What the hell are you doing?
Shut the fuck up,
you sons of bitches!
So there's no friendship
between women, indeed.
None.
As long as men continue to exist.
That's sad to hear.
"The kiddo felt dizzy,
but desperately kept hanging on."
"This waltz is no
laughing matter, either."
"So she pranced around the
kitchen as if she went batty,"
"making the cupboard shake
left and right, and making a mess."
Any hobbies?
"making the cupboard shake
left and right, and making a mess."
I do some ballroom dancing,
every now and then.
"making the cupboard shake
left and right, and making a mess."
I do some ballroom dancing,
every now and then.
"An ice cold stare was
stamped on her mother's face"
Is... that so?!
"An ice cold stare was
stamped on her mother's face"
Yes.
"An ice cold stare was
stamped on her mother's face"
If you look back at the
history of ballroom dancing,
you'll inevitably go
back to its roots in waltz.
There's this theory that it
all started in the Provence area,
with a dance called "volt."
Our Prince Charming is out there!
Right?!
"You brought me to bed,"
"as I was still hanging onto you,"
"while dancing the waltz."
Tastes like crap.
Come on in.
Ume.
Coming.
In the end,
finally decimated to one,
our Ochazuke Sisters.
You know, at this age.
How should I put it.
You kind of start obsessing
over curious little things.
Yeah...
How should I put it...
I thought long and hard about it,
but why do we do that?
Even though we know that...
we won't gain anything
out of that anyhow.
I shouldn't really
be the one talking about this,
but wouldn't making
things simpler solve it?
Like this ochazuke.
There's no need to
make things so complicated.
You like what you like.
Shouldn't that be enough?
Bon apetit.
It's so damn salty!
Are you losing your touch?
Might very well be the case.
Every now and then,
why don't you try
another kind of ochazuke?
On the house.
Like salmon...
or tarako, for instance.
I'll have salmon.
Coming!
Come on in.
Ume ochazuke.
Coming.
I broke up.
I couldn't take him anymore.
What did I tell you?
Here you go.
Ume... and salmon.
Ume's not bad?!
Salmon, too.
Sorry about everything.
Forget about it.
I should...
say the same.
It's just that...
I felt frustrated.
By the way...
Seems like Rumi
is coming back to Tokyo.
Uh?! Really?
Guess her mother recovered...
Or the omiai didn't
go according to plans.
Guess so.
See? You take the easy way out,
and look at what happens.
If it's marriage,
you need them younger.
Right.
You need to experience
that passionate, ardent romance.
Right?!
Tarako!
Tell me, how was the omiai?
- The what?
- Don't act all coy.
Looks like our Ochazuke Sisters...
are back in town.
- What are you prattling about?
- "What are you prattling about?"
~ to be continued ~
Here's your one
point advice for ochazuke.
Only pour the tea or broth
moments before you serve.
Or the rice will get all bloated.
As for the rest,
whichever toppings you prefer.
It's so tasty yet so simple to make,
ochazuke is really great.
Right?!
So... Good night everyone!