~ Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ~
*Misty white breaths you exhale*
~ Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte ~
*Slowly blown by the wind now*
~ Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni ~
*Into the clouds in the sky*
~ Sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku ~
*Gradually fading away*
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above in the sky*
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
At the end of the day...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
...when people are rushing to get home...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
...when people are rushing to get home...
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
...that's when my day starts.
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
This is my only menu.
(tonjiru, beer, sake, shochu)
If a customer wants something else...
...I'll say "I'll make it if I can."
That is my business policy.
(Store Sign: 'Meshi-ya')
If you're wondering if I ever get customers...
...I do get quite a number.
SHINYA SHOKUDO
(The Late Night Diner)
=Season 2=
Some say that...
...compared to women who are
sensitive to heat (cold-blooded)...
...women who are sensitive to cold weather
(warm-blooded) are more endearing.
Good evening.
This woman falls into the latter category.
Are you alright, Hitomi-chan?
- So cold! I'd like to order nabeyaki udon please.
- That one again?
It's even an added bonus
if the woman is pretty.
- Master, beer please.
- Comin right up.
Here.. thanks for waiting.
Hey, Master, can you also try
talking some sense into this girl?
After supporting her boyfriend all this time,
she ended up getting dumped.
You knew that lazy bum was just using you.
Why did you have to buy
clothes for that younger guy?
You coulda bought a coat for yourself.... And you
wouldn't go around complaining about the cold.
I'm afraid this is a different kind of cold.
You don't get to spend money for yourself.
Instead you just let someone else use it.
In short, you always chase after
penniless young guys.
What's wrong with liking younger guys?
Leave me be...
After all, it IS my money.
- Yeah, it's okay, right?
- That's right, to each his own.
- Now... See?
- If you're gonna be this stubborn about it...
...you'll feel even more frustrated.
I wasn't being stubborn.
- She's really like this.
- Yeah.
Over here.
Soon, Hitomi-chan...
...was able to find a new man again...
It's unusual since it happens to be an older man.
C'mon.
Nah, it's more than unusual, I should say.
Welcome.
Master.
Can we have "hiyashi chuuka" (cold noodles)?
Cold noodles?
Hashimoto-san would like to have some.
Can you make it?
Well, I guess...
...Sure.
Here you go.
It's delicious.
Thank you.
Say, can I have a bite?
Mmm, it's good.
I feel cold just by watching.
Yeah.
Are you alright?
The radish tastes so good.
Radish?
Ah, so good.
"We met in a pet store, you see."
- Cute!
- So cute.
Here, here, boy..
That's right, come here, you.
Stay now, stay.
"Soon, we started chatting in front of a puppy."
I already sold it.
"Later, the two of us went out
and got some drinks."
- Cheers.
"Then he said, he liked to eat cold noodles."
So it was on that day?
There weren't any other diner selling cold
noodles in this winter season, right?
Ah, I remember before...
Something from jazz musician,
Yamashita Yosuke...
He couldn't understand why we
don't eat cold noodles in winter.
So he set up a Japanese association
for fans of cold noodles.
Its nickname was "Zenchuurei" for short...
No, no... I think it was "Zenreichuu."
Man, those were the days.
A 'cold-blooded man' and a
'warm-blooded woman'...
...is not exactly compatible, right?
A younger guy isn't any better, is it?
I did later notice it...
The warmth that exudes from an older man.
I was very young when my father passed away.
How should I say it...
it somehow makes me think of the past.
Well, it's better than supporting a younger guy.
- What does he do anyway?
- He's a live-in book binder.
Before his days-off come,
he gets to stay overnight at my place.
So I wouldn't be needing an electric
blanket during the weekends.
Oh, really.
So then, on weekends...
Welcome.
- It's delicious, right?
- Yeah.
- Can I have your ham?
- Sure.
- Good?
- Yum!
People rush home at the end of the day.
But if you also feel something's left unfinished...
...on some nights, you might
want to make a detour.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
Master.
I brought along an important person.
Come in, come in.
He's Inuzuka Heihachi-san.
He's a well-known, legendary police officer.
They call him "The Tenacious Inuzuka."
Right now, they're doing a special feature on
him for Japan Weekly magazine.
- He has been getting a lot of interviews.
- Hey, don't call me a legend.
I'm still on active duty.
Even though, I'll reach my retirement
age in a week's time.
- Anyway, hot sake, please.
- Comin right up.
Inuzuka-san, even though this is only
what's written on the menu...
...in most cases, Master can make
anything that you wish to order.
Interesting, eh?
Look, she's eating those cold noodles.
Obviously her taste got affected by
a 'cold-blooded man...'
That woman's heart sure got tinkered with.
Cold noodles reminds me of something...
A fugitive I had been searching before...
He managed to elude me.
Even you encountered such a thing, huh?
It was more than just a thing...
It's something that I had regretted.
I have desperately tried to
draw out information about him...
Curiously enough...
Different people...
...gave impressions of him...
...that are not the same.
Some say he's a kind person.
Others said he was a rough guy
Yet everyone...
...agrees on one thing about him.
And that is, he really likes to eat cold noodles.
So, like an idiot...
...I staked out Chinese eateries in Tokyo...
Day in and day out.
...And I only ate cold noodles, too.
It was an obsession, eh?
I was just stupid.
Incidentally, Inuzuka-san...
...how old would the criminal be now?
This year marks the 20th year
since he escaped...
So that makes him 50 by now.
Finally, they abolished the statute of limitations*...
(*in 2010 = for murder and other crimes)
And yet, I'm now facing retirement.
Life is really lousy, eh?
What's the profile like...
of that guy?
They said he looks modest.
I can't remember what he looks like...
But basing it on the description
from those people...
...it's quite difficult.
Oh, I remember...
He had here between the brows...
A Buddha mole!
Yeah, but I dunno if it's a mole or a wart though.
Say... when's the next time you'll meet
with your boyfriend?
What're you saying?
Just because he happens to like cold noodles....
Then you mean somehow all the
people in Japan...
... who like cold noodles
should be questioned?
No, but don't you think
there's something about it?
What an idiot.
Sorry, okay?
Didn't mean to upset you.
It's an occupational disease... Suspecting a
person immediately just because of a little thing.
I apologize.
- I'm done.
- Thanks!
Inuzuka-san.
Here you go.
Hitomi-chan.
Sorry, did you wait?
No, let's go.
Yes, sir. They just left the store.
- Roger.
- Are we gonna arrest him?
No, we have to wait and see.
Why? We might miss this chance.
Keep quiet, will you? We can't make
a move til Inuzuka-san says so.
Say, Hashimoto-san.
You like dogs, right?
Have you ever bought one?
It's not allowed at my company where I stay in.
Besides, if I get a dog...
I feel I may not be able
to get out of that place.
Is there something wrong?
You know...
It doesn't matter to me
what happened to you in the past.
Right now, I know that I like you.
That's why...
...if you want to go to a
different place, then let's go.
I'll go anywhere with you.
I see.
Let's go out for a bit.
No, no.
Please leave...
"Meshi"-ya is my diner.
It's not a place to do your investigation.
It's too annoying.
But Master, don't be like that--
We're sorry.
Let's do what Master says.
Hey...What's wrong?
Why aren't you saying anything?
If you don't tell me, how will
I be able to know you?
What kind of a person you are.
What you are thinking.
I wanted to forgive her...
My wife who went off with another man...
I did really love her.
I even agreed to a divorce...
But then when I saw that man.
I couldn't hold back.
I found myself
shouting angrily at him.
We grabbed at each other
and my mind just went blank.
I frantically pushed him away hard
and then ran out of the store.
The next day...
...newspapers reported that he was dead.
I was afraid and so I ran away.
Then a year ago...
I don't know why...
...but I came back to this town.
Somehow maybe, I think I
just wanted this to end.
Hashimoto-san, let's run away together?
It couldn't be helped, okay?
It wasn't your fault.
No more... How about if we go there now?
That diner, I mean.
From now on, I'll be the one to make
you cold noodles everyday.
But...
Hitomi-chan's cooking is hard to eat.
What're you saying?
Okay then, for the last time,
let's go and eat there.
Afterwards, we'll leave this town.
Let's make a run for it.
C'mon, let's go!
Saruhashi.
As always, you still like cold noodles, don't you?
Can I ask...
for one last favor?
Welcome.
Master, cold noodles please...
for two.
Comin right up.
Here you go.
Hitomi-chan, I'm sorry.
And thank you.
(...Under a false name, he befriended a woman..)
(The last big case of the legendary cop...
...His only clue was 'cold noodles...')
One shouldn't really eat cold noodles
during the dead of winter, eh?
Making omelette into
thread-like pieces is not easy.
First, make sure the egg is fully scrambled
with all the proteins broken up.
Cook the omelette on low fire.
Wait patiently for the edges to coagulate.
Afterwards, cut all the ingredients neatly.
Rinse the noodles to take out the starch...
...by dipping it firmly in iced water.
Finally drain it, then remember to arrange the
ingredients neatly to make it more delicious.
Here you go.
So then, good night.
~ Yarusenai yuhi yori ~
*More than the dreary sunset*
To be continued
~ Shinji reru asahi o mitai ~
*Rather see the sunrise to believe*
KOBAYASHI Kaoru as 'Master'
~ Dakara sukoshi yume o mi sasete ~
*Let me dream a little*
SAKAI Wakana as 'Hitomi'
ASHIKAWA Makoto as 'Hashimoto/Saruhashi'
~ Ashita e mukau tame ~
*So I can go on tomorrow*
SHIOMI Sansei as 'Inuzuka Heihachi'
UNO Shohei as 'Komichi'
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
MATSUO Satoru as 'Goro'
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Music: SATOU Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by SUZUKI Tsunekichi
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Food Stylist: IIJIMA Nami
Based on the manga by: ABE Yaro
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
Screenplay: MUKAI Kosuke
Directed by: KOBAYASHI Shotaro
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*