KOBAYASHI KAORU
AWATA URARA
TSUJI KAORI
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
MAJIMA HIDEKAZU
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
KOBAYASHI ASAKO / YOSHIMOTO NAHOKO
KIYOBUMI KANEKO / UNO SHOHEI
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
HAJIZUME RYU / HARADA CHIEKO / SUZUKI TATSUYA
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
...That's when my day starts.
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne
Always seems like a thing of the past
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
[MESHIYA]
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
"Late Night Diner"
EP 5: "BEAN VERMICELLI SALAD..."
It's been raining since nightfall.
I wonder if it's better to carry an umbrella
or maybe better off without it... in a harusame*...
(*"Spring rain", also "bean starch vermicelli noodles")
- This is the place.
- Oh, okay...
Good evening.
Welcome.
Is it still raining?
Yeah. We didn't bring umbrellas though.
Beer for now please.
Sure thing.
- Is it okay?
- Yeah.
If you say what you want to eat,
most of the time, this shop can make it so...
...ask away.
- Really?
Wonder what to order...
Anyway, I was shocked.
Yama-chan's head had become like that...
- To think I had a crush on him a long time ago.
- 'Cause Yama-chan seemed to had it tough.
With all the restructuring and the divorce...
I see, so with all the troubles,
he lost all of his hair.
Here you go.
Master, this is my elementary school classmate, Sayuri.
She's a teacher now in our alma mater.
Hello.
Did you have an class reunion today?
No. Our reunion is at the
end of the month but...
We both became the organizers
and we just came from the meeting today.
Our class buried a time capsule
at the time of our graduation...
And we're gonna dig it up after 25 years
so the preparations is already getting hard.
Really... 25 years ....
Yeah.
Speaking of time capsules,
the one that's famous is...
...the one that's buried in Osaka Castle Park
during the Expo 1970 in Osaka.
They'll dig it up in the year 6970,
a whopping 5000 years after.
When I was also in elementary school...
...our class buried one, too.
So what happened to it?
When we dug it up after 10 years,
there was water inside, and got stained...
The letters were indecipherable,
we couldn't read them anymore.
Really, can such a thing happen?
The capsule's lid wasn't closed properly.
It's good that yours is going well...
As someone from the same generation,
I wish you good luck.
Same generation!?
What? You got a problem with that?
You graduated 25 years ago so...
Hey! Don't calculate it!
Hey Sayuri. Have you decided what to eat?
Yeah. Vermicelli salad.
Here, thanks for waiting.
I'm digging in.
- Delicious!
- Yeah.
Hey, speaking of vermicelli salad,
it's Shigacchi, right?
Didn't you use to get food
from someone else at lunchtime?
You remember the strange things, don't you?
I liked Yama-chan and
kept following him around.
Oh, Sayuri, who was your crush back then?
Tell me~.
Shigacchi.
You liked him?
The truth is I hated vermicelli salad.
But since I really liked Shiga-kun...
...I thought, I'll come to like it, too, I guess.
When I ate it every day...
I came to love it before I realized it.
I see. Then, it would be great
if Shigacchi comes to the reunion, huh.
Yeah.
Have you reached it?
I don't know. Ah~ I can't anymore. Take over.
- Ah~ so dirty...
- It's okay... You can do it...
We'll be waiting, do your best.
Say, Yama-chan. Didn't you see Sayuri?
Huh? I haven't seen her...
she's didn't come?
I can't even contact her phone.
It's a mystery, isn't it?
It is a wonder...
Are you perhaps Tajima?
Shigacchi?
Oh, we found it!
Oh, um... I've completely mistaken you
for Miho-san's husband. I'm so sorry.
I'm Shiga, her elementary school classmate.
Ah. The rumored Shigacchi-san...
- What?
- Uh, so here's my son, Taichi.
I'm divorced and single right now.
Nice to meet you, I'm Tajima Taichi.
Thank you for being friends
with my mother.
You have such a good kid.
There's been a lot of times when I'm not around
because of work, so it just happened naturally.
- And you come back home drunk, right?
- Hey now...
- You promised not to say that...
- Here.
Large serving of Vermicelli salad...
This one's a special kid's meal.
- Thank you.
- Thanks for waiting.
We're digging in.
Hot? Is it good?
- I'm glad.
- Mm, good.
Where's Sayuri-san today?
She's been hospitalized for appendicitis.
- Plus, today was the class reunion.
- Then, I feel sorry for her.
So we went and paid her a visit today.
Long time no see.
Been a long time...
Oh, dear. Pardon my appearance...
What are you saying...
you're sick, of course!
- Here, for you.
- Oh, thank you.
Taichi-kun also came, huh.
- Yes. This too is for you.
- What's this?
It's your letter and music box
inside the time capsule.
This brings back memories!
Miho, do you remember this?
I sure did! Hey, what's written in the letter?
Let me read it.
No way! I will read it later by myself.
How stingy.
Even though we took pains to
bring it to her... right?
She's right. Why don't you read
and let them hear it?
Mom, not you too...
Come, please replace these flowers.
Sure, sure...
Ma'am, I'll do it...
No, no... you took time to come here so...
Hey Sayuri.
Shigacchi said he's still single.
It's good news, right?
Komatsu hasn't changed at all, huh?
I was surprised.
She's still the same old sweet Sayuri...
Her dad died early on...
...she and her mom had been
living together all this time so...
It seems she can't leave
her mother on her own.
Hmm... You know her pretty well huh.
Since we've come a long way.
Even when I was worried about
giving birth for the first time...
When I was also depressed at the time
I decided to get a divorce...
...it was Sayuri who always supported me.
Well then, when Komatsu is discharged from
the hospital, let's have a celebration.
- Let the three of us get together again.
- Yeah, let's do that.
Master, make sure to prepare
lots of vermicelli salad, okay?
Sure thing.
Well, good night.
We enjoyed the food.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Thanks, Master!
- He's sleeping soundly.
- He is. Is he heavy?
- No. I'm okay.
- Really? Thank you.
- Congratulations on your discharge!
- Thank you.
- Okay. Well then, let's toast.
- Here, thanks for waiting.
- Cheers!
Congratulations. I'm happy for you.
Thank you so much.
But still I wasn't able
to go to the class reunion.
After going through the trouble
of organizing it and yet...
Stop complaining. Are you
dissatisfied with just me and Shigacchi?
I'm not saying that...
But I wondered if everyone else
is doing fine...
Yeah... but 25 years have truly passed...
Everyone has changed. Gotten married
and having families, especially the guys...
Shiga-kun, you haven't changed at all.
Neither have you.
But with Tajima...
When I first saw you, I hardly recognized you.
Hang on, what do you mean?
- That I've become more like an Auntie?
- No, no. I'm not saying that...
It's okay. 'Cause y'see,
your insides haven't changed.
- Huh?
- What does that mean?
You're scary when you get angry.
That doesn't make me happy at all!
Hey... He's a good guy, isn't he? Shigacchi.
Yeah.
Go and invite him out...
I can't do such a thing so suddenly.
- I just met him the other day.
- What are you saying...
You met him 25 years ago.
Yeah but it's...
Oh, but it's okay 'cause
you're both single.
Even you...
For me, my son is enough.
After all, my son's quite a looker, isn't he?
He IS a cutie...
Huh? What is it?
What are you guys talking about?
Secret.
Okay now. We've arrived.
Put her down on the sofa.
Okay now... Careful...
We're here. Here you go.
Ah~ goodness.
It's been a long time...
...since Miho has been this far gone.
She was so glad when you got better.
She said the other day, you have always
supported her when things were difficult.
I was only by her side.
Miho overcame her own problems herself...
Because she's a strong person.
Is it not perhaps that she has
unexpectedly become reliant on you?
- What?
- It's gotta be, just look at her...
...she can't sleep soundly at all.
Can't be helped... indeed...
Sensei, goodbye!
Okay, goodbye.
Be careful on your way home.
We will.
(Note: She's humming "Wakare no Kyoku" or
"Song of Parting" = Chopin's "Étude Op. 10, No. 3")
Sayuri-sensei.
Sayuri-san, long time no see.
Good evening.
Welcome. Are you alone today?
Yes. Bean vermicelli salad and beer please.
Sure thing.
I've heard...
you were hospitalized for appendicitis?
Too bad about the reunion.
Yeah...
The other day... Miho-san brought her
son along and that classmate...
...uh... Shigacchi?
- The vermicelli salad guy?
- That's the one.
I had mistaken him for Miho-san's husband...
I was so embarrassed.
That will... likely become true.
Oh my gosh...
Many things have changed
...but it still brings back memories.
My seat was here.
Mine was here.
I remember it quite well...
Even though 25 years have passed.
Shiga-kun's seat was over there.
I was always watching
Shiga-kun from here.
Us sitting here... reminds me of
many things from those days...
Sayuri, I'm sorry.
What's the matter? All of a sudden...
Shiga-kun told me he loves me...
What?
He asked me to go out with him
with the premise of marriage.
What do you mean...?
At first, I rejected him because
I know how you feel about him.
But you know...
I've done some thinking...
about him, and Taichi too...
When I take a look in the mirror,
and really face it...
I think to myself,
"Ah... I like him, too."
Enough! I don't want to hear it!
Please listen, Sayuri...
Don't say things as you please!
I'm sorry.
But... I don't want to lie
to my own feelings.
Then...
what about my feelings!
It's ALWAYS like this with you.
When you come to talk to me,
you already have your answer.
You just want to affirm yourself!
Even at the time of your first marriage...
I told you to think about it
carefully before marrying, right?
And yet you had your own answer after all...
I can't help it! I can't live
any other way than that.
If that's the case...!
...What do you need me for?
I had been admiring you since the old days.
You're able to pull yourself together...
Even if you fail, you're always positive...
I thought it would be great
if I too become like you..
But you know...
I can not become strong like you.
Thanks for waiting.
The letter that I placed in the time capsule...
I wrote, "I want to marry
the person I love..."
"...and make him vermicelli salad."
Can't believe I wrote such a thing...
I had completely forgotten about it.
I also placed this music box along
with the letter but...
Oh... It's "Song of Parting".
Miho gave this to me for my birthday.
Because I liked this song.
It's the perfect song for me now.
What a laugh, huh?
That's right.
Please forget, and laugh about it.
You're right!
Okay! Today, I'm all about eating!
I'm digging in.
Master, the bean vermicelli salad...
...is super delicious.
Really.
Thank you.
It's okay...
You don't have to force
yourself to laugh.
Perhaps tonight's rain is
the rain of Sayuri-san's tears.
Good morning.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I kind of cried like an idiot.
It doesn't matter.
I thought to bring this and to throw it away.
You're gonna throw it?
Hello...
"Miho..."
"Be happy, okay?"
And... I'll be stronger.
So...
Be happy, okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
The season for harusame* is already finished.
(Again, double meaning for "spring rain"
and "vermicelli")
Yeah.
Well then...
After boiling, wash the cellophane noodles
with running water...
Drain it well.
Add your choice of ingredients
like cucumber, ham and cloud ear mushrooms.
To give the dressing a rich flavor,
add green onion oil.
It will also add depth to the taste.
- Thanks for waiting.
- Ah, here it is!
Master, macaroni salad for me.
Sure thing.
- Eh? - Eh?
- Have a good night!
Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo
Even if it's laughing or mad
'Master'- KOBAYASHI KAORU
Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo
Even if it's laughing or mad
'Komatsu Sayuri' - AWATA URARA
'Tajima Miho' - TSUJI KAORI
Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo
Even if it's laughing or mad
'Komatsu Sayuri' - AWATA URARA
'Tajima Miho' - TSUJI KAORI
Itoshikute shikatanakatta yo
I adore your face, can't be helped
'Shiga' - MAJIMA HIDEKAZU
Itoshikute shikatanakatta yo
I adore your face, can't be helped
'Shiga' - MAJIMA HIDEKAZU
Kimi no koto ga sukida yo
I love you
'Kanemoto' - KIYOBUMI KANEKO
'Komichi' - UNO SHOHEI
Kimi no koto ga sukida yo
I love you
'Kanemoto' - KIYOBUMI KANEKO
'Komichi' - UNO SHOHEI
Korekara mo zutto kimi o dakishimetai
I want to hold you in my arms now and forever
'Tajima Taichi' - HAJIZUME RYU
'Sayuri's mother' - HARADA CHIEKO
Korekara mo zutto kimi o dakishimetai
I want to hold you in my arms now and forever
Original work: "Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
Korekara mo zutto kimi o dakishimetai
I want to hold you in my arms now and forever
Screenplay: KOJIMA KENSAKU
Korekara mo zutto kimi o dakishimetai
I want to hold you in my arms now and forever
Screenplay: KOJIMA KENSAKU
Kimi o tsuyoku dakishimetai
I want to hold you tightly in my arms
Planning: ENDO HITOSHI / SHIBANO MASAYUKI
Kimi o tsuyoku dakishimetai
I want to hold you tightly in my arms
Producers: TSUITSUI RYUHEI / OSANO TAMOTSU
ISHIZUKA SHOGO / TAKEZONO MOTO
Kimi o tsuyoku dakishimetai
I want to hold you tightly in my arms
OP Theme Song: "Omoiizu"
by SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI
Kimi o tsuyoku dakishimetai
I want to hold you tightly in my arms
Theme song: 'Yakimochi'
by TAKAHASHI YU (Warner Music Japan)
Kimi o tsuyoku dakishimetai
I want to hold you tightly in my arms
Art:
HARADA MITSUO
Director:
NOMOTO FUMIO
Planning:
AMUSE
MBS
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT
GEEK SITE
A 2014 production of:
AMUSE / SHOGAKUKAN / TOEI / KINOSHITA GROUP
GEEK PICTURES / MBS / RKB
This drama is fictional