Opening Song
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
STARRING
Kobayashi Kaoru
Tanaka Kei
Murakawa Eri
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Directed By Yamashita Nobuhiro
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
and people make their way home,
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
my own day begins.
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
Max. three drinks per customer
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
My menu is all there.
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
The possibility of getting served anything else...
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
The possibility of getting served anything else...
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
as long as it's possible,
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
my business model.
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
I am open from midnight to seven of the morning after.
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
How is business doing?!
Well enough, I'd say.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
Midnight Restaurant
Episode 7
Egg Sandwich
If you tell me anything you'd like,
I'll make it for you if possible.
I guess...
traditional tonjiru will do.
Coming.
Can I shoot a photo?
I want to post it on my blog.
Blog?!
It's a kind of diary
you write on your PC.
Have no problem with that,
but make sure you
don't promote this place.
That's weird.
Uh? Why?
Most people actually ask me
for a photo, to get some publicity.
Is that so?
Here you go.
(*TV actress)
I'm aspiring to become a talent*.
Although I'm probably busier
working part time at our family restaurant.
I see...
So that's why you blog...
If I can get even just
a little bit of publicity....
Seems like he'll be here soon.
Good morning.
Morning.
Can you make me an egg sandwich?
I also made you ones with
cucumber and ham.
Thank you.
If you'd like to, go ahead.
Uh?!
May I?
Thank you.
Is something on my face?
No...
Just seemed like you were enjoying it.
Are there any decent
men left out there?!
It was a disaster.
We should have just
remained at home watching TV.
Those ads were just a farce.
What could it be?
They went to, what is it,
an omiai party or something?
Here. Beer and macaroni salad.
Master.
Didn't one of them
go back to her hometown?
Looks like her
mother has gotten better.
Master!
- Ochazuke
Coming.
And I thought without one
they'd become a little more docile.
Did you?
You two over there.
Yes?
Don't just mumble
by yourselves, you men!
Dammit.
As if any of you
losers are any different.
Bragging as if
you're anything special.
Stop talking about
yourselves alone, will you?
All you can find at those meetings
are the leftovers, after all.
Losers, minions and nothing else.
Right?!
Look who's talking....
So, tell me,
what kind of man
would you like to date?
Someone who's
not a good for nothing,
who spares his words,
who has only eyes for me.
The type who might
be popular with women,
but can only love one.
Like Takakura Ken?
Right!
Also, he must make
over 10 million yen a year,
have a house with
a garden in Setagaya.
Also, no eldest sons!
Since you'd have
to look after his parents.
That's quite important...
Right?!
The hell is that?
Also, a villa abroad!
About a week later...
Egg sandwich, please.
Coming.
You know, that day?
I was contacted for a gravure shoot!
Although it was
just a throwaway gig.
But it seems like eating egg
sandwich here brings me luck.
It's just an egg sandwich.
That guy, the other day...
What does he do for a living?
He should be
here soon, so wait.
Uh? He's coming tonight?
Yeah.
Every night.
Morning.
Ah... Thank you for the
egg sandwich the other day!
Ahh... It's nothing.
If it's okay with you,
let me pay back the courtesy.
Thank you.
That kiddo...
is paying his college tuition
by delivering papers.
Looks like things aren't
going well for his family.
I see...
During holidays,
instead of delivering papers,
he brings me bread,
like the other day.
I should have given him
the whole plate, then.
He must be so hungry...
It's all right.
He said he always has
breakfast waiting for him at work.
They look good together,
don't they, Master?
Just seeing them
makes me feel elated.
What, have you
met them before?
The girl comes here around
the time when he delivers papers,
and then gives
him half her egg sandwich,
while he looks
embarrassed as he takes it.
That's so nice of her.
So what, you're always so piss drunk
you spend the whole night here?
Isn't it, Master?
Now that I think
about it, you're right.
So it's not "Midnight Restaurant,"
but the lovebirds' "Dawn Restaurant."
Although it's okay with me.
So he's on a scholarship...
You rarely see students working to pay
their college fees in this day and age.
He's quite something.
Do you even realize...
how hard that is?
Every day,
you wake up at three in
the morning when it's still dark,
and start delivering
papers a half hour later.
By the time you're done,
it's already half past six,
after which you wrap up things
at work, and head to school.
Good morning.
Then, you pay attention to your
lesson, fighting off the urge to sleep.
Once the lecture is done,
you go deliver the evening papers.
Even if your friends
call you out for a drink...
Nakajima,
let's have a drink.
Sorry... Have to go...
So you can't even make friends.
You complete deliveries
past six in the evening,
and without a minute to spare,
prepare the next day's
morning papers for delivery.
And then you have to study,
and the infernal loop starts again with
the morning papers after a little sleep.
It's hard... Living that life...
Kanemoto-san...
How come you know that so well?
Because I've experienced it firsthand.
Ohh... You can't really judge
a book by its cover, all right.
But after I learned this,
I failed at both.
Drinking is scary.
So.... That way...
Sure!
Sorry!
Ah... Don't worry about it!
I should feel sorry for keeping you
on the phone for so long at that hour.
Sorry.
So what is this thing
you couldn't tell me on the phone?
I was wondering what you think of me.
That...
I like you, Nakajima-kun.
- I....
- Excuse me!
Are you Aikawa Risa-san,
by any chance?
Yes.
It's her!
I'm a fan!
Ah... Thank you very much.
I'll keep supporting you!
Thank you.
Keep up the good work!
- We'll keep supporting you!
- Thank you.
- What is she doing here?
- Right? Totally awesome!
You still haven't answered me.
The worlds you and I live in...
are so different...
That girl, she's showing up on TV
pretty often these days, isn't she?
Seemed so.
There's no need to worry.
No matter how busy they are,
they'll end up together.
The world out there
isn't as easy as you think.
Here she starts again.
One is a up and coming talent,
the other a delivery boy.
It's not just a little difference.
They're of a different class altogether!
In this world of ours,
be it the Arisu's
downstream or midstream,
don't belittle life.
Hepburn and Gregory Peck
will break up in the end.
Why's that?
(*Rom-Com film starring
Audrey Hepburn and Gregory Peck)
You don't know Roman Holiday*?!
What an ignorant man!
But...
(*Rom-Com films)
The romance in Notting Hill* went well!
Pretty Woman*, too!
Haha! That's funny.
They don't even kiss, right?
That's right...
The voices of the two platonics
are not fulfilled.
The price has not been decided!
But...!
Your heart wil cry more than your body...
It's a loss if you are only aware of
yourself rather than your partner.
In general... In general...
What are you looking at?
About Scene 19...
Give it a look before we go.
"Nakajima here, how are things?
Sorry for the other day,
can we meet again..."
~ Exit? ~
~ Checking Incoming Messages ~
~ No Messages ~
~ Secret Late Night Meeting
Between Aikawa Risa and IT President ~
See? Just as we told you.
See? You can't trust women.
Losers in tears,
how miserable.
Thank you.
What are you
doing here,
at this hour?
Tomorrow the paper is not coming out.
Here... Let's drink the night away.
Women have always been
that kind of species, you know?
Drink, go ahead.
Thank you.
Listen.
What?
Will you let these two men
enjoy their drink together?
I'm not talking to you.
You know?
You're really pathetic.
It's obvious you'd let another
man steal her under your eyes!
If you truly
have any feelings for her,
get her back!
What is that pair hanging there
in the middle for, decoration?
~ Where are you? ~
~ I need to meet you ~
~ and have a word ~
~ Still at the studio ~
~ We need to talk, ~
~ I have something to say myself ~
Hey!
Good job!
So I hear, Risa and that
president got engaged?
What is it? Didn't she care
about her career even a bit?
Right.
Looks like they
were going out for real.
She was just starting
to get noticed, it's killing me.
Killing what...
Risa, let's go.
I have to work early in the morning,
so I need some sleep.
Congrats.
Thank you.
Want some egg sandwich?
Sure.
We shared this the very
first day we met, didn't we?
Yes.
Yes, I'll come in right now.
Thank you for that.
So... I'll get going.
Goodbye.
Master...
Yeah?
You might despise me for saying this,
but will they eventually break up?
When was it...
The other day,
she came here alone.
So...
That president fella
finally proposed to you.
Will you accept it?
I don't know anything about this president,
so I can only take that kiddo's side.
He's a decent guy.
I know.
I do know, but...
Whenever I'm with Nakajima-kun,
it doesn't feel like it used to be.
He said we live in different worlds,
and at first,
I thought I should have told him otherwise,
but I just couldn't say a thing.
Right when that happened,
I met this man.
I think he's a nice person,
but I don't like him
or anything of that sort.
That is why I talked to him
about Nakajima-kun as well.
What did he say?
To reflect until I can't take it anymore.
Think and keep thinking about it,
and if you still can't find an answer,
then it can't be helped.
Peculiar fella.
Thought so myself.
Still...
He made me feel more comfortable.
Whenever I'm with him,
I felt I could be more sincere.
So there's nice people
among IT presidents as well.
As for people like me...
She came...
to properly bid farewell.
Isn't falling for a woman like that...
something you should feel proud about?
Your feelings for her were sincere,
so don't look down on that.
Reality...
is not like what you find in the movies.
Nakajima-kun is still
delivering papers every day.
Although I think it's still
too early for egg sandwich...
~ to be continued ~
First things first,
finely chop the boiled egg.
Mayo fits with just about everything,
doesn't it?
But if you use too much,
it'll cover the taste of eggs,
so use just enough to make
it sticky and nothing more.
Add just the right doses
of salt and pepper.
Ahh! Master...
Use this for me.
So... Good night everyone!