KOBAYASHI KAORU
TANIMURA MITSUKI
ARATANI KIYOMI
UNO SHOHEI
Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ima yukkuri kaze ni notte
Misty white breaths you exhale, now gently riding on the wind
Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku
Into the clouds in the sky, gradually fading away
Toku takai sora no naka de te o nobasu shiroi kumo
From up above in the sky white clouds reach down
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
At the end of the day, when people are rushing home...
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
...That's when my day starts.
Kimi ga haita iki o sutte pokkari to ukan deru
To inhale your exhaled breaths that float by
...That's when my day starts.
Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne
Always seems like a thing of the past
Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds passing over a flowing river
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
[Pork Miso Soup Set ¥600, Beer ¥600, Sake ¥500, Shochu ¥400,
Alcoholic drinks are limited to 3 servings]
These are the only items on the menu.
[Pork Miso Soup Set ¥600, Beer ¥600, Sake ¥500, Shochu ¥400,
Alcoholic drinks are limited to 3 servings]
If one orders something
aside from these...
...I'll make it if I can.
Such is my business philosophy.
Do customers come? You ask...
There's quite a number who do.
Wabi-Sabi Subs presents:
SHINYA SHOKUDO Season 3
EP 4: "Red Pickled Ginger Tempura..."
- Is it okay?
- Slowly, slowly...
- Okay, okay.
- I said slow down!
- Go! Okay, okay...
- Is it okay?
- Yeah, it's fine.
- Thanks!
- See ya.
- Thanks for the help!
Why does he always passes through here?
Delicious! I guess it's still summer, huh?
Such a nice sound...
It'll be the festival around here soon, right?
We'll come and wear yukata* here, Master!
(*light kimono)
Oh, you're not happy about that?
It's just that smoke got in my eyes.
Komichi-kun, you don't look so well today, huh.
Well you always look like that though...
He's suffering, y'know.
Eh? Cirrhosis of the liver?
Could it be that you have the same thing
that we suffer from?
Are you in love? With whom?
What kind of person? Is she older? Younger?
Is she a full-time employee?
Or non-regular?
Aren't you guys treating this
like one of your vulgar marriage huntings?
This guy is similar but different.
Well, excuse us.
Originally, Komichi had asked me
for help at the start.
What do you mean by "similar but different".
I'm sorry, Master for always asking for a favor...
I used to make these when I worked part-time
in a street stall a long time ago.
I also bought these. Please use it.
It's okay. 'Cause I have mine.
Oh, of course.
What do you think, Kasumi-san?
Master can cook kushi-age (deep fried skewers), right?
It ain't "kushi-age". It's "kushi-katsu".
Kasumi-chan sometimes shows up
at my shop; she's a Naniwa* girl.
(*former name of Osaka)
This is the girl Kochimi-kun is pining for.
Oh, right. You call it "kushi-katsu" in Osaka, huh?
It's called "kushi-katsu" everywhere.
In order to please the girl he's in love with...
...he orders Osaka specialties for her but...
But even though Tokyo kushi-age is all classy,
it tastes all the same.
Well, when compared to the authentic...
I like Master's kushi-age.
It's kushi-katsu.
It seems they can't see eye to eye.
Oww, oww, hot!
You're kinda clumsy too, eh? Mister.
- This is a bit... Excuse me...
- Oh, okay.
[Pharmacy, 9 am opening]
Okay, here we go...
Yep.
That was nice... Can you
smile a bit more?
- Smile.
- Okay, here we go...
Oh, thanks thanks...
Sorry for asking you to come out so late!
Oh, it's okay. Don't worry about it.
- So where is it?
- This way, sir.
Right this way.
Looks nice.
Please, right this way.
It's close.
Uh... oh, here?
No, over here.
Ide-san is the president of the pharmacy,
and has branched out into Tokyo...
He has asked me to take pictures
for a publicity magazine.
Well, he asked me for help...
He told me he is at his wit's end
with a girl from Osaka.
I too will give her a good talk...
After that you and her will get along well,
it'll be a breeze!
Thank you. President, would you
like some beer?
Will you be paying?
- Of course.
- Well, good. Don't mind if I do.
Okay. Master, beer.
- Two glasses.
- Sure thing.
- President.
- Huh?
People from Osaka really do that, huh?
What the heck are ya doin...
Bang!
That ain't right.
Your timing is totally wrong.
It's difficult.
We use sophisticated technology when
physical performance is called into question.
There may be the Tokyo Olympics
scoring competition.
If so, I'll be scheduled to be
the Jury President.
Will you be getting tickets for the new
National Stadium? It's still 6 years from now though...
It'll be a cinch. No problem.
Do you want to see the 100 meter dash?
No... the women's high jump,
if you please.
That's a good one.
Thanks for waiting.
Welcome.
- Kasumi-san.
- I came just as promised.
What are we gonna eat today?
- Oh, is this the girl?
- Yes.
Where in Osaka are you from?
What? Is this guy your sponsor?
You can trust me.
But before that, Komichi-kun has only
been treating you...
...but you haven't even given him
your cell phone nor email address.
Aintcha being too cruel?
Society is interdependent.
It's a give and take.
Beer and this... make tempura out of it.
Am I gonna fry it as is?
Oh, slice em diagonally...
then plop em in the oil.
She's quite a formidable gal but...
...I find it challenging.
Okay.
How cool is that...
Thanks for waiting.
What is that?
Beniten*.
(*Benishoga or Red pickled ginger Tempura)
Beniten?
Then you began to stock up with benishoga?
Yeah. I buy even those pesky items
that I don't have here.
That Naniwa Girl. What is she?
I asked Komichi-kun what she does but
he said, he doesn't know.
She always doesn't pay for her bills here, right?
Isn't that a nice way of saying,
she's a dine-and-dash girl?
Right~?
- Thanks for waiting.
- Benishoga Tempura...
Would you like some?
No thanks.
Benishoga is good if it
goes with yakisoba but...
The red food coloring looks odious, doesn't it?
I wonder what ingredients they put into it?
I heard they put that in soups in
stand-and-eat soba shops in Akihabara and Asakusa.
- Mm! I can see why...
- Yes! Yes!
It does work!
Indeed...
...it has no shadow (boring and featureless).
In Osaka, they normally sell these as side dishes...
It seems they often eat it at home.
That's impossible. I wonder
if they're born poor over there.
Wait, you don't have to say it that far!
(Note: he suddenly speaks in Osaka dialect)
Kou-chan... you're...
I have come here to eat dinner.
♫ Kon'na yoru daremoga warai uka re teru kisetsu
Such seasonal evening with everyone laughing merrily
♫ Sake o nomi, uta o utai, shinda yo ni yoruru no sa
Drinking and singing songs, until the night dies
♫ Doko made mo, doko made mo
Wherever, wherever
♫ Tabi wa hatenaku tsudzuku ka
Will the journey end or continue
♫ Deau saki de warai ai
To laugh and get along with people you'll meet ahead
♫ Wakareru toki ne
In another time
Chief! Beniten for me too.
Sorry but I'm all out.
I have some other minced stuff though.
I could fry that up for you if you like.
I don't want that. Missy...
Can you share one with me?
- These are mine.
- How much did you pay for it?
One million yen.
(In Osaka shops, they would jokingly refer to 1 yen
as 1 million yen, 5 yen = 5 million yen and so forth)
How cheap, huh?
(In Osaka shops, they would jokingly refer to 1 yen
as 1 million yen, 5 yen = 5 million yen and so forth)
Well, then. I'm done.
- Komichi-kun, you pick up the tab, okay?
- Huh? But the other day...
That was for the other day.
Now is now.
Circumstances always changes.
You want an Olympic
platinum diamond ticket, doncha?
Oh...
Mister. Your wig is showing.
Don't say stupid things.
This ain't a wig.
She's right. There's no reason to wear
such an obvious wig, right?
Uh... no... um...
I think it's better if you take it off.
She's really an interesting gal...
Here.
Thanks.
- Welcome.
- Hello.
- Can I also have Beniten?
- Good for one person?
No no, I usually order half, right?
Who'd pay 400 yen for such a thing...
I used to pay 5 yen for each piece.
Sure thing.
And also some cold tea.
President, your head...
- Oh, you noticed?
- I could see it.
You're a breath of fresh air.
As merchants say, "It's bad,
if you're afraid of change."
Ide-san... Take only 3 toothpicks here.
Come on, don't be so stingy.
The owner here is so stingy.
Well, Missy, whatchu think?
- About what?
- About this.
I wonder if it's more interesting
if you wear a wig?
But it looks cute.
Cute?
It suits you. It's like Billiken-san*,
when he grants your wish...
(*Good luck image of a bald, smiling man)
How about it, Missy? You want to be
my mistress? If you want money, I have plenty.
My mom said...
"Don't become just a cheap mistress."
Well, goodbye. Pay for my tab, okay?
She really is one interesting gal...
If you've grown bored of such
Osaka dialect exchange...
...be on your guard.
Disaster strikes when you least expect it.
- Thanks for waiting.
- Thank you.
C'mon, let's just try it out once.
As they say...
..."you can't judge a horse
until you've ridden it", right?
I've already cured my gum disease.
Your nose is like a marshmallow.
- Good evening.
- Welcome!
Honey!
When you said you'd be working late...
...I knew you're going out occasionally.
I- I wasn't doing anything...
Eh? How come you know I'm here...
I ordered plenty of detectives to
watch you closely.
I've even called former CIA agent, Snowden.
Really? It's globalization, ain't it?
You dumb stupid scum!
How old do you think you are?
You sex-obsessed fiend.
I'll get yours, Mister.
How pathetic!
Let's go home! Goodness...
- Ah! Your change!
- Oh, right.
Here's 5 million yen.
Oh, you're learning well.
That was good.
You're such a loser!
I enjoyed the service.
If you'll excuse me.
Honey~!
It had been a while since that uproar...
It's good that it was found out early.
Just focus on having it cured through surgery.
Don't say such a thing so easily.
If the surgery fails...
If I'll lose my crown jewels...
...there'll be nothing to look
forward to in life anymore.
- Missy.
- What?
I'll have surgery the day after tomorrow.
If so, I will no longer be able to satisfy you.
Please... Can you spend the night with me?
President! You said you're gonna
stop being irresponsible...
Fine.
Well, let's go. Pay for my tab.
Um... uh... I'm done. Thanks.
There's a chance that he lied
about having surgery, right? Master.
Hotel's over there.
- You still don't know yet?
- Don't worry.
If it's spending money,
I'll give you plenty to splurge on.
"Don't become just a cheap mistress..."
That's what my mom told me
long before she went to heaven.
Right! Let's both go to heaven too, you and I.
So let's go. Come on.
Look and you'll know right away.
Know what?
Beniten...
...is the flavor I associate with my mom
and my fatherless family...
It's the taste of poverty.
Even if it's for being nothing
but getting stabbed in the back...
...it's bad if you don't express your gratitude...
...Dad.
Who are you?
There's no way you'd know, huh.
I was just born during that time.
What are you saying?
Take a look at my face.
There's a trace of it, right?
25 years ago, the woman you discarded
in Higashi-Sumiyoshi...
...was my mom.
Thanks.
Oh! This is super-duper good!
Your surgery was a success...
From here on, focus on the business, okay?
I know that. You don't have
to say anything more.
I won't be here if it weren't for you.
You can count on me from here on too.
You really are a devil.
Oh, wait... it shifted too much...
What is this, no message but
only a picture of beniten.
Is this some kind of cryptic message?
Gimme a break, Honey...
I have really drawn the line between
me and that girl. Please believe me.
If you've drawn the line, then you wouldn't
be getting this, would you?
Well...
How much is this phone?
Ah~ 3,000 yen.
Well, then good.
When the asking price is like that in business...
...it's disgrace to a merchant's reputation.
Right?
♫ Tabako o kuyurase
Smoking a cigarette
Are you gonna take a pic of it every time?
♫ Kon'ya wa doko e nagarete ku no
To where does the night flow
It's like a diary.
♫ Kon'ya wa doko e nagarete ku no
To where does the night flow
♫ Akai kuchibiru wa subete o miryō shite shimau
Red lips that fascinate everyone
Take the moisture off from the ginger, then slice.
♫ Akai kuchibiru wa subete o miryō shite shimau
Red lips that fascinate everyone
Take the moisture off from the ginger, then slice.
♫ Beniten na manazashi de kokoro o misukashi teru
Its fiery red gaze pierces through the heart
Once coated with batter...
♫ Beniten na manazashi de kokoro o misukashi teru
Its fiery red gaze pierces through the heart
Gently plop it in...
♫ Beniten na manazashi de kokoro o misukashi teru
Its fiery red gaze pierces through the heart
Yes.
♫ Beniten na manazashi de kokoro o misukashi teru
Its fiery red gaze pierces through the heart
Well then, goodbye.
♫ Beniten na manazashi de kokoro o misukashi teru
Its fiery red gaze pierces through the heart
Kasumi-san, what work do you do?
♫ Beniten na manazashi de kokoro o misukashi teru
Its fiery red gaze pierces through the heart
♫ Beniten yona anata
You're like Beniten
Kasumi-san!
♫ Beniten yona anata
You're like Beniten
Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo
Even if it's laughing or mad
'Master' - KOBAYASHI KAORU
Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo
Even if it's laughing or mad
'Kasumi' - TANIMURA MITSUKI
Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo
Even if it's laughing or mad
'Kasumi' - TANIMURA MITSUKI
Itoshikute shikatanakatta yo
I adore your face, can't be helped
'Ide' - ARATANI KIYOMI
'Komichi' - UNO SHOHEI
Itoshikute shikatanakatta yo
I adore your face, can't be helped
'Ide' - ARATANI KIYOMI
'Komichi' - UNO SHOHEI
Uchiakete kureta kako mo
You even confided to me your past
'Kosuzu' - AYATA TOSHIKI
'Chuu-san' - FUWA MANSAKU
'Gen' - YAMANAKA TAKAHASHI
Uchiakete kureta kako mo
You even confided to me your past
'Kosuzu' - AYATA TOSHIKI
'Chuu-san' - FUWA MANSAKU
'Gen' - YAMANAKA TAKAHASHI
Futari ga mitaaozora mo wasurenai
Two people won't forget the sky they have seen
'Miki' - SUDO RISA
'Rumi' - KOBAYASHI ASAKO
'Kana' - YOSHIMOTO NAHOKO
Futari ga mitaaozora mo wasurenai
Two people won't forget the sky they have seen
'Ide's Wife' - KAMO SUZUME
'Kocchan' - YOSHIMI YUKIHIRO
Futari ga mitaaozora mo wasurenai
Two people won't forget the sky they have seen
'Ide's son' - TAKAHASHI AKIRA
'Ide's daughter' - HOJO KIKUMI
'Singer' - FUKUHARA KIMIE
Original Work:
"Shinya Shokudo" by ABE YARO
[Big Comic Original Publications]
Screenplay:
MANABE KATSUHIKO
Planning:
ENDO HITOSHI
SHIBANO MASAYUKI
Producers:
TSUITSUI RYUHEI / OSANO TAMOTSU
ISHIZUKA SHOGO / TAKEZONO MOTO
OP Theme Song:
"Omoiizu"
by SUZUKI TSUNEKICHI
Theme Song: 'Yakimochi' by TAKAHASHI YU
(Warner Music Japan)
Issho ni i rareru dake de
Just staying together
Food Stylist: IJIMA NAMI
Issho ni i rareru dake de
Just staying together
Food Stylist: IJIMA NAMI
Te to te o kasane aeru dakede yokatta ne
And just touching and holding hands feel great, doesn't it
Art: HARADA MITSUO
Te to te o kasane aeru dakede yokatta ne
And just touching and holding hands feel great, doesn't it
Title Logo Design: BAY BRIDGE STUDIOS
Te to te o kasane aeru dakede yokatta ne
And just touching and holding hands feel great, doesn't it
Sound Supervisor / MA: ASARI NAOKO
Te to te o kasane aeru dakede yokatta ne
And just touching and holding hands feel great, doesn't it
Sound Supervisor / MA: ASARI NAOKO
Taisetsuna koto hodo minareta basho de kagayaku no kamo shirenai
Seems the important things and familiar places are shining more
Planning Cooperation: OKAMOTO JUNYA
Taisetsuna koto hodo minareta basho de kagayaku no kamo shirenai
Seems the important things and familiar places are shining more
Draft Cooperation: YOSHIDA KAZUTO / HIROOKA NOBUTAKA
Taisetsuna koto hodo minareta basho de kagayaku no kamo shirenai
Seems the important things and familiar places are shining more
Organization: TAKAHASHI TOSHIHIRO
Taisetsuna koto hodo minareta basho de kagayaku no kamo shirenai
Seems the important things and familiar places are shining more
Organization: TAKAHASHI TOSHIHIRO
Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo
Even if it's laughing or mad
Line Producer: TAKAHASHI JUN
Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo
Even if it's laughing or mad
Photography: OTSUKA RYO
Hohoende kureta kao mo okottakao mo
Even if it's laughing or mad
Photography: OTSUKA RYO
Itoshikute shikatanakatta yo
I adore your face, can't be helped
Lighting: KIMURA AKIO
Itoshikute shikatanakatta yo
I adore your face, can't be helped
Director: MATSUOKA JOJI
Itoshikute shikatanakatta yo
I adore your face, can't be helped
Planning: AMUSE / MBS
Itoshikute shikatanakatta yo
I adore your face, can't be helped
Planning:
AMUSE / MBS
Kimi no koto ga sukida yo
I love you
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT / GEEK SITE
Kimi no koto ga sukida yo
I love you
Production:
AMUSE VIDEO PRODUCTION UNIT / GEEK SITE
Korekara mo zutto kimi o dakishimetai
I want to hold you in my arms now and forever
A 2014 production of:
AMUSE / SHOGAKUKAN / TOEI / KINOSHITA GROUP
GEEK PICTURES / MBS / RKB
Korekara mo zutto kimi o dakishimetai
I want to hold you in my arms now and forever
This drama is fictional
Korekara mo zutto kimi o dakishimetai
I want to hold you in my arms now and forever