~ Kimi ga haita shiroi iki ga ~
*Misty white breaths you exhale*
~ Ima yukkuri kaze ni notte ~
*Slowly blown by the wind now*
~ Sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni ~
*Into the clouds in the sky*
~ Sukoshi zutsu kiete yuku ~
*Gradually fading away*
~  Toku takai sora no naka de ~
*From up above the sky*
~ Te o nobasu shiroi kumo ~
*White clouds reach down*
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
At the end of the day...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
When people are rushing home...
~ Kimi ga haita iki o sutte ~
*To inhale your breaths*
That's when my day starts.
~ Pokkari to ukan deru ~
*They continue to float away*
~ Zutto mukashi no koto no yoda ne ~
*Seems just like the distant past*
~ Kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru ~
*Clouds passing over a flowing river*
My business hours start from midnight to 7 am.
People call my restaurant 'the late night diner.'
This is my only menu.
(tonjiru, beer, sake, shochu)
If a customer wants something else...
...I'll say "I'll make it if I can."
That is my business policy.
(Store Sign: 'Meshi-ya')
Do I ever get customers, you may ask?
I do get quite a few.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
(Late-Night Diner)
=Season 2=
It's been so long since I felt so
thrilled like that.
Especially when I saw Kirari-chan's sweaty
skin glistening in the spotlight.
She was sparkling, wasn't she?
Yeah! Kira-kira (sparkling) Kirari!
Was that a pun just now?
- That was good!
- You really think so?
Can you give me that look just now?
That look just now? Okay, sure.
Hey, oji-san, you're too close!
You're getting in my shot.
Here you go.
Who's she?
They seem so very excited.
That's Kirari-chan.
A new stripper over at New World Theater.
Those two are obsessed with her.
Two guys over one girl...?
This will not end well, won't it?
While Marilyn hasn't returned yet,
this is their idea of being morally faithful to her.
Oh, I wanna sing Girls' Generation songs!
Let's go!
I'll take care of the tab here while
you pay for the karaoke.
Eh? But I'm the one who paid
for our tickets at the theater.
Oji-san wants you to sing that song
about the chrysanthemums of Fuji.
- What song's that?
- I have to bring my stuff.
Hey, Chuu-san... please wait for me!
See you, Master.
So noisy here.
Good evenin'~.
Are you drunk again?
That's bad. Your son will get worried again.
I don't need your preachings.
Serve me some 'asari no sakamushi'* and sake.
(*sake-steamed clams)
Comin right up.
Why's this sake of yours taste like water?
It's because you're drunk and that any
liquor tastes like water to you by now.
You just don't wanna admit
that this is some cheap old sake.
Hey you, come here and have
a drink with me.
Oh... but this is already my third glass.
(Master only allows 3 liquor orders per person)
What're you sayin?
You're a grown man now...
...doesn't matter how much you drink.
You younger people these days
are so square...
Okay, fine. I understand.
You just don't like to drink with me...
...am I right?
No, that's not what I meant.
Spare me the excuse.
I can drink on my own.
Gimme more.
You already had three.
Nevermind that. This is my body anyway.
So leave me be.
C'mon. Gimme more.
Hey, old hag...
enough of that.
Just because you don't drink, you can act like
some role model who can preach to me.
That's why you're no fun.
Maybe when I was raising him...
I made a mistake at some point.
What're you saying? Aren't I the one
taking care of you now?
What? Of course not.
Sorry if she's always giving you trouble.
I wasn't annoyin' anyone.
Today, I also mixed the sake with water.
- Put me down.
- Why?
- I'll just go to a hotel.
- What're you saying?
You'll go home and sleep.
Not over there.
That mother and son...
...I always wonder whether they really
have a good relationship.
You're all wrinkled up everywhere...
...you really ARE an old hag.
What about you...?
You've already become an ossan
(middle-aged uncle).
You're still awake?
'Cause you know... I've been
thinking that if you'll give me a grandkid...
...I'll quit drinking right away.
You say that now but you won't do it.
Besides who would marry...
...an 'oji-san' like me with
an alcoholic mother?
You're beyond old.
Only because of good food
that you got to live this long.
- Ready.
- Yes!
Thrust your left fist out,
and pull back your right.
- Then keep punching the center front.
- Osu!
Start!
One, two, three...
...Five, six, seven, eight...
Pull back your right arm a bit more.
- Next, we'll work on offensive and defensive.
- Osu!*
(*in dojos, it means 'push and endure')
Prepare your armor!
Be careful...
Do it in an orderly manner!
Alright, you guys...
...you can order anything you like.
- Really?
- Yay~!
Sorry, Master....
...for asking you to help me out
during your off-work hours.
It's alright.
Your guests are all welcome here.
- Besides, this seldom happens, right?
- I want hamburger!
Steak for me.
I want ramen!
Yes, alright.
What about you, Jo-san?
For me, none.
I wanna lose some weight.
Lately, I noticed that
I'm getting a bit sluggish.
I see.
Mmm, good.
Yum.
Thanks for the meal!
Osu!
Osu.
Wait wait wait.
Alright.
I've brought the stocks.
Go ahead, you can get them now...
These are the new ones
you ordered for your dojo's exhibition.
Thank you.
It's just that...
regarding the payment...
No problem.
Just pay me when you can.
I'm sorry.
Why do you have to be
so embarrassed about it, Jo-yan?
Anyway, just go now..
You still have to practice, right?
Okay.
Osu.
- Let's go.
- Osu.
Well, then, you give me this, too.
You brought your car today, Nagai-san?
I'm going to fetch my wife.
That guy comes to fetch his mother..
...while you go and fetch your wife, eh?
What's with that teasing?
Because, you see...
...my wife and my mom aren't getting along
...it's really a pain to deal with.
Alright.
Though his dojo business is looking good...
Jo-yan's also worried...
...about his mother's condition.
Her health is not so well...
...and he's troubled about it...
...He told me that one time.
That's why he needs to save a bit of money.
Don't tell him I told you that.
Of course.
Master, Master...
...would you believe?
That Jo-yan was always being
bullied when he was a child?
With that big body of his?
He was a chubby kid before
and was such a crybaby...
...he was always getting ostracized.
Then one day...
...he climbed that jungle
gym thing in the park...
He was in some sort of a daze...
...when his foot slipped.
Jo!
Mom.
Tell me who did it!
I'll kill him right away!
Ever since then, Jo-yan began
learning karate...
...he practiced hard every
single day.
His mother...
...could very well kill for him, huh?
When Jo-yan won the
national tournament...
...we all went to him and apologized.
'We?'
I was one of those who
used to bully him.
You did?
But you know...
...he forgave us right away.
He had become a good person
that we couldn't even measure up to.
Since then, he and I have become
good buddies.
That was a good story.
I'll treat you to a drink.
Here you go.
Just by the smell...
it's irresistable.
It would be good if you and your
mom would eat here together.
You must be joking.
I'm already taking care of
that old hag every day...
...when I go out I don't need
to take her with me.
About what happened before, sorry for that.
After I talked with her,
she said she won't drink anymore.
Jo-san.
I may be poking my nose in
somebody else's business.
But maybe you should bring
her to the hospital once more.
I know that.
But she doesn't want to.
'If she wants to drink...'
'...then let her drink...'
That's what I've been thinking lately.
She always have had a hard life.
Long ago, my dad's factory
went bankrupt...
...then, he ran away with some woman.
Then those debt collectors kept
coming everyday...
...and Mom would bow down and
apologize to them each time.
Then one day...
...I didn't know why back then but she took
me to this seashore...
It was just the two of us walking
along that long stretch of beach.
I said, I can't walk anymore...
She told me I was a spoiled brat.
Then we went inside this nearby diner...
...and she ordered for me this dish.
I ended up eating three bowls.
And still I wanted more.
So Mom scolded me for it.
Bet it was quite delicious, huh?
That was the first time...
...I ever ate sake-steamed clams.
When I grew up, Mom told me...
'After seeing you eat so heartily...'
'...I gave up the idea of dying.'
(TN: double suicide through drowning)
So that's why Oren-san...
...always asks for sake-steamed clams
whenever she comes here.
Hold on a sec.
This one's on the house.
Thank you, Master.
It's just like that time
when I first ate it, huh?
After that, Oren-san continued to
come here to drink...
...and Jo-san would follow
and carry his mother home.
Until finally, she agreed to be
sent to the hospital.
Sorry...
I'm still setting up shop...
Oh, hey...
Welcome back.
Been a long time.
You're the one to blame, Chuu-san.
You sang most of the songs that day,
and wouldn't let go of the mic.
I wish Marilyn would hurry
up and come back.
You guys got dumped?
We cheered, clapped, and even
popped some confetti for her...
...she still paid no attention to us.
Anyway, that girl can't sing at all...
...seems she lost some of her flavor.
Besides she was just using us, that's all.
'A moment of bliss,
Gradually, a sense of desolation.'
'A stripper shares a glimpse of her crotch,
Aegean Sea.'
'Man on the road,
Moves on to Rome.'
Don't treat life impertinently.
Welcome.
The old hag's feeling much better
at the hospital.
Kept complaining though that
she feels like an inmate.
That's so like Oren-san.
Oh, and she has sobered up, too.
Since she can't possibly get a
drink in the hospital.
So maybe she won't be giving
you anymore trouble, Master.
Do you know what might be the most
important reason for it?
What is it?
Jo-yan and one of the attending nurses
are getting along well.
His mom is thrilled about it.
When your mother gets discharged next week,
bring her here and we'll have a celebration.
No, don't trouble yourself, Master!
But... mom will surely be happy if you do that.
That's a good idea, isn't it? Now,
you have a reason to invite that nurse.
Stop it, will you!
Cool~.
Master, I'm sorry!
It's okay.
He could even use that technique...
...to impress that nurse, right?
I said stop it.
Ah, watch it, watch it.
- 'Art brings bread' eh? (*Learn a trade, for a
time shall come when you'll be needing it)
- Osu.
Sensei's taking too long, huh?
Well, he said that on the way from the hospital,
they'll be dropping by in a nearby beach.
Maybe they got caught in traffic.
What will they do in the beach?
I'll just call him up.
Okay, who wants a drink of juice?
Me~!
What's up? What happened?
Uh... a nurse answered his phone.
She said they got into
a traffic accident.
Doctor! Please you can take
my internal organs if need be....
...just make sure you save him!
It's alright. Please leave it to us.
Wait...
If you let my son die...
...I will kill you myself.
Three months after that, Oren-san's
threat seemed to have worked.
Jo-san was successfully discharged
from the hospital...
...and his young students' grief
have ended as well.
Congratulations on your recovery.
Sorry for making you all worry about me.
Thank you.
It's a good thing you're well and safe.
Here.
Yes~.
Here... to celebrate the return of your health.
Anyway, this would be great
along with sake-steamed clams, eh?
It's a wonder...
...that a non-drinker like Jo-san finally
takes a drink after surgery, eh?
To think I quit drinking because this idiot son
of mine kept nagging me about it.
Shuttup, old hag. Go away and die.
What the heck...
What's with that cursing?
Plus, he got dumped by that nurse, you know.
Hey!
You promised not to talk about it.
I had actually thought...
...that I'll finally be relieved of you.
I should be the one saying that,
you crappy old hag.
What're you saying?
...I want more clams.
Shuttup. Here, have some broth.
This mother and son... I always wonder whether
they really have a good relationship.
~ Kai kai kai kai~
*Clams clams clams clams*
~ Mazuwa suna nuki shite ~
*First, remove the sand*
~ Taka no tsume to ninnuku o itamete ~
*Then stir-fry chili and garlic*
~Asari to sake o iretanara ~
*Add clams and sake*
~ Futa oshite kuchi ga hiraku no o machimasu ~
*Cover and let clams open*
~ Watashi no sukina asari no sakamushi o ~
*Today I want to eat with you...*
~ Anata to issho ni kyo wa tabetai no ~
*...steamed clams that I love*
~ Shiage ni o shoyu to bata o ~
*Finish up with melted butter and soy sauce*
~ Tokashite ko negi chirashite ~
*And sprinkle with green onions*
Sorry for the wait.
~ Deki agari ~
*Then serve.*
- Also with the remaining broth...
- ...Mix it with the rice.
~ Itadakimasu ~
*Let's eat*
Osu...
It should also be served with rice.
Dummy!
Good night.
~ Yarusenai yuhi yori ~
*More than the dreary sunset*
To be continued
~ Shinji reru asahi o mitai ~
*Rather see the sunrise to believe*
KOBAYASHI KAORU as 'Master'
~ Dakara sukoshi yume o mi sasete ~
*Let me dream a little*
UKAJI TAKASHI as 'Jo'
MABUCHI HARUKO as 'Oren'
~ Ashita e mukau tame ~
*So I can go on tomorrow*
KOMOTO MASAHIRO as 'Nagai'
FUWA MANSAKU as 'Chuu-san'
UNO SHOHEI as 'Komichi'
~ Waraetara waraetara ~
*We laugh and laugh*
and ODAGIRI JOE as 'Katagiri'
~ Bokura warai aeru nara ~
*And smile when we meet*
Music: Satou Kimihiko
OP song: "Omoide" by Suzuki Tsunekichi
~ Tsumetai te o nigirishimete ~
*I grasp your cold hands*
Theme song: 'Uso no Tsuki Kata'
by LOVE LOVE LOVE
Insert song: 'Sake-Steamed Clams'
by Fukuhara Kimie
~ Sotto uso tsuku yo ~
*We lie discreetly*
Food Stylist: Iijima Nami
Based on the manga by: Abe Yaro
~ Kyo mo boku-tachi wa
dare ka ni uso tsukukedo ~
*Even today we may lie to someone*
Screenplay: Manabe Katsuhi
Directed by: Kobayashi Shotaro
~ Demo hitotsu tsukenai uso ga aru ~
*But there's one thing I'll not lie about*
~ Kimi no koto aishi teru ~
*And that is, I love you*