Opening Song
Omohide (Memories) by Suzuki Tsunekichi
STARRING
Kobayashi Kaoru
Iwamatsu Ryo
Ogata Morio
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
Produced by Tosaka Takuma
kimi ga hai ta shiroi iki ga
The white breath you exhale
ima, yukkuri kaze notte
Is slowly riding in the wind
sora ni ukabu kumo no naka ni
And little by little vanishing
sukoshi zutsu kie te yuku
Inside the clouds up in the sky
tooku takai sora no naka de
From inside the high and faraway sky
te o nobasu shiroi kumo
The white clouds reach out to you
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
kimi ga hai ta iki o sutte
And drink the white breath you exhale
As the day comes to an end,
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
and people make their way home,
pokkari to ukan de iru
Gently floating up high
my own day begins.
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
Max. three drinks per customer
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
My menu is all there.
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
Traditional Tonjiru (¥600), Beer (¥600), Sake (¥500), Shochu (¥400)
The possibility of getting served anything else...
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
The possibility of getting served anything else...
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
as long as it's possible,
zutto mukashi no koto no you da ne
Feeling like a memory long past
my business model.
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
I am open from midnight to seven of the morning after.
kawamo no ue o kumo ga nagareru
Clouds floating above the surface
People call this...
Midnight Restaurant.
How is business doing?!
Well enough, I'd say.
~ SHINYA SHOKUDO ~
Midnight Restaurant
Episode 5
Butter Rice
Ahh... Right!
Yuriko is getting married!
It's with her first love from
middle school or something,
and they got in touch again because
of business, completely by chance!
Wait a second...
How old is Yuriko again?
36.
Arafo*.
(*Around 40)
So that means... what...
A reunion after twenty years?!
Sure does!
Fantasy!!
Compared to her, we're just...
"We" what?
Don't group us all with you?
I knew it.
It does exist!
Is it fate?
That red thread...
The only red thread you bring
to mind is a tangled one.
Still better to have a tangled
one than nothing at all!
Guess so?!
But take a closer look, and
you'll start seeing the flaws already.
Enough with that.
Been a while.
Ohh!
Ohh... Looks promising.
Back when I was studying
in Paris and penniless,
I would often spend
time at bistros like this.
Here, should we sit over there?
All right.
I think I saw him on TV.
Be it 3 stars or 5, this place
has very little to do with that game.
Master.
For starters, some beers.
(*a thicker variety of aburaage,
deep-fried tofu)
Also... You have some atsuage* left?
Sure do.
- Then, we'll have that.
- Still, Komi-chan...
brought along exactly the kind of
species I detest, food critics.
Tasty.
Haven't had a beer in Japan in
quite some time, all right.
Had grown tired of wine,
so all the better.
Ahh... I'm glad I
brought you here, then.
(*veal sweetbreads,
renowned gourmet delicacy)
But that ris de veau* earlier
today was just a tragedy.
A little more and I would
have puked right there.
Is that so?
The sauce's flavor
was barely masking it,
but they didn't even wash
away the blood properly.
It's scary to see such amateurs be
allowed to serve food and be praised for it.
In Paris, they'd have
gone belly-up by now.
But, tell me.
You like caviar?
Well, I have no particular...
Next time, I'll take you to
this restaurant I often go to,
(*Traditional Russian pancakes)
and have you try blin*.
It's the best dish you can get,
among those using caviar.
Instead, get me a
fine bottle of champagne.
Someone is stinking up
my ochazuke, all of a sudden.
Here you go, atsuage is ready.
Ohh!
Thank you.
But, how about that
pizza from your last show...
- Italian?
- Yeah.
Ahh... That pizza...
was second rate
even by Tokyo standards.
Right when he was about to
completely kill the atmosphere...
Come on in!
How are you?
Goro-san is one of the very
few remaining of a dying breed,
the street singer.
Here you are.
Butter rice and a
small serving of Tonjiru.
I'm always thankful.
Waiting about thirty
seconds for the butter to melt...
is Goro'san style.
Just a little...
A little...
And after that, adding a touch
of soy sauce, and stirring gently.
Excuse me.
Can I have that as well?
Me, too.
Coming.
What now...
Don't! You already had
two servings of ochazuke.
I take no money from Goro-san.
And instead of that...
he graces me with just one song.
Always the same one.
"Wandering about the last 40 years,"
"I am known around these parts
for even making crying kids smile,"
"Goro is my name."
Ahh... If you were in the middle
of a meal, just go ahead and eat.
"It was a long and winding
road to Hakodate."
"Past the storming waves I went."
"As you sent me away, you hid
the tears flowing down your face."
"Memories of you ache
like a distant wound,"
"a desire hard to control."
"Waves of pain sweltering my soul."
Thanks for that.
Have you heard that?!
That was great!
So poignant.
Butter rice.
One serving of
butter rice for me as well.
Coming.
(*French for frying pan
**creamed meat+breadcrumbs)
Here is wagyu poele* on a
bed of red wine sauce and quenelles**.
Sensei?!
Ohh...
The ingredients are quite passable.
(*black hair)
Yes, we get A5 class kuroge*
wagyu delivered to us daily.
It is so fresh and delicate,
it could even be eaten raw.
The quenelle is made with
three different kinds of pesto,
while the sauce was
infused with truffles, and...
If you'll excuse us,
(*upscale Shibuya district)
Sensei's participation is
required at a party in Hiroo*.
Here...
Shall we get going?
Yes.
Master.
I upset you yesterday, didn't I?
For bringing a famous food critic
like Toyama Masao here...
I guess.
I just wanted to show him...
What real food tasted like.
Butter rice.
To make something like butter rice,
all you need to do is adding butter on
top, so you can make it at home.
My wife has spent so long overseas,
all she gives me is bread.
Ohh Ohh!
Will that...
street singer come tonight?
Goro-san, you mean?
He comes only once
per week, on Thursdays.
That street singer thing,
can he make a living out of that?
Don't ask me.
So... Here you go.
Sadly I don't have enough
change for that.
Ohh... I'll come again anyway,
so you can give it to me next time.
Can you drop me over there?
But we're still far from your place?!
It's all right.
There is a place
I need to drop by to.
You can go ahead.
Ahh... Fine.
From there on in,
Toyama-san would come
by every Thursday night.
How's things?
Ahh.... Sensei!
That sushi place you
reviewed was really something.
The chief was happy with it as well.
I'm so envious!
I'd love to go there.
I guess with my salary it
would be a little over the top?
Master.
Butter rice.
Coming.
What shall we have?
Our Critic Sensei
comes all the time now,
but Goro-san has been nowhere
to be seen for quite some time.
Goro-san!
Is it all right?
Yes.
Sorry for pushing you so much.
But low-paying jobs are
gaining steam in this bad economy.
I'll leave you to it.
The day Goro-san finally showed up...
was about three months after
Toyama-san had become a regular.
Goro-san...
I owe you so much for all this time,
but now my career
as street singer is over.
Is anything wrong?
Can't play guitar anymore.
Broke my fingers doing factory work.
I'm going around thanking all the
people who kindly offered me their patronage.
That's so sudden...
So long.
Goro-san.
By any chance,
do you remember me?
I'm Ritsuko's little brother, Masao.
You know, the one
you gave guitar lessons to...
Your index goes here.
While the middle finger goes here.
Press hard with the ring finger here.
Here you go.
- Bon apetit!
- Yes.
I'm sorry I
only had this much.
Masao, do it this way,
and it'll taste even better.
Just a little...
A little here...
That's right!
So tasty.
"That's right!
So tasty!"
Stop that!
Is that so?
How about any family?
No, I have none.
My sister is alone as well, now.
But, Ritsuko...
She was going to marry
whom her parents chose,
but she changed
her mind and came back.
But, when she did, you
had already left Hakodate.
A lot has happened since then,
but she's still living by herself.
She runs a small karaoke
bar in Matzukaze-cho.
I am sure she's
still waiting for you.
But...
It's already too late, now.
Butter rice never loses
its taste, no matter what.
Here you go.
Goro-san.
So there really was someone
in Hakodate, as you sang.
Just a little...
According to Toyama-san,
Goro-san returned
to Hakodate after that,
and seems like he's
helping out his sister at her bar.
What is this?
It's all right, go ahead and eat.
Yes...
After Goro-san left,
less and less people ordered butter rice.
But, at least as far as this man goes,
there was no change.
Great!
Master!
Butter rice for three!
Uh?!
Coming.
Sensei.
Are you reviewing this place for
some magazine or something?
Won't write a thing!
I don't want people
to know about this place.
Why is that?
If customers start piling up,
I won't be able to come.
- Not to mention...
- Not to mention?
You can't rate this kind of food.
Another one!
Still,
can there truly
be a food critic like that?
Coming.
~ to be continued ~
As simple to make as it is tasty,
butter rice consists in adding
butter on top of your rice,
and waiting for it
to melt, nothing more.
The flavor of butter
is just irresistible.
Also, as butter sold
in stores already has salt,
only add a touch,
just a touch of soy sauce.
Excess salt, intake warning!
More than that, it's enough not
to ruin that irresistible flavor.
(*seaweed)
You can eat it wrapped in nori*,
or any other spice is fine as well.
Ohh?! Goro-san,
you were here?
Nice dreams to you....
Good night, everyone!