Taiwan is located along the
boundary of the Pacific Ocean
and the Eurasian continent.
It is also the largest island
along the Tropic of Cancer.
While most countries along
the Tropic of Cancer are desert regions,
Taiwan is rich in vegetation
with subtropical and tropical climates.
Taiwan is thus paradise
to many plants and animals.
Moreover,
people from faraway lands
and mainland China crossed
Taiwan Strait and arrived on the island
during different periods.
As a result, the island
features culture as diverse
as its fauna and flora.
The ecology and geology in Taiwan
are rich and diverse,
yet nature also delivers calamities.
Typhoons in summer bring
floods and strong winds.
Earthquakes also cause
huge damage and deform the island,
resulting in structural changes
to Taiwan's topography and landforms.
Due to natural and artificial disasters,
people coming to and from
the island have developed
a unique quality
for being resilient.
Sometimes
the people are resigned to adversities.
Yet when they are determined to resist,
they show indomitable fighting spirit
in creating new opportunities.
The cycle of destruction and construction
makes Taiwan an island of miracle.
When the Earth was still young,
the island of Taiwan
began to take shape
over 100 million years ago.
Some 65 million years ago
during the late Cretaceous Period
when dinosaurs became extinct
the Eurasian Plate
and the Philippine Plate
gradually converged.
The early forms of Taiwan's topography
took shape during that time.
But still, the island of Taiwan
remained submerged.
It was not until 20 million years ago,
that the South China Sea Plate
subducted eastward
under the Philippine Plate,
thus forming a volcanic island arc
on the Philippine Plate.
Meanwhile,
the Philippine Plate was moving
in a northwestern direction
at a speed of 10 centimeters per year.
Stress resulting from
plate compression peaked
10 million years ago.
During a massive volcanic eruption,
the Penghu islands was raised
from under the sea by lavas.
Six million years ago,
during the period of Penglai Orogeny,
the Philippine Sea Plate and
the Eurasia Plate collided.
The arc-continent collision
started the merging of coastal mountains
and the island of Taiwan,
which gradually emerged from the sea.
Fifty thousand years ago,
the volcanic arc at the eastern coast
was merged with the island.
Pushed to the surface,
the volcanic arc merged with
the central mountain range
on the Taiwan main island.
These two mountains,
which were located on different plates,
became parts of the Taiwan island.
High mountains,
plains,
valleys, and river terrace
thus emerged in Taiwan.
For over one million years,
glacial periods appeared periodically.
The glaciers caused the sea surface
to drop over 140 meters.
Since the average depth of the Taiwan Strait
was only 80 meters,
land masses linked to mainland China
thus appeared during the glacial periods.
Many animals south of the mainland
crossed these land bridges to
the swamp lands in Taiwan for survival.
These included ancient Chinese rhinos,
Chinese Stegodon elephants,
as well as species of bulls,
wild boars and crocodiles.
Ancestors of the Formosan rock monkey
and Formosan black bear
appeared during this period.
This was the Taiwan Strait today.
It was a grassy plain
during the glacial period,
and was referred to as Penghu Channel.
Forty-four thousand years ago,
this herd of ancient moose
migrated to the old Min River area
to escape the severe cold in the north.
As they passed along the river,
they discovered a big grassy plain
along with other creatures
from northern China.
This group of hunters from faraway
might have become the earliest
humans to inhabit the island of Taiwan.
This is present-day Changpin Township
in Taitung County.
The scenic Pahsien Caves
are almost as old as
the Upper Caveman in China.
Fifteen thousand years ago
in the sea-eroded caves
along Taiwan's east coast,
there lived humans in the Paleolithic Age.
They were the Changpin culture people.
They are performing
one of the most ancient survival skills:
fishing.
To hunt,
they needed tools.
The egg-shaped stones on the beach
thus became the most popular material
used by this group of prehistoric humans.
In addition to stone tools,
man during the Paleolithic Age
also hunted animals for food
and were adept at using
animal bones and skins
to take care of their tribesmen.
Abundant environmental resources
also facilitated the survival
of the Changpin people.
They used their hands
and stone implements to live
for thousands of years.
During the late glacial period
temperatures began to rise.
Sea levels also continued to rise.
Some 10,000 years ago,
the land bridge between Taiwan and
the mainland became submerged.
Taiwan thus became
an isolated island.
The Formosan Landlocked
Salmons in Tachia River
first appeared off the sea of Japan.
Between 800,000 to 100,000 years ago,
temperature dropped rapidly
during the glacial period,
and salmons migrated southward
to the rivers of Taiwan.
At the end of the glacial period,
temperature rose,
and the salmons became trapped
in the cool-water rivers
in Taiwan's high mountains.
They have survived to the present
and evolved to become
a species unique to Taiwan.
Isolation caused species
to undergo fascinating evolution.
Glaciers
also brought various flora
to Taiwan.
Some 1.5 million years ago,
the first cypress trees from the north
thrived in Taiwan.
Five hundred thousand years later,
a large number of Fagaceae
appeared on the island,
followed by
broad-leaved trees.
One hundred thousand years ago,
Pinaceae trees began to appear
and compete with broad-leaved trees.
Ten thousand years later,
climate change,
ocean current, and birds
brought tropical plants from the South
into Taiwan.
Isolation
enabled the local fauna to be
unique and vivacious.
At the end of the glacial period,
sea level rose and
inundated areas
inhabited by humans.
When Noah was said to have built the Arc,
and when flood stories were popular,
people from south of the Asian continent
and Indo-China
might have
used canoes
to cross the sea
and arrive at the western coast of Taiwan.
A whirl of dusty wind sweeps beach.
The splashing waves rise as high
as a building.
Once, they buried a dog
that had lived with them for a long time.
The dog, buried thousands of years ago,
proves that
which imprinted rope designs
on the surface of ceramic implements.
During the Neolithic Age,
the early Tapenkeng culture
subsequently evolved into
cultures of the intermediate
and later periods,
such as the Yuanshan,
Peinan, and Chilin cultures.
There were also spiritual creations.
The rope-design ceramics
evolved into more beautiful
and intricate thread-design ceramics.
This is Yuanshan 3000 years ago.
In the famous War at Muyeh
in Chinese history,
when Emperor Wu battled
against Emperor Chou
and established the Chou Dynasty,
migrants from the Asian continent
arrived at the dense forest
and animal-infested areas
along Tamsui bank.
There they met the latter-period
Tapenkeng people who
had settled along river bank.
To avoid confrontation
with the Tapenkeng people
across the river,
the new migrants
chose to leave.
They moved inland, settling
by a lake at Yuanshan Island.
They depended on the rich
resources in the lake for livelihood.
These were the Yuanshan culture people.
They harvested shellfish for food.
The discarded shells were piled in pits
and buried underground,
forming what archeologists
today call the shell mound.
Also, 3000 years ago,
in Peinan plains of Taitung
lived the Peinan culture people.
They took a different path
in their pursuit for beauty.
The Peinan people loved ornaments.
Their favorite ornaments
were jade earrings, porcelain bracelets,
and jade arm bands.
The Peinan people buried
their dead at home
to symbolize the coexistence
and companionship of the dead
and their living relatives.
They laid the remains horizontally,
and put jade earrings
with human-animal designs
along side the body as burial objects.
These jade ornaments
became the key symbol
of the Peinan culture people.
This design might be
a fad or be popular
among people in the past.
Similar artifacts were also found
in the Wanshan ruins in Yilan and
the Yuanshan ruins in Taipei.
They show that during ancient times,
there might have been close contacts
between people living in
different areas islandwide.
Peinan culture people
buried their dead
with the feet facing Tulan mountain,
which was holy to the
Peinan culture people.
They believed that,
this way, the dead
would have real peace.
To mankind,
the sea is both an obstacle
and a passageway.
Those who had overcome
Hardships to arrive here
might set sail to far places
to fulfill their dreams.
Some historians and linguists believe
Taiwan is the origin of Austronesian.
Some 5000 years ago,
a group of people from Taiwan
traveled south to the Philippines.
Some 4,500 years ago,
they proceeded west to the north
of Borneo, finally arriving
at Sulawesi in Indonesia.
Timor.
Settlers arrived at Sumatra 4000 years ago.
They arrived at Java
3600 years ago.
They arrived
at northern coast of New Guinea
and the stretch of land
along the southeastern coast.
The population rapidly spread,
moving to the east of Solomon Islands,
the Pacific Ocean where
no man had ever set foot.
Some 1000 years ago,
all the inhabitable islands
in Oceania
were occupied by settlers.
They then moved west along
the northern coast of Indian
Ocean, arriving at Madagascar
at Africa's east coast.
Legend of the Tawu tribe in Lanyu tells
of ancestors from the southern islands,
who traveled to and from the islands
for a long period of time.
They engaged in trade and intermarriage.
This mobile lifestyle depicts
possible traces of development
and migration of the Austronesian.
If Austronesian originated from Taiwan
5000 years ago
and migrated to the Pacific islands,
then within this
4000 to 5000 years and aided
by the climate and ocean current,
other Austronesian from the South
could also have migrated to Taiwan.
At different times,
there were different peoples
who came and left,
which contributed to the
complex culture in Taiwan.
To the later immigrants
from mainland China,
Taiwan was a hew home.
To Austronesian,
Taiwan was a starting point
of their southward migration.
The coming and going of peoples
facilitated historical development
in Taiwan.
The stories started and finished
on the island.
Isolated by the sea
and screened off by mountains,
Austronesian who arrived
during different periods
developed their own unique civilizations.
On this beautiful island,
they maintained their unique customs,
traditions,
arts, and beliefs.
Yet the subsequent rulers that arrived,
in order to facilitate governance,
classified the natives
as “raw” and “cultured”
based on their familiarity
with Chinese culture
and geography.
The rulers then called them
mountain and plain dwellers.
Fact is,
the peoples of Taiwan were far more
complicated
than the categorization suggests.
We are uncertain whether
those who lived during the Neolithic Age
and in the different culture areas
were ancestors of the mountain dwellers.
Their lifestyles,
nevertheless,
showed similarities.
For instance, 2700 years ago,
the people living in Tamalin,
came from the eastern coast.
They migrated upstream Choshui River
and settled in the mountains
923 meters above sea level.
They were later referred to
as the Chu-ping people.
We don't know if they were ancestors of
the Bunun or Atayal people,
but their houses were build
the same way as the Bunun's.
The headhunting custom
of the Austronesian
was also similar to that of
Yuanshan culture people who
lived in the Taipei basin.
From Austronesian legends and songs,
there are evidences of their continuing
migration on land.
(Atayal dialect by the tribal chief)
I'll tell you today's topic.
It's about ancient traditional customs.
About how the Atayals migrated.
I will use ancient poems to tell the story.
Uncle Temu, I'll begin.
Allow me to look for
a place to reflect.
This is not a serious matter.
Come, let us chat.
(Ancient Atayal teachings)
Ah!
The ancestral home of the Atayals.
To seek prosperity for our tribe,
three brothers
ventured north.
Buta went to Taoyuan and Hsinchu.
Ayen went to Yilan.
Yabox went to Nantou and Taichung.
Before leaving, they made a promise
to not use wooden fences
to isolate one another.
They would thrive like bamboo shoots.
Some 1800 years ago,
the earliest metallurgy appeared
in northern Taiwan.
It was unique and indigenous.
These Shihsanhang culture people,
who knew metallurgy,
might be the ancestors of the
plain-dwelling Ketagalan
in northern and northeastern Taiwan.
They collected iron sand
along the coast of Pali,
and set up workshop near the lagoon.
They introduced iron sand
and fuel separately into
furnaces made of stones
and mud from the lagoon.
They struck the metal repeatedly
and polished the metal.
The daily metallic implement used by the
Shihsanhang culture people
was how finished.
Because iron sand contains titanium,
the quality of the products was poor.
Taiwan's Iron Age was
1200 to 1600 years behind
those of Europe and China.
Taiwan's civilization, however,
skipped the Bronze Age,
and jumped directly from
the Stone Age
into the Iron Age.
During the 15th century
when Chengho sailed the oceans,
the Shihsanhang culture people
already knew how to trade sulfur
and deer hide
for Chinese porcelain bowls,
salt, and textiles with
traders from the Ming Dynasty.
This might be the beginning of
external economic activities in Taiwan..
Compared with mountain dwellers,
plain-dwellers were more
diverse and complicated.
Their ancestors were Austronesian who
arrived very early in Taiwan.
Most settled in the
western and eastern coastal plains.
Burning forest for farming,
they fished and hunted.
Before the 16th and 17th centuries,
before their frequent contact
with the Han people,
their life and customs were
pure to their culture.
Some plain-dwellers lived
in maternal societies
where women were responsible
for agriculture,
while men were responsible for hunting.
The men would bring their dogs,
bow and arrows, and blowguns
to hunt for deer and boars in groups,
or fish in the rivers.
The River of Time
has engulfed ancient civilizations.
Heavily influenced by the Han culture,
most of their traditional customs and
mother tongue became lost.
In 1544,
a Portuguese ship
set sail from Macao
to cross the Taiwan Strait.
The ship's destination was Japan.
The 16th century was a time
of great geographic discoveries.
Armed with cannons and strong ships,
Westerners sailed all over the world.
They opened opportunities
for cultural interaction.
They also gave a beautiful
name to an island in the East.
Terra (land).
Ilha Formosa (beautiful island)
From then on, Taiwan,
which was mostly Austronesian,
became the beautiful
island of Formosa to the Westerners.
Things changed rapidly
with the advent of the 17th century.
The quickened pace of change
has dawned upon the island of Taiwan.
Faced with superior Western sea power,
Japanese pirates to the east,
and contentions among trader groups,
Taiwan started to emerge
into the world scene.